<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>大胆的火球</title><subtitle>约翰·格鲁伯</subtitle><link href="https://daringfireball.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/main" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><id> https://daringfireball.net/feeds/main</id><updated> 2023-06-10T00:49:49Z</updated><rights>版权所有 © 2023，约翰·格鲁伯</rights><entry><title>阿波罗是一件艺术品</title><link href="https://mastodon.social/@christianselig/110509739563895220" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv6" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/apollo-work-of-art" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.40002</id><published> 2023-06-09T23:15:35Z</published><updated> 2023-06-09T23:15:35Z</updated><author><name>约翰格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>值得仔细阅读对 Apollo 开发人员 Christian Selig<a href="https://mastodon.social/@christianselig/110509739563895220">在 Mastodon</a>和<a href="https://twitter.com/ChristianSelig/status/1666857672489189376">Twitter</a>上的日落公告的回复（以及<a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/apolloapp/comments/144f6xm/apollo_will_close_down_on_june_30th_reddits/">Reddit 本身的</a>长线程）。对 Selig 近十年的辛勤工作给予如此多的爱、感情和赞赏，所有这些都是为了外人肯定认为仅仅是一个“应用程序”。这些线程显示了开发者和用户之间的关系在多大程度上可以像任何艺术家和他们最忠实的粉丝之间的关系一样。</p><div> <a  title="“阿波罗是一件艺术品”的永久链接"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/apollo-work-of-art">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Reddit 的首次公开募股和兑现 OpenAI 炒作的白日梦</title><link href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2023/06/apollo-to-shut-down-developer-has-receipts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv5" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/reddit-ipo" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.40001</id><published> 2023-06-09T22:38:21Z</published><updated> 2023-06-10T00:49:25Z</updated><author><name>约翰格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Jason Snell，在六种颜色上写道：</p><blockquote><p>老实说，这个霍夫曼家伙看起来确实像个撒谎的小人，Reddit 关于尊重第三方应用程序的所有公开声明似乎都是在试图对 Reddit 用户撒谎，这样他们看起来就不像坏人了。但最重要的是，Reddit 重新定价其 API 是为了让第三方应用程序破产。 （塞利格说他将在停工期间损失 250,000 美元。）</p></blockquote><p>很明显，霍夫曼最近的所有决定都是由 Reddit 希望进行的 IPO 推动的。一方面是 Reddit 的估值正在下降这一丑陋的事实。 <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/06/01/fidelity-reddit-valuation/">TechCrunch 上周报道</a>：</p><blockquote><p>富达是 Reddit 2021 年最新一轮融资的主要投资者，自投资以来已将其在流行社交媒体平台的股权估值削减了 41%。 [...]</p><p>这种贬值是过去一年影响全球各种成长阶段初创公司的更广泛趋势的一部分，引发了人们对 Reddit 是否会保持其最初意图以 150 亿美元左右的估值上市的不确定性。</p></blockquote><p>另一方面是 OpenAI，目前受到天价估值的支撑，它使用 Reddit 内容作为其海量训练数据的一部分。这些 API 从免费变成非常昂贵的全部意义在于让 OpenAI 和类似的公司为它们付费。这是一个白日梦。 <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/reddit-openai-chatgpt-ipo-valuation-karma-2023-6">Insider 的 Julie Bort</a> ：</p><blockquote><p> “Reddit 的数据语料库非常有价值。但我们不需要将所有这些价值免费提供给世界上一些最大的公司，”Reddit 首席执行官史蒂夫霍夫曼说。</p><p>我问 ChatGPT 是否会为 Reddit 数据付费。它告诉我它的训练数据截止日期是 2021 年 9 月，所以它不知道该日期之后发生了什么。</p></blockquote><p> Reddit 已经将其所有数据免费提供给大公司。霍夫曼现在正试图为几年前放出马厩的马匹收费。而且他显然不关心 Apollo 或其他第三方 Reddit 客户端，或者这些举措对 Reddit 作为平台供应商的声誉有何影响。他只是陷入了一种幻想，即投资者会以某种方式将 Reddit 视为当前 AI 炒作的参与者。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“Reddit 希望的 IPO 和从 OpenAI 的炒作中获利的白日梦”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/reddit-ipo">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>面对 Reddit 过高的 API 定价，Christian Selig 正在关闭 Apollo </title><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apolloapp/comments/144f6xm/apollo_will_close_down_on_june_30th_reddits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv4" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/apollo-reddit-demise" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.40000</id><published> 2023-06-09T17:37:06Z</published><updated> 2023-06-10T00:49:49Z</updated><author><name>约翰格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Christian Selig，在 r/apolloapp 中写道：</p><blockquote><p>八年前，我在 Apple subreddit 上发布了<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apple/comments/2u86mj/announcing_apollo_a_brand_new_gorgeous_reddit_app/">一篇关于我正在为其寻找 Beta 测试人员的 Reddit 应用程序的帖子</a>，那天我的生活彻底改变了。我刚刚完成大学学业并在 Apple 实习，我想构建一个属于我自己的 Reddit 客户端：一个首屈一指的、可定制的、精心设计的 iPhone 版 Reddit 应用程序。幸运的是，这立即引起了人们的共鸣，从那以后这就是我的全职工作。</p><p>今天的帖子比八年前的第一个帖子要悲伤得多。 6 月 30 日将是阿波罗的最后一天。</p><p>我和很多人谈过，并且在过去几周接受了这个，因为与 Reddit 的谈话已经恶化到一个丑陋的地步，为了社区的透明度，我想谈谈我是如何到达这个决定，如果你最后有任何问题，我很乐意回答。这篇文章会很长，因为我有很多主题要涵盖。</p><p>请注意，我用 Reddit 记录了我所有的通话，所以我的陈述不是基于记忆，而是 Reddit 在这一年中记录的陈述。单方同意记录在我所在的国家/地区加拿大是合法的。另外我不会点名，这不重要，我不想打人。</p></blockquote><p>鉴于我们在一周前了解 Reddit 对该 API 定价的立场，这并不奇怪，但仍然让人感到悲惨。 Apollo——就像之前的 Tweetbot 和 Twitterrific——不仅仅是特定服务的好客户。这是有史以来最好的应用程序之一，句号。</p><p>不过，让我们停止将这次关闭归咎于“Reddit”公司，并将责任归咎于真正的责任：Reddit 首席执行官兼联合创始人史蒂夫霍夫曼个人。当 Twitter 杀死第三方客户时，每个人都自然而正确地把责任推给了 Elon Musk，因为 Musk 非常有名，并且在他管理 Twitter 的过程中非常公开，因为他现在拥有它。</p><p>我敢打赌你们中的很多人，甚至是 Reddit 用户，在我上面提到霍夫曼之前，都想不起 Reddit 首席执行官的名字。但从 Selig 的描述——可以说是他的收据——可以清楚地看出，Huffman 密切参与了这一决定，不仅负有责任，而且还积极地用敲诈勒索<em>和</em>劣质工程的可证明是错误的指控来诋毁 Selig。</p><p> Reddit 没有杀死阿波罗。 Reddit 首席执行官史蒂夫霍夫曼做到了。</p><p>让我们看看 Huffman 是否有勇气通过<a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/reddit/comments/145bram/addressing_the_community_about_changes_to_our_api/">今天计划的 AMA 来讨论 Reddit 的 API 政策变化</a>。我有一个简单的问题要问他：如果 Reddit 的<a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/d2njs/comment/c0x40yz/">联合创始人</a>亚伦·<a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/">斯沃茨 (Aaron Swartz)</a>还活着，你认为他会怎么说？</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“面对 Reddit 过高的 API 定价，Christian Selig 正在关闭 Apollo”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/apollo-reddit-demise">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>莱昂内尔·梅西即将加盟美国职业足球大联盟，与苹果达成收入分成协议</title><link href="https://500ish.com/apples-messi-strategy-48bd95fe006" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv3" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/messi-apple" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39999</id><published> 2023-06-09T16:51:11Z</published><updated> 2023-06-09T16:51:11Z</updated><author><name>约翰格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>MG西格勒：</p><blockquote><p>今天早些时候，世界上最伟大的足球运动员莱昂内尔·梅西<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/07/sports/soccer/lionel-messi-inter-miami-mls.html">宣布</a>将离开欧洲，加盟迈阿密国际。这很重要，因为<a href="https://500ish.com/a-most-beautiful-game-e3a3dcbd228d">fútbol</a> （足球）以及可以说是所有运动中的大腕即将来到美国。但这也很重要，因为他要来美国职业足球大联盟打球。与 Apple 有独家电视交易的联盟。因此，Apple 显然通过一项非凡的优惠来帮助吸引梅西：从他们的季票服务的新订阅者那里抽取收入。</p></blockquote><p>我很想知道梅西从苹果那里获得了多大的收入分成，但不管细节如何，这对 MLS 和 Apple TV+ 来说都是一次非凡的政变。只有少数运动员如此出色，如此受人喜爱，以至于他们可以单枪匹马地在一项团队运动中提升整个<em>联盟</em>。莱昂内尔·梅西就是其中之一。</p><blockquote><p>在早期看过 Vision Pro 的人中，似乎普遍赞扬 NBA 球场和 MLB 教练席演示。这些显然是用苹果制造的特殊相机拍摄的，这些相机能够捕捉到可以充分利用新设备观看体验的镜头。这种类型的内容可能需要一点时间才能在联盟中变得更加广泛和接受。你知道它不会在哪里吗？大联盟。<a href="https://twitter.com/mgsiegler/status/1666535803068256259">我完全希望</a>Apple 很快就会用他们的新空间相机（我编造了这个名字，但它似乎是他们可能会使用的东西……）拍摄游戏，如果他们还没有开始的话！ Apple 并没有削弱这里的任何其他电视转播权（就像 NBA 那样），<a href="https://mgs.blog/skating-to-where-the-soccer-ball-will-be-bc889b8c368">他们拥有独家转播权</a>。<em>随时随地</em>在任何设备上显示任何游戏。</p></blockquote><p>在使用 Vision Pro 进行演示后，我突然想到，Apple 包括 NBA 篮球和 MLB 棒球的空间演示，但不包括 MLS 足球，这有点令人惊讶——体育 TV+ 是最全面的。 （当然，Apple 每周都会在全国广播 MLB 的周五晚上棒球赛。）但如果 Apple 不打算用这项技术广播整个 MLS 比赛，我会吃掉我的帽子。</p><blockquote><p>最后，第五点，就像苹果公司在推出 iPhone 时使用 AT&amp;T 作为他们的独家运营商一样，</strong"> <a href=”https://twitter.com/mgsiegler/status/1666536683251339272<strong>我可以看到他们</a>以类似的方式使用他们的 MLS 交易。也就是说，与愿意打破常规并允许 Apple 控制产品和服务的联盟/运营商合作。当它成功时，看着其他联盟/运营商为了排队而被自己绊倒。它适用于 iPhone。它会在这里工作吗？感觉是一个不错的赌注。</p></blockquote><p>这正是我<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/06/first_impressions_of_vision_pro_and_visionos#fn2-2023-06-07">本周在第一印象文章的脚注中</a>提到的，尤其是 NFL 可能犯了一个巨大的错误，与谷歌就周日门票转播权签署了一项长期协议。西格勒将苹果公司如何利用其与 AT&amp;T 的最初独家协议与 iPhone 进行比较，这似乎是恰当的。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“莱昂内尔·梅西即将加盟美国职业足球大联盟，并与苹果达成收入分成协议”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/09/messi-apple">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/06/first_impressions_of_vision_pro_and_visionos" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv2" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023://1.39998</id><published> 2023-06-07T18:21:22Z</published><updated> 2023-06-08T22:56:53Z</updated><author><name>约翰格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">与 iPhone 引入的多点触控消除了概念抽象层的方式相同——无需触摸鼠标或触控板将屏幕上的指针移动到屏幕上的对象，你只需触摸屏幕上的对象——VisionOS 删除了一个空间抽象层。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>周一下午，我在 Apple Park 花了大约 30 分钟的时间使用 Vision Pro 和 VisionOS，在 Apple 专门为这次体验建造的临时“场地屋”里。这是与 Vision 产品营销团队成员进行的一对一导览，基本规则是我可以谈论我所经历的一切，但不允许照片和视频。</p><p> 30分钟非常快，总之体验是身临其境。我愿意花很多钱再次跑完全相同的 30 分钟。</p><p>时间远远不够，我也无法偏离准备好的演示的轨道。很明显，操作系统和应用程序远未完成。但即使考虑到演示的简洁性和软件当前状态的限制，我还是有信心描述一些事情。</p><p>第一：整体技术非凡，远超我的预期。<a href="https://stratechery.com/2023/apple-vision/">就像我的朋友和 Dithering 的联合主持人 Ben Thompson 一样</a>，我的期望很高。苹果超过了他们。 Vision Pro 和 VisionOS 感觉它们已经从未来被及时拉了过来。自从 2007 年推出第一代 iPhone 以来，我就没有对新产品有过这种感觉。体验的几个方面让人感觉不可思议。</p><p>它是一个引人注目的<em>产品</em>吗？史蒂夫·乔布斯 (Steve Jobs) 有一句著名的格言，即技术是不够的，您无法制造引人注目的产品——更不用说整个平台了——从先进技术开始并向后工作。您从产品和平台体验的愿景开始，然后创造新技术使其成为现实。我只是不能说 Vision Pro 是否会成为一款引人注目的产品。我花的时间太少了，今天的软件还远未完成，最重要的是，整个体验太过全新和令人费解，无法得出任何这样的结论。</p><p>但 Vision Pro 在多个用例中成为引人注目的产品的潜力是显而易见的。这可能很棒。毫无疑问，它很有趣，而且我认为 Apple 为 VisionOS 设计的基本概念框架为长远的未来奠定了基础。第一代 Vision Pro 可能会也可能不会是一款成功的产品——我只是不想在这方面进行推测。但即使是对 VisionOS 的一点点尝试也让我充满信心，相信它将成为 Apple 和 Apple 开发人员的下一个主要平台，与 MacOS 和 iOS/iPadOS 并驾齐驱。 <sup id="fnr1-2023-06-07"><a href="#fn1-2023-06-07">1个</a></sup></p><hr /><p>几年前，我不再戴隐形眼镜，而是全天佩戴矫正眼镜。在我演示之前，Apple 的一位代表拿走了我的眼镜，并使用一个设备来测量我的镜片，为我的演示装置提供矫正镜片插入物。只用了大约三四分钟。当 Vision Pro 明年上市销售时，购买矫正镜片插入物可能就像从 Warby Parker 等零售商处在线购买眼镜一样——您需要提供眼科医生开具的处方副本。对于我们戴眼镜的人来说，这会有点麻烦，但不会太大，而且是不可避免的。 （我在不戴眼镜的情况下近距离看得很清楚，所以我很好奇在不戴矫正镜片的情况下使用 Vision Pro 的效果如何。）在镜头测量之后，我使用 iPhone 进行了简短的面部扫描，类似于注册 Face ID（看在电话前，将头转一圈），然后进行耳朵扫描。该测试用于确定最能阻挡光线的光密封件，并校准扬声器。</p><p>我的演示是在一个相对宽敞的客厅里进行的。我坐在沙发上。可以说，我的产品营销部导游坐在沙发旁边的扶手椅上。我们花了几分钟时间调整表带，让它戴在我脸上很舒服。我的光封很好，但并不完美。我的演示体验中最大的一个缺点是 Vision Pro 在您脸上的感觉比我希望的要重。这并不令人不舒服——至少 30 分钟内不会——但我从未忘记它在那里，它只是让你的头感觉有点前倾。</p><p>佩戴 Vision Pro 的首次运行体验需要进行几分钟非常简单的眼动追踪校准练习。你保持头部不动，VisionOS 在你面前显示一系列点，在纯黑色背景上。只移动你的眼睛，而不是你的头，你只需在它们出现时看着你面前的每个点。一两分钟后，砰，你进来了。</p><p>你最初看到的只是……你的世界。你只能看到你所在的房间。没有状态信息，没有元数据，没有指示器。只需从耳机正面的摄像头输入，呈现在您眼前的显示屏上。它并没有神奇地看起来与现实生活无异，但它<em>根本</em>不像是在看屏幕。我感觉完全没有延迟。我绝对看不到像素——体验是“视网膜”质量。 Apple 尚未说明 Vision Pro 的运行帧率，但我猜测它的运行速度为每秒 90 帧，甚至更高。</p><p>同样，它看起来一点也不像在耳机内看屏幕。它看起来像现实，尽管是通过一副安全眼镜或一个覆盖面部的大透明防护罩之类的东西。视野中没有边界——您通过 Vision Pro 的视野与没有​​它时您通过眼睛看到的完全一致。最令人印象深刻和不可思议的是，视野似乎与您自然看到的<em>完全</em>吻合。它甚至没有稍微宽一点的角度，甚至没有稍微长一点的远摄。没有鱼眼效应，周边视觉也没有像差或扭曲。当您将 Vision Pro 举过眼睛时，您在脸部看到的景象与您亲眼看到的景象完全一致。想象一下，一副经过玻璃处理的安全眼镜让世界看起来有点像“胶片”。轻微的色调（到明年，这种色调可能会变得更接近现实——对我来说，从颜色上看，它感觉非常温暖），所有的东西都有一点视觉上的平滑度。</p><p>要在 VisionOS 中执行任何操作，首先要单击右眼上方的数字表冠按钮。 （左侧顶部的另一个按钮将用于拍摄空间照片和视频，但该按钮昨天在我们的演示设备上被禁用）。按下数字表冠按钮和吊杆，您的应用程序图标主屏幕出现在您面前的平面上。长按数字表冠按钮，它会将您的虚拟世界重新置于您现在正在查看的内容前面。</p><p> VisionOS 的导航模型是对概念简单性的突破。您只需看着某样东西，然后用食指和拇指在您的任意一只手上轻敲。由于找不到更好的动词，我将其称为“敲击”。当您在 VisionOS 中查看任何可点击的 UI 元素时，它会在视觉上突出显示。这种突出显示与使用触控板或鼠标时 iPadOS 中的悬停效果极为相似。在 iPadOS 中，如果将鼠标指针圆圈移动到按钮或图标上，该按钮/图标会在视觉上弹出一点。如果您查看 VisionOS 中的按钮或图标，该按钮/图标会弹出一点。某些应用程序的工具栏带有深色背景和灰色按钮图标。查看一个按钮，该按钮将变为白色。在看着它的同时轻按你的手指和拇指，它就会激活。就是这样。难以置信的简单，惊人的有效。</p><p>起初我发现自己伸手去捏我面前看到的图标和按钮。就像如果我想激活 Safari，我会把手伸向 Safari 图标并捏它。那很好用。但这是完全没有必要的。你真的可以把手放在膝盖上。当你试图在你的视野中捏住实际的虚拟图标时它会起作用，因为你正在看着图标，你的手指和拇指会点击，但你的手可以在任何地方。重要的是你在看什么。它在一两分钟内开始感觉自然，随着演示的进行，我能感觉到自己在界面中导航得更快。</p><p>体验的下一个最引人注目的方面是 VisionOS 中的一切在空间中都是完全稳定的。假设您打开一个 Safari 窗口，然后打开它旁边的一个信息窗口。 （您可以通过捏住并拖动悬停在每个窗户下方的“窗口栏”来在房间内移动窗户。您可以将窗户向左/向右、向上/向下移动<em>以及</em>离您更近/更远。）然后您转过头向你这边90度，然后把你的头转向另一边，然后你的目光回到中心。相对于现实世界，Safari 和 Messages 的那些窗口根本不会移动。一点也不是。你知道当你在 iPhone 或 iPad 上使用 AR 时——内置的 Measure 应用程序就是一个很好的例子——当你平移和旋转 iPhone 或 iPad 时，虚拟 UI 元素或项目会相对于现实移动一点点吗？在 VisionOS 中没有这样的东西。虚拟元素是完全稳定的。显然，这就是你<em>想要</em>的 XR 体验，但据我所知，没有其他耳机可以达到这种稳定性。我的理解是，这种高度的稳定性——虚拟元素的这种明显的<em>真实性</em>——要归功于 Vision Pro 实现的非凡精确的眼动追踪。 <em>Uncanny</em>通常是一个贬义词——例如<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncanny_valley">uncanny valley——</a>但在这种情况下，我将它用作强烈的赞美。 Vision Pro 如何使虚拟元素在空间上与墙壁、家具和您周围房间中的人一样稳定，简直不可思议。</p><p>主屏幕左侧还有一个顶级“环境”选项卡。到目前为止，我所描述的一切都发生在事实上的默认“环境”中，即您的实际环境。但是“环境”选项卡允许您从直通相机现实切换到虚拟现实。我经历过的地点之一是胡德山。选择它，就像您在那里一样。这些环境令人难以置信地身临其境，360 度。因此，您不必在起居室的浮动窗口中查看邮件和消息，您可以在看起来像是在山顶上、海滩上，或者，嗯，任何地方的情况下进行操作。它很漂亮，空间上的每一点都像穿越现实一样稳定。当您处于身临其境的环境中时，您可以转动数字表冠来调整它环绕您视野的距离。完全身临其境意味着您从实际物理环境中看不到任何东西；部分沉浸将它从你的外围拨回到中心，边缘模糊如梦。</p><p>最后，“突破”是 Apple 的一项功能术语，可以识别在沉浸时接近您的真人。它们有点像透明的幽灵一样淡入。但不是幽灵般的幽灵。这是一个无缝的功能，根据我使用其他 VR 耳机的经验，这是一个必要的功能，可以避免在您沉浸其中后与周围的人隔离。你看到有人淡入视野，你可以转动数字表冠来调低沉浸度，真正地看着他们。</p><hr /><p> Apple<a href="https://twitter.com/tim_cook/status/1665806600261763072">将</a>Vision Pro 的发布宣传为“空间计算时代”的启动。这个词感觉很完美。它不是 AR、VR 或 XR。它是空间计算，空间计算的某些<em>方面</em>是 AR 或 VR。</p><p>对我来说，Macintosh 更像是一个<em>地方</em>而不是一件<em>东西</em>。不是我身体去的地方，而是我的思想在智力上去的地方。当我工作或娱乐时，我总是觉得 MacOS 就是我<em>所在的</em>地方。我在 Mac 里。当我在 Mac 上工作时，打断——比如门铃或我的电话铃声——会暂时让我迷失方向，因为我被拉出了那个世界，进入了现实世界。 iOS 也有类似的效果，但我总觉得没那么深刻。这部分是 iOS 的本质，它不像 MacOS 那样对我来说是惯用的。我认为这可以从很多方面解释为什么我在 iPad 上从未像在 Mac 上那样感觉<em>顺畅</em>，即使屏幕尺寸相同。但对于 iPhone 特别是屏幕尺寸是一个重要因素。我认为<em>任何</em>假设的手机操作系统都不会像我发现的 MacOS 那样身临其境，仅仅是因为即使是最大的手机显示屏也太小了。在手机上看电影的体验不如在大电视机上看，即使在大电视上看电影也比在漂亮的剧院看电影要差。我们人类是视觉动物，我们的视野会影响我们的重要性感。大小事项。</p><p>可以说，MacOS 和 iOS（或 Windows、Android 或其他）的<em>世界</em>是由它们运行的​​显示器定义和限制的。如果 MacOS 是我在工作时精神上去的地方，那么这个地方就会通过 Mac 的显示屏在物理上体现出来。它就像运动中的运动场或球场——它有非常清晰、坚硬、快速的矩形边界。它具有固定的大小和形状，我在那个世界中所做的一切都发生在这些显示边界的范围内。</p><p> VisionOS 将成为一个类似工作的概念性场所。但是没有显示。没有边界。展示 VisionOS 应用程序的智能“场所”是您使用设备的真实世界场所，或者您选择的广阔虚拟环境。你所在的房间就是画布。整个房间。 Mac 或 iOS 设备上的显示对我来说就像一个门户，一个进入定义明确的虚拟世界的矩形窗口。使用 VisionOS，虚拟世界就是您周围的真实世界。</p><p>与 iPhone 引入的多点触控消除了概念抽象层的方式相同——无需触摸鼠标或触控板将屏幕上的指针移动到屏幕上的对象，你只需触摸屏幕上的对象——VisionOS 删除了一个空间抽象层。使用 Mac，你在一个物理位置，那个地方有一个显示器在你面前，那个显示器上是应用程序窗口。使用 VisionOS，您所在的物理位置只有应用程序窗口。星期一，我打开了 Safari 浏览器、“信息”和“照片”，并排打开，每个窗口都在一个看起来像电影海报那么大的窗口中——也就是说，每个应用程序在一个窗口中，看起来比我曾经使用过的任何实际计算机显示屏都大用过的。都是并排的。 <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2023/06/introducing-apple-vision-pro/">Apple Newsroom 帖子中介绍 Vision Pro 的一些视频</a>说明了这一点。但是在这种环境中看到演员的照片并不能代表亲身体验，因为显示这种环境的照片本身已经定义了矩形边框。</p><p>这并不令人困惑或复杂，但感觉很深刻。昨晚我和一位朋友聊天，直到那时我才发现他已经在 Apple 内部使用 Vision Pro 几个月了。在谈到“你的真实世界房间是你安排应用程序窗口的画布”方面的体验时，他说他花了数周时间感到有点受限，将他打开的 VisionOS 窗口全部放在他面前，就像在虚拟显示器上一样，在一位同事敞开心扉，<em>展开</em>并使应用程序窗口更大，并将它们安排在更宽的旋转木马中，不仅在他面前，而且在他<em>周围</em>。即使是最大的物理显示器的限制在 VisionOS 中也不存在。</p><hr /><p>我将周一经历的一切分为三个松散的类别。</p><p>第一个，由于没有更好的术语，就是“计算”。工作，就像过去一样。阅读网页、通过 FaceTime 通话、阅读电子邮件或信息。使用<em>应用程序</em>。你从类似 iOS 的应用程序图标网格开始，点击应用程序以在窗口中打开它们，然后根据需要排列和调整这些窗口的大小。文本在 Windows 中非常易读。我简短的 30 分钟演示涵盖了很多内容，因此我对长时间阅读的愉悦程度或容忍度持零看法，但我的印象是它还不错。 Windows 看起来很坚固，文字看起来很清晰，而且您可以在虚拟空间中使窗口变得非常大。如果在 VisionOS 中进行长篇阅读有任何奇怪或错误的地方，那不是视觉保真度，而是我一生中从未在出现 4 或 5 的窗口中阅读文章或电子邮件消息这一事实英尺高。</p><p>第二种体验是二维内容的消费，如照片和视频。在虚拟的大屏幕上观看普通电影是不可思议的。这更像是在真正的电影院看电影，而不是在电视上看。苹果公司让我们观看的其中一部电影是詹姆斯·卡梅隆的<em>《阿凡达：水之道》</em> ，既出现在漂浮在我们面前的窗口中，也出现在“剧院模式”中，它以身临其境的方式消除了您的实际物理环境。卡梅隆用最先进的 3D 相机拍摄了<em>《阿凡达 2》</em> ，正如承诺的那样，3D 效果比我在剧院或主题公园见过的任何东西都要好。我一般根本不喜欢 3D 长片电影——我发现自己事后不记得它们了——但我可能会用 Vision Pro 以这种方式观看像<em>阿凡达</em>这样的电影。但即使<em>阿凡达</em>是 3D 的，它仍然是一部矩形电影。它只是呈现为一个非常大的矩形，在该矩形内部具有非常引人注目的 3D 深度。</p><p>第三种体验是完全身临其境。 Apple 委托和创建的内容本质上只能在三个维度上使用。完全沉浸其中，就像在美丽的春日将您带到山顶的悬崖边或湖边。其中一些沉浸式环境完全围绕着您——您可以 360 度转身，仰望天空或俯视地面（或者，令人眼花缭乱地俯视悬崖边缘）。另一种定制体验是在房间对面的墙上打开一个入口，首先飞出一只小蝴蝶，落在我伸出的手指上。这太有说服力了，以至于一些经历过它的媒体人都被骗到<em>了</em>蝴蝶乐园。我没有，但我明白他们为什么这样做。然后，一只恐龙——一种看起来像迅猛龙的东西，似乎有 9 或 10 英尺高——靠近墙上的“入口”，从中间进入房间。我被邀请从沙发上站起来走近它。沙发前有一张咖啡桌，可能会发生撞到小腿的事故，但直通视频体验是如此无缝、如此自然，就像只是透过眼镜看，而不是在看屏幕内的屏幕耳机，我根本不需要集中注意力或小心翼翼地站起来绕着咖啡桌走来走去接近恐龙。恐龙不是预先录制的。它对我有反应，活生生，始终与我保持目光接触。这很恐怖，我自己蜥蜴大脑的很大一部分本能地<em>非常</em>惊慌。我非常靠近恐龙的头部，它是真实存在的幻觉从未破灭。即使走近看，也看不出它是由多边形拼接而成之类的。它看起来像一只 10 英尺高的恐龙，它的下颚可以咬断我，就在我的房间里，离我的脸和我正在写这些文字的 MacBook Pro 显示器一样近。</p><p>空间照片和视频——使用 Vision Pro 本身拍摄的照片和视频——被视为 2D 内容和完全身临其境的 3D 内容之间的一种混合体。它们不会出现在清晰定义的矩形中。相反，它们的周围出现了朦胧的梦幻般的边界。就像哈利波特电影中的某种传送魔法咒语之类的。这种效果让我想起了史蒂文斯皮尔伯格的<em>少数派报告</em>，汤姆克鲁斯的角色<a href="https://hachyderm.io/@tcook/110509376936866896">可以着迷地观看他儿子的“记忆”</a> ，以及通灵“预知者”感知他们即将发生的谋杀的愿景。这就像看一场梦，但通过一扇通往另一个世界的门户。</p><p>最后，我们观看了两个体育演示：一个是在芬威公园举行的棒球比赛中的击球演示（Phil Schiller 的双手全都在那场比赛中），另一个是掘金队与太阳队 NBA 篮球比赛中的得分比赛。对于棒球比赛，视角甚至不是来自看台，而是来自主队的休息区，地面，就在一垒后面。这不<em>完全</em>像身临其境，但<em>很像</em>身临其境。它比看起来更现实。您可以选择将目光投向何处：本垒板上的击球手、投手或外场。或者在外野手之上，在记分牌上。对于 NBA 比赛，视角是场边，就在篮筐后面。但比实际的场边视角更好，因为视角略高于座位高度。完全身临其境，完全三维，而且看起来比例完美。凯文杜兰特看起来大约 6 英尺 10 英寸，就在我面前。恰到好处的比例显然是展示这一点的正确方法，但实际实现起来似乎非常棘手。Apple 已经实现了。这些棒球和篮球场景由 Apple 使用完全定制的相机装备拍摄，并以全新的文件格式存储。这根本不像是 2D 素材外推到 3D，或者只是画在你周围的虚拟圆形墙上。它看起来很真实。它看起来完全不同从观看体育赛事的常规电视转播，因为电视转播来自纯音频广播<sup id="fnr2-2023-06-07"><a href="#fn2-2023-06-07">。2</a></sup>太不可思议了。如果 Vision Pro 所做的唯一一件事就是像这样播放整个体育赛事，我真的会考虑购买 Vision Pro。</p><p> The first two types of experiences — doing computer “work”, and watching 2D and 2D-ish 3D content, have analogs to existing experiences. Using Safari in VisionOS is like using Safari on a Mac or iPad, but with a different presentation. Watching a movie in VisionOS is just watching a movie, albeit with the completely convincing illusion that you&#39;re looking at an enormous room-filling cinema screen. But the third, these original immersive experiences, have no analogs except to the real world. It&#39;s extraordinary, and only possible because Apple has gotten so many little things so exactly right.</p><p> I walked away from my demo more than a bit discombobulated. Not because it was disorienting or even the least bit nauseating, but because it was so unlike anything I&#39;ve ever experienced. It strikes me that in some ways Bob Iger&#39;s cameo during the keynote had the relationship between Apple and Disney backwards. Iger spent his keynote cameo talking about Disney creating original new content for VisionOS&#39;s new medium. But after experiencing it, it felt more like what Disney should want is Apple providing this technology for Disney to use in their theme parks. The sports and dinosaur demos I experienced using Vision Pro were in many ways more immersive and thrilling than tentpole major attractions I&#39;ve experienced at Disney World.</p><p> Are you going to want to buy a Vision Pro for $3,500? That price is high enough that the answer is probably not, for most of you, no matter how compelling it is. But are you going to want to try one out for an hour or two, and find yourself craving another hour or two? I guarantee it. You need to see it. <sup id="fnr3-2023-06-07"><a href="#fn3-2023-06-07">3个</a></sup></p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2023-06-07"><p>I mean no disrespect to WatchOS or even tvOS by leaving them off that list. But what I mean here by “major platform” is a platform that could serve as a serious users&#39;s primary or sole computing device. Something you use for any combination of work, entertainment, and content creation. Apple Watch isn&#39;t that, but of course isn&#39;t meant to be that. Apple Watch is sort of a hybrid between a platform (like iPhone) and a peripheral (like AirPods). <a href="#fnr1-2023-06-07"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.">↩︎</a></p></li><li id="fn2-2023-06-07"><p> These sports examples were so exciting, so viscerally compelling, that it makes me wonder whether Apple demoed this, or even described it, in confidence, with NFL executives while negotiating for the rights to Sunday Ticket that the NFL wound up selling to Google for YouTube TV. It suddenly strikes me as a colossal mistake on the NFL&#39;s part that they might be the last major sport to provide their games through this technology that is, for now, exclusive to Apple. <a href="#fnr2-2023-06-07"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回正文中的脚注 2。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn3-2023-06-07"><p> And hear it. I neglected to mention it until this footnote but the audio experience is quite remarkable as well. Immersive and spatial, yes, but also: Apple isn&#39;t kidding about the way that the audio dynamically adjusts to the acoustics of your real-world surroundings. <a href="#fnr3-2023-06-07"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 3 in the text.">↩︎︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ First Impressions of Vision Pro and VisionOS</title></entry><entry><title> Last-Minute Tickets for The Talk Show Live From WWDC 2023 </title><link href="https://ti.to/daringfireball/the-talk-show-live-from-wwdc-2023" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv1" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/06/last-minute-tickets-for-the-talk-show-live" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39997</id><published> 2023-06-07T02:38:59Z</published><updated> 2023-06-07T02:51:46Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Seats are getting closer to full, but tickets are still available for The Talk Show Live From WWDC tomorrow:</p><p> <strong>Location:</strong> The California Theatre, San Jose<br /> <strong>Showtime:</strong> Wednesday, 7 June 2023, 5pm PT (Doors open 4pm)<br /> <strong>Special Guest(s):</strong> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/06/who.gif">Revealed in this GIF</a></p><p> Use discount code “ <strong>lastminute</strong> ” for $50 off the price of the remaining general admission tickets. Video of the show will, of course, be published at the end of the week, but will not be livestreamed. So if you want to see the show tomorrow, you need to be there. And if you can make it, you should. There&#39;s a lot to talk about.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Last-Minute Tickets for The Talk Show Live From WWDC 2023’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/06/last-minute-tickets-for-the-talk-show-live">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://retool.com/?utm_source=sponsor&amp;utm_medium=newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=daringfireball" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uv0" rel="shorturl"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2023/06/retool_6" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/feeds/sponsors//11.39996</id><author><name> Daring Fireball Department of Commerce</name></author><published> 2023-06-06T19:48:54Z</published><updated> 2023-06-06T19:48:54Z </updated><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Programming hasn&#39;t fundamentally changed in a long time. Building an app usually means searching for the right component library, debugging dependencies, rewriting a lot of boilerplate code, and figuring out where to deploy. Everything but solving the problem at hand.</p><p> Retool is a new approach: we&#39;ve unified the ease of visual programming with the power and flexibility of real code. Connect to any database or API. Drag-and-drop a UI while simultaneously live programming it. Deploy instantly and scale as you grow. You can use Retool to build web apps, native iOS and Android apps, and automated workflows to help your business run.</p><p> Our customers use Retool to solve all kinds of business problems 10× faster: Plaid uses Retool to manage integration product support. Amazon uses Retool to handle GDPR requests. You, too, can use it to manage users and orders, analyze data, run DevOps, or build any other business-critical application, fast.</p><p> <a href="https://retool.com/?utm_source=sponsor&amp;utm_medium=newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=daringfireball">Start building for free today</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Retool’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2023/06/retool_6">★</a></div> ]]>;</content><title> [Sponsor] Retool</title></entry><entry><title> Introducing the Wavelength AI Bot Designer </title><link href="https://wavelength.app/blog/introducing-wavelength-ai-bot-designer" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuz" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/04/wavelength-bot-designer" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39995</id><published> 2023-06-05T00:10:15Z</published><updated> 2023-06-05T00:13:23Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Richard Henry, writing for the Wavelength blog:</p><blockquote><p> AI is a huge part of Wavelength today — 1/3 of all messages sent invoke the @AI bot in a conversation.</p><p> Today we&#39;re launching an AI bot designer built into Wavelength. This lets you easily create custom AI bots — amazing lifelike personalities that you can interact with in your group chats or via direct message. You can choose from GPT-3.5 or Claude Instant v1.1 for the model that powers your bot. We&#39;ve found that sometimes a particular model is much better for a character, so it&#39;s worth trying both and comparing results. [...]</p><p> Make a fun bot? You can share it with others using a link, or make it public so that anyone can discover it. Make a fun character, a text-based adventure game, or anything else!</p></blockquote><p> I&#39;ve been testing this feature for a few weeks (in my previously disclosed role as an advisor to Wavelength), and it&#39;s a lot of fun. For characters, I&#39;ve found the Claude model, from Anthropic, to be better. Or at least more “in character”. Two fun bots I&#39;ve made: <a href="https://wavelength.app/bot/FGlF1KSBEYj">Don Rickles</a> and <a href="https://wavelength.app/bot/2GOIR9h4ZWs">Triumph the Insult Comic Dog</a> .</p><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/06/rickles-gpt35-vs-claude.png">Here&#39;s a screenshot showing the difference</a> — same prompt/bot definition, just switching from GPT 3.5 to Claude. It&#39;s fun to get trivia question answers <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/06/rickles-question-larry-brown.jpeg">with a bit of personality</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Introducing the Wavelength AI Bot Designer’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/04/wavelength-bot-designer">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Ted Chiang on AI: &#39;The Machines We Have Now Are Not Conscious&#39; </title><link href="https://www.ft.com/content/c1f6d948-3dde-405f-924c-09cc0dcf8c84" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuy" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/04/chiang-ai" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39994</id><published> 2023-06-04T23:21:59Z</published><updated> 2023-06-04T23:40:18Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Science fiction writer Ted Chiang, in an interview with Madhumita Murgia for The Financial Times ( <a href="https://archive.is/2023.06.04-050658/https://www.ft.com/content/c1f6d948-3dde-405f-924c-09cc0dcf8c84">Archive.is link</a> ):</p><blockquote><p> Chiang&#39;s main objection, a writerly one, is with the words we choose to describe all this. Anthropomorphic language such as “learn”, “understand”, “know” and personal pronouns such as “I” that AI engineers and journalists project on to chatbots such as ChatGPT create an illusion. This hasty shorthand pushes all of us, he says — even those intimately familiar with how these systems work — towards seeing sparks of sentience in AI tools, where there are none.</p><p> “There was an exchange on Twitter a while back where someone said, &#39;What is artificial intelligence?&#39; And someone else said, &#39;A poor choice of words in 1954&#39;,” he says. “And, you know, they&#39;re right. I think that if we had chosen a different phrase for it, back in the &#39;50s, we might have avoided a lot of the confusion that we&#39;re having now.”</p><p> So if he had to invent a term, what would it be? His answer is instant: applied statistics.</p></blockquote><p> My puerile mind is tempted to make a joke that tacking on “system” would make for a fun acronym, but I shan&#39;t crack that joke, as I think Chiang makes a strong point here. What we have with these LLMs isn&#39;t low-level intelligence but rather high-level applied statistics that creates the powerful illusion of low-level intelligence.</p><p> <strong>See also:</strong> Chiang&#39;s very short story “ <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/436150a">What&#39;s Expected of Us</a> ”, referenced in the interview.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Ted Chiang on AI: ‘The Machines We Have Now Are Not Conscious’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/04/chiang-ai">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Sky Guide </title><link href="https://www.fifthstarlabs.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uux" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/03/sky-guide" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39993</id><published> 2023-06-04T02:15:33Z</published><updated> 2023-06-04T02:15:34Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>My thanks to Sky Guide for sponsoring this week at DF. Sky Guide brings the beauty of the stars down to Earth. Just hold it overhead to automatically identify any star, constellation, planet, or satellite. Thanks to AR, understanding the cosmos has never been simpler. (Good timing?)</p><p> Sky Guide is just a wonderful, painstakingly well-crafted app made by a small team that clearly has tremendous enthusiasm both for astronomy and making great apps. Download and try it out free of charge.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Sky Guide’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/03/sky-guide">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Among the Companies With the Worst Reputations in America: Twitter, Facebook, and TikTok </title><link href="https://www.axios.com/2023/05/23/corporate-brands-reputation-america" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuw" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/03/companies-with-worst-reputations-in-america" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39992</id><published> 2023-06-03T20:37:49Z</published><updated> 2023-06-04T12:06:01Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Axios:</p><blockquote><p> This survey is the result of a partnership between Axios and Harris Poll to gauge the reputation of the most visible brands in America, based on 20 years of Harris Poll research.</p></blockquote><p> I&#39;m not as interested in the top of the list as the bottom. Here are the companies with the worst reputations, starting with the obvious “winner”:</p><ol><li> The Trump “Organization”</li><li> FTX</li><li> Fox Corporation</li><li>推特</li><li>元</li><li>Spirit Airlines</li><li> TikTok</li><li> Bitcoin</li><li> BP</li><li> Balenciaga</li></ol><p> So other than the two <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/ftx-founder-indicted-fraud-money-laundering-and-campaign-finance-offenses">outright</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2023/01/10/trump-financial-weisselberg-prison-sentence/">criminal</a> organizations at the top and an ostensible “news” network that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/27/business/media/fox-news-dominion-voting.html">just lost the largest defamation lawsuit in history</a> , there are no big companies in America with worse reputations than Twitter or Facebook, and the only company separating them from TikTok is <a href="https://www.insider.com/spirit-airlines-flight-review-food-photos-2018-6#you-pay-extra-fees-for-a-carry-on-bag-a-checked-bag-and-more-2">the worst airline</a> in the country. Sounds right.</p><p> (But what the hell did Balenciaga do to get on this list? <strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/what-to-know-about-the-balenciaga-ad-scandal.html">This</a> .)</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Among the Companies With the Worst Reputations in America: Twitter, Facebook, and TikTok’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/03/companies-with-worst-reputations-in-america">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Dithering </title><link href="https://dithering.fm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuv" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/dithering" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39991</id><published> 2023-06-03T01:35:47Z</published><updated> 2023-06-03T01:35:47Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://dithering.fm/" class="noborder"><img
    src = "https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/06/dithering-cover-june-2023.jpeg"
    alt="June 2023 cover art for Dithering, depicting a couple cuddling in a movie theater while wearing 3D glasses."
    width = "500"
/></a></p><p> How could I not link to this month&#39;s cover art (by the ever-talented <a href="https://hachyderm.io/@bradellis">Brad Ellis</a> ) for yours truly and Ben Thompson&#39;s podcast? Two episodes per week, 15 minutes per episode. Not a minute less, not a minute more for just $5/month or $50/year. We&#39;re now starting our fourth year, and we&#39;ve had remarkably little churn — people who subscribe to Dithering tend to stay subscribed.</p><p> Ben and I will both be in Cupertino next week for WWDC, and our next episode, with thoughts on the keynote, will be out Tuesday morning.</p><p> Bonus content:</p><ul><li><p> There&#39;s a Dithering group with over 3,200 members on <a href="https://wavelength.app/">Wavelength</a> , the new private group messaging app <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/03/wavelength">I started advising earlier this year</a> . The link to the group is in the show notes for each episode.</p></li><li><p> Speaking of WWDC, Dithering subscribers are welcome to use discount code <strong>dithering</strong> to save $50 on <a href="https://ti.to/daringfireball/the-talk-show-live-from-wwdc-2023/">tickets to The Talk Show Live From WWDC 2023</a> next Wednesday in San Jose. It&#39;s like getting a year of Dithering free of charge.</p></li></ul><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Dithering’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/dithering">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> iA Presenter </title><link href="https://ia.net/presenter" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuu" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/ia-presenter" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39990</id><published> 2023-06-02T18:56:38Z</published><updated> 2023-06-02T19:00:57Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>New Mac app, now out of beta, from the makers of the renowned iA Writer. iA Presenter is a presentation/slide deck creation tool where you write your deck using Markdown. But even though you&#39;re creating with plain text, iA Presenter is, as you&#39;d expect, an exquisite design tool. $4.50/month, $44.50/year, or a one-time purchase of $89.</p><p> <strong>See also:</strong> iA founder Oliver Reichenstein is <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/ia-presenter-launch">hanging out on Product Hunt today</a> , answering questions regarding iA Presenter.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘iA Presenter’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/ia-presenter">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> You Should Follow Daring Fireball on Mastodon </title><link href="https://mastodon.social/@daringfireball" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uut" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/follow-df-on-mastodon" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39989</id><published> 2023-06-02T18:33:49Z</published><updated> 2023-06-02T18:33:49Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Inexplicably late but better than never, there&#39;s now a Daring Fireball account on Mastodon where links to new articles are posted automatically. You should follow.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘You Should Follow Daring Fireball on Mastodon’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/follow-df-on-mastodon">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Twitter Staff Exodus Continues After a Weird, Sad Day on Twitter Even by Twitter&#39;s Weird, Sad Standards </title><link href="https://www.techdirt.com/2023/06/02/twitter-briefly-took-a-stand-against-hate-but-then-elon-admitted-it-was-all-a-mistake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uus" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/weird-sad-twitter" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39988</id><published> 2023-06-02T17:24:25Z</published><updated> 2023-06-03T18:10:06Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Mike Masnick, writing at TechDirt:</p><blockquote><p> Basically, a manufactured martyrdom controversy, combined with Twitter pretending to stand up to encouraging hatred, only for Musk to double down that hate has a comfy, welcoming home on Twitter.</p><p> Of course, in the midst of all this, the news came out that Ella Irwin, who had been leading trust and safety since relatively early in the Elon Musk reign, and who had been on Twitter through Wednesday directly responding to trust and safety requests, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/twitter-management-idUSKBN2XN3WY">had resigned</a> and was no longer at the company. It&#39;s unclear if her resignation had anything to do with this mess, but the timing does seem notable.</p><p> Still, given all of this, is it really any wonder that advertisers like Ben &amp; Jerry&#39;s have announced that they&#39;re <a href="https://www.benjerry.com/whats-new/2023/05/ending-paid-twitter-advertising">ending all paid advertising on the site</a> in response to the proliferation of hate speech?</p></blockquote><p> Also yesterday, Twitter iOS engineer <a href="https://twitter.com/niw/status/1664414700984242177">Yoshimasa Niwa resigned</a> :</p><blockquote><p> I just sent that email.</p><p> -- numstat gives me these numbers.<br /> + 728752, - 263722</p></blockquote><p> One former Twitter colleague told me, “This is a big deal. One of the few (8?) remaining iOS engineers at Twitter. Yoshi has been at the company for something like 14 years and is one of the very best iOS engineers I know — maybe one of the best in the world.” Until yesterday <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoshimasaniwa/">Niwa had been at Twitter since 2010</a> , and thus may well have been the longest-standing employee in the entire company. He&#39;d worked at Twitter for more time cumulatively than Jack Dorsey. That “numstat” nerdery reveals the number of lines of source code Niwa had added and removed over his tenure — just short of one million in total.</p><p> <strong>Sidenote:</strong> In recent weeks Niwa published <a href="https://github.com/niw/AlpacaChat">AlpacaChat</a> , an open-source Swift library to run the Alpaca-LoRA LLM locally on Macs and iOS devices.</p><p> <strong>Update 3 June:</strong> Adam Singer, a Twitter engineer for 8 years, <a href="https://twitter.com/printf/status/1664874821736620032">resigned today</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Twitter Staff Exodus Continues After a Weird, Sad Day on Twitter Even by Twitter’s Weird, Sad Standards’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/02/weird-sad-twitter">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> MLS Season Pass Drops Price for Midseason </title><link href="https://9to5mac.com/2023/06/01/mls-season-pass-price-drop-for-midseason/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uur" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/mls-season-pass-cue" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39987</id><published> 2023-06-01T23:34:50Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T23:34:51Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Benjamin Mayo, writing for 9to5Mac:</p><blockquote><p> <a href="https://tv.apple.com/us/channel/mls-season-pass/tvs.sbd.7000">MLS Season Pass on Apple TV</a> is dropping its price to account for the fact that about half of the season is now over. The 2023 pass subscription is now available for $49 (down from $99), with an additional $10 discount for Apple TV+ subscribers. The monthly subscription price is unchanged.</p><p> Although Apple does not release viewership figures, Apple SVP of services Eddy Cue commented this week that MLS Season Pass had exceeded its own expectations and doing “much better than forecasted” in terms of both subscription and viewership numbers.</p></blockquote><p> We&#39;ll have to take Cue at his word on that, given that Apple never released its forecast nor is releasing viewership numbers now, but I&#39;m not surprised. MLS has a smaller fanbase than the NFL, NBA, MLB, or even NHL, but I&#39;m sure its fans skew younger.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘MLS Season Pass Drops Price for Midseason’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/mls-season-pass-cue">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> &#39;Asteroid City&#39; Letterboxd Scavenger Hunt </title><link href="https://letterboxd.com/journal/asteroid-city-scavenger-hunt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuq" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/asteroid-city-scavenger-hunt" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39986</id><published> 2023-06-01T23:02:06Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T23:20:45Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Letterboxd:</p><blockquote><p> In a marvelous first for us, we&#39;ve teamed up with Focus Features to create a playful <em>Asteroid City</em> scavenger hunt. You&#39;ll be looking for fourteen items inspired by Wes Anderson&#39;s signature aesthetic, hidden around our website and apps, in the lead up to the theatrical release of his eleventh feature film.</p><p> Every day for the next fourteen days, a new item will be hidden on Letterboxd somewhere in the extended Wes Anderson universe of films and their creators. We&#39;ll drop daily clues on our social media, and once you have collected all fourteen items, you&#39;re automatically in the draw to win the grand prize: a private screening of <em>Asteroid City</em> for you and your friends at your nearest cinema.</p></blockquote><p> Letterboxd <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/03/08/love-letter-from-letterboxd">continues to ascend</a> in Hollywood, and I love to see it. They&#39;ve even got <a href="https://youtu.be/8BCbjVUrFu0">an announcement video from Jeffrey Wright</a> , whose palpable disdain for the teleprompter is absolutely endearing.</p><p> <strong>See also:</strong> <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/letterboxd-unboxed-grassroots-social-network-131500390.html">This recent feature on Letterboxd</a> by Harper Lambert for TheWrap.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘‘Asteroid City’ Letterboxd Scavenger Hunt’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/asteroid-city-scavenger-hunt">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> The Talk Show: &#39;guyenglish.zip&#39; </title><link href="https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2023/05/31/ep-377" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uup" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/the-talk-show-377" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39985</id><published> 2023-06-01T20:21:15Z</published><updated> 2023-06-02T16:32:57Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Guy English returns to the show to talk about the live show from WWDC, Mac Pros past and future, Marathon and Mac gaming, and Apple&#39;s seemingly imminent XR headset. And definitely <em>not</em> to talk about <em>Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker</em> . </p><p><audio
    src = "https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/daringfireball/thetalkshow-377-guy-english.mp3"
    controls
    preload = "none"
/></p><p> Sponsored by:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://squarespace.com/talkshow">Squarespace</a> : Make your next move. Use code <strong>talkshow</strong> for 10% off your first order.</li><li> <a href="https://kolide.com/thetalkshow">Kolide</a> : Cross-platform endpoint security solution for teams that value privacy and transparency.</li><li> <a href="https://rocketmoney.com/thetalkshow">Rocket Money</a> : Stop throwing your money away. Cancel unwanted subscriptions and manage your expenses the easy way.</li></ul><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Talk Show: ‘guyenglish.zip’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/the-talk-show-377">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Survey Results on Why Android Users Switch to iPhone </title><link href="https://9to5mac.com/2023/05/31/top-reason-android-users-switch-to-iphone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuo" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/android-switcher-reasons" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39984</id><published> 2023-06-01T16:19:36Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T16:19:36Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Michael Potuck, reporting for 9to5Mac <a href="https://cirpapple.substack.com/p/why-android-owners-switch-to-iphone">on a survey of Android switchers</a> conducted by CIRP:</p><blockquote><p> The top reason was actually an issue with the Android experience. Over 53% of respondents said they moved to iPhone because of problems with their Android smartphone. Specifics cited were “their old phone did not serve them, because it was aging, needed repair, or had some deficiency that affected their user experience.” The second most common reason to switch was for new features on iPhone like “a better camera, enhanced accessory options, or a more intuitive user interface.” [...]</p><p> Finally, just 6% of those who switched from Android to iPhone said they made the move because of iMessage and FaceTime.</p></blockquote><p> It&#39;s easier, and more comfortable, for Google to argue that it&#39;s all about <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2022/01/seeing_green">the green bubbles</a> . The hard truth is that iPhones and iOS are simply better overall.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Survey Results on Why Android Users Switch to iPhone’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/android-switcher-reasons">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Facebook Pre-Announces Meta Quest 3 Headset; Timing Is Purely Coincidental I&#39;m Sure </title><link href="https://www.meta.com/blog/quest/vr-hardware-news-quest-3-sneak-peek-price-drop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uun" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/meta-quest-3-lol" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39983</id><published> 2023-06-01T15:56:38Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T15:56:39Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Facebook, on the Meta Quest blog:</p><blockquote><p> The countdown is on for today&#39;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@MetaQuestVR">Meta Quest Gaming Showcase</a> , but there&#39;s some juicy news we just couldn&#39;t wait any longer to share.</p><p> Today, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cs809N-BUJ7/">Mark Zuckerberg announced</a> our next-generation virtual and mixed reality headset, which launches later this year. It&#39;s called <a href="https://www.meta.com/quest/quest-3/">Meta Quest 3</a> . It features higher resolution, stronger performance, breakthrough <a href="https://www.meta.com/blog/quest/mixed-reality-definition-passthrough-scene-understanding-spatial-anchors/">Meta Reality</a> technology, and a slimmer, more comfortable form factor. Quest 3 will ship in <a href="https://www.meta.com/help/orders-and-returns/articles/quest-2-supported-countries/">all countries where Meta Quest is currently supported</a> this fall. The 128GB headset starts at $499.99 USD, and we&#39;ll offer an additional storage option for those who want some extra space. Mark your calendars because we&#39;ll have lots more to share at Meta Connect, which returns this year on September 27.</p></blockquote><p> One difference between Apple and other companies: Apple acts like they are the only company in the markets they are in. They never rush out scared pre-announcements to get “ahead” of Samsung or whoever. Apple has the discipline and confidence to hold their fire until <em>they</em> are ready.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Facebook Pre-Announces Meta Quest 3 Headset; Timing Is Purely Coincidental I’m Sure’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/meta-quest-3-lol">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Three Mint-Condition 2010 Tesla Roadsters Available at Auction </title><link href="https://www.thedrive.com/news/those-zero-mile-tesla-roadsters-unearthed-in-china-were-meant-to-be-reverse-engineered" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uum" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/tesla-gruber" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39982</id><published> 2023-06-01T15:16:46Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T15:16:46Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Rob Stumpf:</p><blockquote><p> Earlier in May, <a href="https://www.thedrive.com/news/3-undelivered-2010-tesla-roadsters-lost-in-shipping-containers-are-up-for-sale">we told you about three zero-mile 2010 Tesla Roadsters found in a shipping container overseas</a> . These pristine examples will seemingly be the last brand-new, completely assembled first-gen Roadsters to be sold 13 years after they were initially built. But why were they never delivered? And how did they land in China?</p><p> <a href="https://grubermotors.com/">Gruber Motors</a> , the shop brokering the deal, performed some detective work to figure it out. It was discovered that the three Roadsters were all intended to be dismantled by an early Tesla competitor — test mules in last decade&#39;s international EV race. And now, someone has submitted a $2 million bid in hopes of adding them to their collection.</p></blockquote><p> First time I&#39;ve had reason to actually link to Gruber Motors. (No relation.) <a href="https://grubermotors.com/product/tesla-sport-roadster-china-3/">Here&#39;s a link to the auction</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Three Mint-Condition 2010 Tesla Roadsters Available at Auction’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/06/01/tesla-gruber">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> US Pay-TV Subscriptions Fall to Lowest Levels Since 1992 </title><link href="https://variety.com/2023/tv/news/cord-cutting-all-time-high-q1-2023-pay-tv-losses-1235610939/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuk" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/pay-tv-decline" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39980</id><published> 2023-05-31T18:54:49Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T00:50:55Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/bally-sports-stiffs-the-padres">Speaking of the demise of regional sports networks</a> , here&#39;s Todd Spangler reporting for Variety:</p><blockquote><p> As streaming video continues its ascendancy, cable, satellite and internet TV providers in the US turned in their worst subscriber losses to date in the first quarter of 2023 — collectively shedding 2.3 million customers in the period, according to analyst estimates. [...] With the Q1 decline, total pay-TV penetration of occupied US households (including for internet services like YouTube TV and Hulu) dropped to 58.5% — its lowest point since 1992, two years before DirecTV launched as a new rival to cable TV, according to Moffett&#39;s calculations. [...]</p><p> Google&#39;s YouTube TV was the only provider tracked by MoffettNathanson that picked up subs in Q1, adding an estimated 300,000 subscribers in the period (to reach about 6.3 million) and netting 1.4 million subscribers over the past year. [...]</p><p> Pay TV is suffering from what Moffett calls “the impoverishment cycle,” in which higher sports-broadcast fees have driven retail prices higher — thereby fueling cord-cutting and forcing distributors to increase prices to compensate. Even ESPN, one-time stalwart of the traditional ecosystem, has conceded that there will be a day when a la carte streaming is a viable option, Moffett noted.</p></blockquote><p> It&#39;ll be interesting to see how much YouTube TV growth is juiced by <a href="https://tv.youtube.com/learn/nflsundayticket/">NFL Sunday Ticket later this year</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘U.S. Pay-TV Subscriptions Fall to Lowest Levels Since 1992’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/pay-tv-decline">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Reddit API Pricing Would Cost Apollo Developer $20 Million Per Year </title><link href="https://www.reddit.com/r/apolloapp/comments/13ws4w3/had_a_call_with_reddit_to_discuss_pricing_bad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uui" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/reddit-apollo-api-pricing" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39978</id><published> 2023-05-31T18:31:00Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T18:32:44Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Christian Selig, developer of the splendid Reddit client <a href="https://apolloapp.io/">Apollo</a> :</p><blockquote><p> I&#39;ll cut to the chase: 50 million requests costs $12,000, a figure far more than I ever could have imagined.</p><p> Apollo made 7 billion requests last month, which would put it at about 1.7 million dollars per month, or 20 million US dollars per year. Even if I only kept subscription users, the average Apollo user uses 344 requests per day, which would cost $2.50 per month, which is over double what the subscription currently costs, so I&#39;d be in the red every month.</p><p> I&#39;m deeply disappointed in this price. Reddit iterated that the price would be A) reasonable and based in reality, and B) they would not operate like Twitter. Twitter&#39;s pricing was <a href="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/twitter-data-api-prices-out-nearly-everyone">publicly ridiculed</a> for its obscene price of $42,000 for 50 million tweets. Reddit&#39;s is still $12,000. For reference, I pay Imgur, a site similar to Reddit in userbase and media, $166 for the same 50 million API calls.</p></blockquote><p> Selig does some ballpark math and estimates that Reddit currently generates about $0.12 in revenue per month per active user. The average Apollo user would cost $2.50 per month in API fees — 20× higher.</p><p> Right now Apollo is free to use, but offers a Pro tier with a slew of additional features and fun stuff for a one-time payment of $5, and an Ultra tier with even more for a $13/year subscription. If Reddit goes through with this API pricing, Apollo&#39;s free and Pro tiers would be unsustainable, and the Ultra subscription would have to cost at least $50 or $60 per year.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Reddit API Pricing Would Cost Apollo Developer $20 Million Per Year’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/reddit-apollo-api-pricing">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Matt Birchler on Apple and Gaming </title><link href="https://birchtree.me/blog/macs-already-run-the-most-popular-pc-games-no-one-cares/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuh" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/birchler-apple-gaming" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39977</id><published> 2023-05-31T18:30:00Z</published><updated> 2023-06-01T14:59:33Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Matt Birchler:</p><blockquote><p> I would not be surprised if <em>No Man&#39;s Sky</em> releases for Apple&#39;s VR headset on day one, and it gets lots of press as it will likely be one of the few games there at launch, but I don&#39;t think it&#39;s an indication of Apple really “getting” gaming in a meaningful way.</p><p> Personally, I just don&#39;t think Apple has it in them to get high end gaming to click on their platforms. Yes, they make a ton of money on iOS games, but poke your head into the App Store top charts and you can pretty clearly see they&#39;re making that money on shitty free-to-play games that rely on whales to spend absurd amounts of money on gems and tokens and whatever else.</p></blockquote><p> Let&#39;s put aside revenue as a measure of a platform&#39;s success in gaming — the free-to-play phenomenon skews that. But even putting aside money as a measuring stick, it&#39;s clear that the iPhone is the premier mobile gaming platform. There are way more good iPhone-only games than Android-only ones. Are there any good Android exclusive games at all?</p><p> The question is: will Apple&#39;s XR platform be like the Mac and Apple TV, where gaming is an afterthought, or will it be like iOS? I wouldn&#39;t bet on the headset turning Apple into a top-tier platform for immersive VR games, but I wouldn&#39;t bet against it either. It&#39;s a chance to start fresh.</p><p> The opportunity is massive: PC and console gaming is considered more “serious” than mobile gaming not just because the games are bigger and the devices more powerful, but because you play them on bigger screens. Nintendo&#39;s Switch proves that — the Switch is way less powerful than any recent iPhone, but way more “serious” because you can play it on your TV. (And yes, of course, because Nintendo&#39;s first-party titles are unique and extraordinarily good.)</p><p> VR gaming has the potential to be far more immersive than anything you play on a TV or PC monitor. Someone will crack that nut eventually.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Matt Birchler on Apple and Gaming’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/birchler-apple-gaming">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Bally Sports Fails to Pay the San Diego Padres, Loses Broadcast Rights </title><link href="https://www.espn.com/mlb/story/_/id/37762861/diamond-sports-group-fails-pay-padres-loses-broadcast-rights" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuj" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/bally-sports-stiffs-the-padres" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39979</id><published> 2023-05-31T18:17:33Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T18:36:28Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Alden Gonzalez, reporting for ESPN:</p><blockquote><p> Diamond Sports Group has decided not to pay the San Diego Padres their latest rights fee, a monumental development that will revert the team&#39;s broadcasting rights to Major League Baseball and establish precedent for an uncertain, rapidly evolving landscape.</p><p> Diamond, the Sinclair subsidiary that operates under the name Bally Sports, skipped its payment to the Padres a couple of weeks ago and had until the end of its grace period on Tuesday to make the team whole and maintain their long-term agreement. Choosing not to meant Tuesday&#39;s game against the Miami Marlins was the last Padres game under the Bally Sports umbrella. Moving forward — starting Wednesday, continuing through the end of the season and resuming in perpetuity — MLB will air Padres games through its streaming service and on different cable channels.</p></blockquote><p> The regional sports network collapse draws nigh. <a href="https://sixcolors.com/link/2023/05/mlb-to-produce-and-broadcast-padres-games/">Jason Snell</a> :</p><blockquote><p> It sure feels like a milestone moment in the future of sports broadcasting — and the unwinding of the exclusivity of cable TV for sports broadcasting.</p></blockquote><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Bally Sports Fails to Pay the San Diego Padres, Loses Broadcast Rights’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/bally-sports-stiffs-the-padres">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> &#39;Boycott Target&#39; Song Tops iTunes Charts </title><link href="https://nypost.com/2023/05/30/boycott-target-song-tops-charts-as-rapper-claims-censorship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uug" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/boycott-target-song" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39976</id><published> 2023-05-31T17:17:28Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T19:57:53Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Shannon Thaler, reporting for The New York Post:</p><blockquote><p> Staunch alt-right rapper Forgiato Blow is topping iTunes charts with his new song, “Boycott Target,” but claims Apple&#39;s censorship is “keeping it off the radar.” The song — featuring fellow rappers Jimmy Levy, Nick Nittoli and Stoney Dudebro — was released on May 25 in response to Target&#39;s Pride-themed clothing for children. [...]</p><p> The track has hit No. 1 on iTunes&#39; most popular chart across all genres, and sits above songs by Taylor Swift and Luke Combs that are in the No. 2 and No. 3 spots, respectively.</p></blockquote><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/spotting-and-fighting-fascism-in-america">Speaking of</a> signs of rising fascism in the US This is so goofy I thought it was a parody (“Stoney Dudebro”?), <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/05/boycott-target-song.png">but it&#39;s not</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘‘Boycott Target’ Song Tops iTunes Charts’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/boycott-target-song">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Forbes: TikTok Creators&#39; Private Financial Information Stored in China </title><link href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/alexandralevine/2023/05/30/tiktok-creators-data-security-china/?sh=77dce1897048" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuf" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/tiktok-creators-financial-info-china" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39975</id><published> 2023-05-31T16:59:47Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T16:59:48Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Alexandra S. Levine, reporting for Forbes:</p><blockquote><p> Over the past several years, thousands of TikTok creators and businesses around the world have given the company sensitive financial information — including their social security numbers and tax IDs — so that they can be paid by the platform. But unbeknownst to many of them, TikTok has stored that personal financial information on servers in China that are accessible by employees there, Forbes has learned.</p><p> TikTok uses various internal tools and databases from its Beijing-based parent ByteDance to manage payments to creators who earn money through the app, including many of its biggest stars in the United States and Europe. The same tools are used to pay outside vendors and small businesses working with TikTok. But a trove of records obtained by Forbes from multiple sources across different parts of the company reveals that highly sensitive financial and personal information about those prized users and third parties has been stored in China. The discovery also raises questions about whether employees who are not authorized to access that data have been able to. It draws on internal communications, audio recordings, videos, screenshots, documents marked “Privileged and Confidential,” and several people familiar with the matter.</p><p> In testimony before Congress earlier this year, TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew claimed US user data has been stored on physical servers outside China. “American data has always been stored in Virginia and Singapore in the past, and access of this is on an as-required basis by our engineers globally,” he said under oath at a House hearing in March.</p></blockquote><p> TikTok should be banned in the United States, and Chew should be charged with perjury. This is not complicated.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Forbes: TikTok Creators’ Private Financial Information Stored in China’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/tiktok-creators-financial-info-china">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> WSJ: &#39;Why You&#39;re Losing More to Casinos on the Las Vegas Strip&#39; </title><link href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/why-youre-losing-more-to-casinos-on-the-las-vegas-strip-73f6f3ab" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uue" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/blackjack-six-to-five" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39974</id><published> 2023-05-31T16:48:27Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T23:26:30Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Katherine Sayre, reporting for The Wall Street Journal ( <a href="https://apple.news/AZg4sD5AdQ86ddbt456JLaw">News+</a> ):</p><blockquote><p> Blackjack, a fast-paced card game, historically paid out a ratio of 3:2 when a player hit 21 on the first two cards. That means a gambler wins $15 for every $10 bet. Now, many blackjack tables on the Strip pay out at 6:5, which means that same $10 yields only $12.</p><p> John and Kristina Mehaffey, owners of gambling-news and data company Vegas Advantage, have been cataloging these changes since 2011, walking miles-long routes through casinos to record the number of blackjack and roulette tables set outside of VIP areas.</p><p> According to the Mehaffeys&#39; data, more than two-thirds of blackjack tables on the Strip currently offer 6:5 payouts, as opposed to 3:2.</p></blockquote><p> 6:5 blackjack should be illegal. I mean that. I don&#39;t understand what the gambling regulators in Nevada are doing that this is permissible. What I&#39;ve seen in recent years is that all of the lower-limit tables have 6:5 payouts, and to get real blackjack, with 3:2 payouts, you need to play at tables with $50 minimums, sometimes $100 on weekends.</p><p> <strong>Update:</strong> My own home state of Pennsylvania <a href="https://www.pacodeandbulletin.gov/Display/pacode?file=/secure/pacode/data/058/chapter633a/s633a.13.html&amp;d=reduce">mandates 3:2 blackjack payouts by law</a> . Who would ever have thought you&#39;d get a better legal game of blackjack in Philadelphia than in Las Vegas?</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘WSJ: ‘Why You’re Losing More to Casinos on the Las Vegas Strip’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/blackjack-six-to-five">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Spotting and Fighting Fascism in America </title><link href="https://heathercoxrichardson.substack.com/p/may-29-2023" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uud" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/spotting-and-fighting-fascism-in-america" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39973</id><published> 2023-05-31T15:51:20Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T23:24:19Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Heather Cox Richardson:</p><blockquote><p> Beginning in 1943, the War Department published a series of pamphlets for US Army personnel in the European theater of World War II. Titled <em>Army Talks</em> , the series was designed “to help [the personnel] become better-informed men and women and therefore better soldiers.” On March 24, 1945, the topic for the week was “FASCISM!” [...]</p><p> The War Department thought it was important for Americans to understand the tactics fascists would use to take power in the United States. They would try to gain power “under the guise of &#39;super-patriotism&#39; and &#39;super-Americanism.&#39;” And they would use three techniques:</p><p> First, they would pit religious, racial, and economic groups against one another to break down national unity. Part of that effort to divide and conquer would be a “well-planned &#39;hate campaign&#39; against minority races, religions, and other groups.”</p><p> Second, they would deny any need for international cooperation, because that would fly in the face of their insistence that their supporters were better than everyone else. “In place of international cooperation, the fascists seek to substitute a perverted sort of ultra-nationalism which tells their people that they are the only people in the world who count. With this goes hatred and suspicion toward the people of all other nations.”</p><p> Third, fascists would insist that “the world has but two choices — either fascism or communism, and they label as &#39;communists&#39; everyone who refuses to support them.”</p></blockquote><p> It&#39;s downright spooky how this pamphlet from 80 years ago describes <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/trump-fbi-justice-department-purge-1234743318/">Trumpism</a> and the MAGA movement to a T. <a href="https://archive.org/details/ArmyTalkOrientationFactSheet64-Fascism/mode/2up">Here&#39;s the original pamphlet</a> . ( <a href="https://kottke.org/23/05/fighting-fascism-in-america">Via Kottke</a> .)</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Spotting and Fighting Fascism in America’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/31/spotting-and-fighting-fascism-in-america">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> iCloud&#39;s &#39;My Photo Stream&#39; Feature Is Shutting Down This Summer </title><link href="https://512pixels.net/2023/05/iclouds-my-photo-stream-feature-being-shuttered/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uuc" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/30/icloud-photo-stream" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39972</id><published> 2023-05-30T23:43:45Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T16:33:36Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Stephen Hackett, writing at 512 Pixels:</p><blockquote><p> Photo Stream is one of the original components of iCloud, and was kept around even after iCloud Photo Library launched in 2014. Here&#39;s how Apple pitched the feature when iCloud was new.</p></blockquote><p> <a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2023/05/29/photo-stream-shutting-down/">Michael Tsai</a> :</p><blockquote><p> You can see why they are consolidating on iCloud Photos, but Photo Stream had some appealing features that will be lost. First, you could backup/sync an unlimited amount of data (for a limited time). There was no need to worry about upgrading your account temporarily or having photo storage crowd out storage for other apps. Second, you could access recent photos and videos on all devices without having to store <em>everything</em> in the cloud.</p></blockquote><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘iCloud’s ‘My Photo Stream’ Feature Is Shutting Down This Summer’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/30/icloud-photo-stream">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Web Roulette — A Swipeable Randomized Web Browser </title><link href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/30/web-roulette-launches-an-addictive-swipeable-web-browser-for-the-tiktok-era/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uub" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/30/web-roulette" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39971</id><published> 2023-05-30T17:47:03Z</published><updated> 2023-05-31T16:33:43Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Sarah Perez, writing for TechCrunch:</p><blockquote><p> If mindlessly browsing the internet is your preferred way to combat boredom and waste time, the indie app makers behind to-do list app Clear and game Heads Up have a new product you&#39;ll want to try: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id6448401688">Web Roulette</a> , a mobile web browser app for iOS built for the short attention spans of the TikTok era. With the debut version out now, you can add your favorite websites or choose from its suggestions, then swipe through the sites to see what&#39;s new or shake the app for a surprise webpage when boredom strikes.</p><p> The team says the idea initially struck them as something of a joke. But they soon realized the idea of a &#39;swipeable,&#39; shakable web browser that delivered our daily hits of dopamine may actually have merit.</p><p> “I mean, this is actually how I spend much of my time browsing the web — I bounce back and forth mindlessly and semi-randomly between my favorite sites, hoping for something fresh. Maybe there&#39;s something here?,” explains Impending founder and designer Phill Ryu.</p></blockquote><p> I&#39;ve been beta testing Web Roulette for a week or two and it&#39;s just plain dumb fun. In the early days of the App Store (and before that, the early days of the web), it was common for people to come up with a dumb fun idea that could be made in a week or two. Web Roulette exemplifies that ethos. It&#39;s not useful, per se, but it&#39;s not use <em>less</em> either. But it&#39;s mainly just fun. I&#39;m so glad to see that coming back.</p><p> <strong>See also:</strong> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTRojEWBw/">This fun launch video on TikTok</a> — interrupted by a special guest. And <a href="https://twitter.com/UseClear/status/1661462990162481152">this tweet with a sketch</a> of the team&#39;s original concept. I love comparing “here&#39;s the napkin sketch of the original idea” to the shipping product.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Web Roulette — A Swipeable Randomized Web Browser’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/30/web-roulette">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> &#39;Lisa&#39;s Final Act</title><link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OFJxFAyT7p8" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uua" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/lisas-final-act" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39970</id><published> 2023-05-29T22:01:46Z</published><updated> 2023-05-30T22:38:52Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Trailer for a new documentary from The Verge:</p><blockquote><p> Sabotage, hired goons, and a landfill in Utah: this is a story about the life, death, and afterlife of Apple&#39;s most pioneering computer, the Lisa. A major inspiration for the Macintosh, Steve Jobs championed the Lisa, then turned against it. In Lisa&#39;s Final Act, The Verge unearths a new spin on this tale. We discover the outsider who gave the maligned computer another chance… before Apple closed the door on the Lisa forever.</p></blockquote><p> Full documentary debuts tomorrow.</p><p> <strong>Update:</strong> Right on schedule, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rZjbNWgsDt8">the full 30-minute documentary is out</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘‘Lisa’s Final Act’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/lisas-final-act">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://www.fifthstarlabs.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu8" rel="shorturl"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2023/05/sky_guide" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/feeds/sponsors//11.39968</id><author><name> Daring Fireball Department of Commerce</name></author><published> 2023-05-29T19:42:00Z</published><updated> 2023-05-29T19:42:06Z </updated><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Sky Guide brings the beauty of the stars down to Earth. Thanks to AR, understanding the cosmos has never been simpler — just hold it overhead to automatically identify any star, constellation, planet or satellite. Developed as a native iOS app over the past decade by a small team, Sky Guide will transform the way you explore the night sky with easy-to-use, yet powerful features. Start your stargazing journey today!</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Sky Guide’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2023/05/sky_guide">★</a></div> ]]>;</content><title> [Sponsor] Sky Guide</title></entry><entry><title> &#39;Succession&#39; Finale </title><link href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-recaps/succession-finale-recap-masterful-feel-bad-ending-shiv-roy-power-move-hbo-sarah-snook-jeremy-strong-1234740344/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu9" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/sepinwall-succession-finale" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39969</id><published> 2023-05-29T19:41:08Z</published><updated> 2023-05-29T19:41:08Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Alan Sepinwall, writing for Rolling Stone:</p><blockquote><p> A lot happens over the course of the 90-minute <em>Succession</em> series finale, “With Open Eyes.” Alliances are made, broken, and made again. Votes happen, fortunes rise and fall, losers become winners, and vice versa.</p><p> For all intents and purposes, though, the only part that matters is a five-minute sequence toward the end.</p></blockquote><p> I&#39;m always wary of recency bias, but at the moment I&#39;d put <em>Succession</em> in the hall of fame for the best TV shows ever. Four great seasons, a rich ensemble of vivid memorable characters, never a bad episode, and a truly great finale.</p><p> See also: <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-lists/succession-characters-ranked-least-despicable-to-most-hbo-1234736505/roman-roy-1234736560/">Sepinwall&#39;s ranking of the top 25 characters on Succession, from least to most despicable</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘‘Succession’ Finale’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/sepinwall-succession-finale">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> The Talk Show: &#39;One True HIG&#39; </title><link href="https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2023/05/29/ep-376" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu6" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/the-talk-show-376" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39966</id><published> 2023-05-29T19:07:00Z</published><updated> 2023-06-02T16:34:21Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Neil Jhaveri, founder and lead developer of Mimestream, the terrific new native Mac email client for Gmail, joins the show to talk about email, Mac apps, and indie software development.</p><p> Sponsored by:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://www.drinktrade.com/thetalkshow">Trade Coffee</a> : Let&#39;s Coffee Better. Get a free bag of fresh coffee with any Trade subscription.</li><li> <a href="https://memberful.com/talkshow">Memberful</a> : Monetize your passion with membership. Start your free trial today.</li><li> <a href="https://rocketmoney.com/thetalkshow">Rocket Money</a> : Stop throwing your money away. Cancel unwanted subscriptions and manage your expenses the easy way.</li></ul><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Talk Show: ‘One True HIG’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/the-talk-show-376">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Adam Engst: &#39;Why I Use Mimestream for Gmail&#39; </title><link href="https://tidbits.com/2023/05/24/why-i-use-mimestream-for-gmail/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu7" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/engst-mimestream" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39967</id><published> 2023-05-29T19:06:31Z</published><updated> 2023-05-29T19:06:32Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Adam Engst, writing at TidBITS:</p><blockquote><p> Mimestream 的亮点在于它对视觉形式和功能细节的关注——让使用电子邮件感觉熟悉、流畅和快速的小界面元素和功能。我每天花几个小时在电子邮件上，虽然我愿意稍微调整我的工作习惯以匹配应用程序的功能，但我更喜欢它来适应我的特质。</p><p>例如，我很少删除消息。我的 Google 帐户有足够的空间，并且 Gmail 的性能不会因大量电子邮件存储而降低，因此我更愿意为后代保留所有内容，并将注意力集中在未读和已加星标的邮件上。因此，我的电子邮件客户端支持这种方法而不是推行自己的收件箱零概念或它可能拥有的任何哲学是至关重要的。</p><p>我无法预测哪些改进和可供性将使使用您的电子邮件成为一种乐趣，因此我想分享一些我认为 Mimestream 令人信服的地方。其中许多并不是独一无二的，它们只是做得非常好，结果是使用 Mimestream 感觉就像驾驶一辆设计精良的汽车，而不是一辆低端汽车，感觉它是用便宜的、非现场组装的-货架组件。</p></blockquote><div> <a  title="永久链接到“Adam Engst：‘为什么我将 Mimestream 用于 Gmail’”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/engst-mimestream">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>小立德</title><link href="https://l.kolide.co/3JWbXEv" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu5" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/kolide" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39965</id><published> 2023-05-29T16:42:30Z</published><updated> 2023-05-29T16:42:31Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>感谢 Kolide 对 DF 的持续赞助支持——他们上周赞助了 Daring Fireball，并且他们是<a href="https://ti.to/daringfireball/the-talk-show-live-from-wwdc-2023/">即将举行的 WWDC 现场脱口秀的</a>赞助商。他们是一家伟大的公司，拥有伟大的产品。</p><p>这是一个令人不安的事实：在大多数公司，员工可以将敏感的公司数据下载到任何设备上，并永远保存在那里，甚至不知道他们做错了什么。 Kolide 的新报告<a href="https://l.kolide.co/3I7025A">《敏感数据状况》</a>直接解决了这个问题。</p><p> Kolide 提供了一种比 MDM 解决方案更细致的方法来设置和执行敏感数据策略。他们的前提很简单：如果员工的设备不合规，就无法访​​问您的应用程序。 Kolide 让管理员可以运行查询来检测敏感数据、标记违反政策的设备，并强制执行操作系统和浏览器更新，从而使易受攻击的设备无法访问数据。</p><p>要了解更多信息并查看 Kolide 的实际应用，<a href="https://l.kolide.co/3XlSqAq">请访问 kolide.com</a> 。</p><div><a  title="“Kolide”的永久链接"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/29/kolide">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> WordPress 20 岁生日</title><link href="https://ma.tt/2023/05/wp20-audrey-scholars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu4" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/28/wordpress-turns-20" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39964</id><published> 2023-05-28T14:38:28Z</published><updated> 2023-05-28T17:58:58Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>有趣的是，从长远来看，什么会获得牵引力，而事后看来，却只是昙花一现。就我个人而言，我从来没有预料到 WordPress 会发展成为<a href="https://w3techs.com/technologies/details/cm-wordpress">迄今为止</a>世界上最受欢迎的 CMS，并且是<a href="https://automattic.com/">一家蓬勃发展的公司</a>的基础，其主要目标是让网络成为一个更好的平台。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“WordPress 20 周年”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/28/wordpress-turns-20">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Mimestream 1.0 </title><link href="https://mimestream.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu3" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/27/mimestream" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39963</id><published> 2023-05-27T23:37:09Z</published><updated> 2023-05-27T23:37:10Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>经过几年的公开测试，Mimestream 1.0 发布了，它非常棒。 Mimestream 是专门针对 Gmail 的 Mac 电子邮件客户端。他们有扩展到 iOS 的计划，并计划在未来可能扩展到 IMAP（和 JMAP）电子邮件帐户，但就目前而言，Mimestream 做了一件事并且做得非常好：它是一个真正的 Gmail Mac 应用程序.它既是一款出色的 Mac 应用程序，也是一款出色的 Gmail 客户端。每月 5 美元或每年 50 美元，可免费试用两周。</p><p> <a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2023/05/mac-gmail-client-mimestream-reaches-1-0/">Jason Snell</a> :</p><blockquote><p>苹果邮件是免费的。浏览器窗口中的 Gmail 是免费的。但是在 Mimestream 工作了两年之后，我无法快速放下信用卡。</p></blockquote><div> <a  title="永久链接到“Mimestream 1.0”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/27/mimestream">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Mona：适用于 Mac 和 iOS 的 Mastodon 客户端</title><link href="https://mastodon.social/@MonaApp" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu2" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/27/mona" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39962</id><published> 2023-05-27T17:18:20Z</published><updated> 2023-05-27T17:18:21Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>我<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/ivory-for-mac">昨天开玩笑</a>说，我认为 Ivory for Mac 不仅是最好的 Mac Mastodon 客户端，而且是唯一的好客户端。<a href="https://appdot.net/@lapcatsoftware/110438201331572138">一群</a>读者<a href="https://masto.ai/@felixbernoully/110439214565712262">赞同</a>Junyu Kuang 的 Mona 是一个<a href="https://infosec.exchange/@ender3/110441484789265773">很好</a>的 Mac 客户端。我曾尝试过 Mona，发现它在 Mac 上有很多不足之处，但昨天我又看了一眼，我的读者是正确的：它现在是一个非常可靠的 Mac 客户端。免费试用，只需 10 美元即可在任何一个平台（Mac、iPhone、iPad）上成为“专业”用户，只需 16 美元即可在所有三个平台上成为专业用户。这些是在 6 月 1 日上涨的<a href="https://mastodon.social/@MonaApp/110418544209519828">介绍性价格</a>。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“Mona：适用于 Mac 和 iOS 的 Mastodon 客户端”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/27/mona">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>平台游戏：“推特内部失败的太空发射” </title><link href="https://www.platformer.news/p/inside-twitters-failed-space-launch" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu1" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/platformer-twitter-spaces" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39961</id><published> 2023-05-27T01:52:29Z</published><updated> 2023-05-27T01:52:29Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Zoë Schiffer 和 Casey Newton，平台游戏的报道：</p><blockquote><p>空间托管在 Twitter 自己的服务器和从 Amazon Web Services 租用的服务器上。一位参与该项目的前员工表示，Spaces 的 AWS 服务器相对于它们的需求“供应不足”。</p><p>周三，服务器短缺导致了一系列可预见的连锁故障。在活动筹备阶段，工程师预计 Spaces 能够容纳数十万用户。但是太多人同时加入了第一个流，结果应用程序一直崩溃。</p><p>我们被告知，马斯克自己的 Twitter 应用程序在活动期间多次崩溃。马斯克使用了名为 Earlybird 的应用程序的员工专用版本，据说事后大发雷霆。</p></blockquote><p>我确定他是。</p><blockquote><p>在前鸣叫者最大的 Slack 和 Discord 频道内，DeSantis 的拙劣公告后的情绪简直是欢欣鼓舞。</p></blockquote><p>我确定是的。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“Platformer：‘Inside Twitter’s Failed Space Launch’”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/platformer-twitter-spaces">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Texas Monthly Profiles Tapbots 创始人 Paul Haddad 和 Mark Jardine </title><link href="https://www.texasmonthly.com/news-politics/texas-tweetbot-developers-fighting-twitter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uu0" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/texas-monthly-tapbots" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39960</id><published> 2023-05-27T01:38:35Z</published><updated> 2023-05-27T01:38:35Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>说到 Tapbots，安德鲁·洛根 (Andrew Logan) 为《德州月刊》撰文：</p><blockquote><p>住在 Round Rock 的 Twitter 前开发者平台产品负责人 Amir Shevat 负责确保 Twitter 为使用该平台的独立软件开发者提供的工具满足他们的需求。他说，从历史上看，Twitter 上大约 17% 的参与度是通过第三方应用程序实现的，这些应用程序在定义 Twitter 的身份方面发挥了至关重要的作用。</p></blockquote><p>据我所知，Twitter 的（或以前的）没有人曾经透露过这一点。显然，绝大多数 Twitter<em>用户</em>只使用过 Twitter 自己的第一方客户端。然而，第三方客户端对 Twitter 如此重要的原因是 Twitter<em>高级用户</em>被他们吸引了。</p><blockquote><p> Jardine 说他收到了关于 Ivory 最初发布的积极反馈，他承认发布时没有他想要包含的所有功能。他说，用户对他的工作感到兴奋令人振奋。但这并不是他的全部动力。 “没有 [象牙]，我们就没有生意，”贾丁说。 “它承受着很大的压力。”</p><p>尽管压力重重，但哈达德似乎在这个勇敢的新世界中蒸蒸日上。 “我不再是独裁者的心血来潮，”他说。</p></blockquote><p>但愿如此。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“Texas Monthly Profiles Tapbots Founders Paul Haddad and Mark Jardine”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/texas-monthly-tapbots">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>适用于 Mac 的象牙色</title><link href="https://tapbots.com/ivory/mac/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/utz" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/ivory-for-mac" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023:/linked//6.39959</id><published> 2023-05-27T01:26:11Z</published><updated> 2023-05-27T23:47:22Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>现在在 Mac App Store 上架：Tapbots&#39;s Ivory for Mac。我已经在测试版中使用它几个月了，不知道没有它我该怎么办。它不仅是最好的 Mac Mastodon 客户端，而且是现存的唯一优秀客户端。 Mac 客户端每年 15 美元，但真正的优惠是 Ivory 在 MacOS 和 iOS 上的 25 美元/年“通用”订阅 Ivory。</p><p> Ivory for Mac 是使用 Catalyst 编写的，但它绝不只是 Ivory for iPad 稍作调整。 （如果是这样的话，Tapbots 可能会在几个月前发布它，<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/01/24/ivory-1">当时 Ivory for iPhone 和 iPad 发布了</a>。）Ivory for Mac 是一款 Mac 应用程序。但是，许多催化剂主义都表现出来了。系统范围的服务菜单项不起作用。智能标点符号（当您键入两个连字符时自动卷曲引号和适当的破折号）仅在您缓慢键入时有效。有些视图通过标准键盘快捷键（空格/shift-空格、Page Up/Page Down）滚动，但有些则不然。很多这些都是我认为 Apple 的 Catalyst 框架中的缺点——20 多年前 Cocoa 的全部要点是标准控件开箱即用的标准行为，使开发人员从制作简单的预期平台标准功能的苦差事中解脱出来工作。 Catalyst 不是那样的——或者至少现在还不是那样。</p><p>但这是 Ivory for Mac 1.0。 Beta 测试期间的进展是稳定的，并且知道 Tapbots 的高标准，我很确定会继续如此。总的来说，今天的 Ivory for Mac 不仅仅是地狱里的一杯冰水，而是一整壶。如果您在 Mac 上使用 Mastodon，如果您不尝试 Ivory，那您就疯了。</p><p><strong>另请参阅：</strong> <a href="https://www.macstories.net/reviews/ivory-for-mac-review-tapbots-superb-mastodon-client-comes-to-apple-desktops-and-laptops/">John Voorhees 在 MacStories 上的评论</a>。</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Ivory for Mac’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/05/26/ivory-for-mac">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/05/bajarin_wwdc_headset" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/uta" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023://1.39934</id><published> 2023-05-19T19:00:37Z</published><updated> 2023-05-19T19:10:07Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">我们不会认为主题演讲太长了；我们会头晕目眩地从中脱颖而出，因为它会涵盖如此之多，如此之快。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/benbajarin/status/1659593595643662336-vhv6gL8w">本·巴加林在 Twitter 上</a>：</p><blockquote><p>如果 Apple 今年发布 VR/AR 耳机，那么在秋季举办专门活动或将其与 Mac 活动捆绑在一起会更有意义。</p><p> WWDC 涵盖的内容太多，30 分钟不足以讲述完整的产品故事。</p></blockquote><p>我也一直在思考这个问题。 WWDC 主题演讲<em>总是</em>座无虚席。近年来，Federighi 已将 Apple 的软件工厂打造得井井有条，以至于每个平台总有重大更新。 iOS/iPadOS 17、MacOS 14 和 WatchOS 10 将发布和演示主要的新功能。我怀疑我们将看到新的 Mac 硬件发布。如果它只是 15 英寸的 MacBook Air，那很容易宣布：它是配备更大显示屏的 MacBook Air。但如果是 M 系列 Mac Pro（终于），<em>那将</em>需要一些演示时间。<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/apple-events-video/id275834665?i=1000565413850">去年的主题演讲</a>时长为 1 小时 48 分； <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/6/23141939/apple-wwdc-2022-biggest-announcements-ios-16-macbook-air-macos-watchos">这是 The Verge 发布的主要公告的摘要</a>。</p><p>但我确实认为耳机将在 WWDC 上发布。烟太多了，不可能生火。 And, seemingly, Apple isn&#39;t quietly trying to dampen expectations for the headset behind the scenes.同样的事情也发生在 2007 年 Macworld Expo 之前的 iPhone 上——有大量谣言称苹果手机终于要来了，而且没有人从消息来源那里听到它不会到来的消息。理想情况下，他们可能希望在今年的 WWDC<em>之前</em>在一个特别活动中宣布它，但如果他们希望开发人员开始为该平台创建软件，现在是时候了。 （为什么他们不希望开发人员开始研究想法？）</p><p> Apple 不喜欢主题演讲超过两个小时。浮现在脑海中的明显例外是 WWDC 2015 主题演讲，它耗时 2 小时 25 分。那是一个有很长一段关于 Apple Music 的节目，Jimmy Iovine 也在舞台上。可能是有史以来最糟糕的 WWDC 主题演讲，也是唯一一个感觉排练不足的演讲。</p><p>不过，事情是这样的：后 COVID 主题演讲不仅是预先录制的，而且经过了非常严格的编辑。我怀疑我们会得到一个主题演讲，即使整个 40 分钟左右的片段都宣布了耳机和 xrOS，仍然会在 2 小时内出现。它会走得很快。将头显和 xrOS 开发者框架融入老式的 WWDC 舞台主题演讲会带来问题。我不认为新的“主题电影”格式有问题。 <sup id="fnr1-2023-05-19"><a href="#fn1-2023-05-19">1</a></sup>我们不会认为主题演讲太长了；我们会头晕目眩地从中脱颖而出，因为它会涵盖如此之多，如此之快。</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2023-05-19"><p>如果我是对的，我敢打赌这是在主题演讲结束后，人们开始仔细研究 Apple 在网络上发布的所有内容的年份，我们发现了数量惊人的非常酷的 iOS 和 MacOS 功能，这些功能并没有使其成为主题演讲。操作系统的所有内容都可能被削减，以便为耳机、xrOS 和 Mac 硬件发布腾出时间。下午有整个第二个国情咨文技术主题演讲，可以从上午的主要主题演讲中删除一些功能。 <a href="#fnr1-2023-05-19"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ 关于 Apple 在总是座无虚席的 WWDC 主题演讲中加入耳机公告</title></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/05/do_wall_street_journal_reporters_read_the_wall_street_journal" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/ut6" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023://1.39930</id><published> 2023-05-19T01:41:49Z</published><updated> 2023-05-20T00:34:04Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">从某种意义上说，Apple *确实*在进入一个新产品类别时有一个传统：他们努力让第一个产品好到可以被批评。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Aaron Tilley 和 Yang Jie 上周为《华尔街日报》报道，“ <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-is-breaking-its-own-rules-with-a-new-headset-80c9b36c">Apple 正在用新耳机打破自己的规则</a>”（ <a href="https://apple.news/AdSGSL1h8RBa5WioRJe_T9g">News+ 链接</a>）：</p><blockquote><p> Apple 的发布计划打破了许多已成为行业黄金标准的关于新产品的传统和规则。与其他 Apple 产品不同，该设备以仍处于试验阶段的模式首次亮相。 Apple 预计，与 Apple Watch 或 iPhone 相比，这款头显的普及速度较慢，而 Apple Watch 和 iPhone 都很快成为消费者的必备品。在进入市场之前经过七年的开发，它将成为任何公司销售过的最复杂的消费产品之一。</p></blockquote><p>在一个段落中要解压的内容太多了。开始：</p><p>我认为苹果公司从来没有以同样的方式推出过两款新产品。每一个新产品的推出都是不同的。老实说，除了谣言工厂的共识之外，我对耳机的了解不多，但我保证它不处于“实验模式”。 Apple Watch 和 iPhone 都没有“迅速成为消费者的必备品”。 <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-watch-with-sizable-sales-cant-shake-its-critics-1461524901">这是 Daisuke Wakabayashi</a>在...<em>支票笔记</em>中的一份报告...2016 年 4 月，即 Apple Watch 发售一年后的《华尔街日报》本身，在开篇段落中说，“然而，智能手表被一种观念所困扰，即鉴于 Apple 最受欢迎的设备的历史：失望似乎为时过早。” （下一段声称“iPhone 的销售正在放缓”。） <sup id="fnr1-2023-05-18"><a href="#fn1-2023-05-18">1</a></sup></p><p> Apple 进入新产品类别的模式通常是这样的：</p><ul><li> Apple 发布第一个版本。它的价格昂贵。它缺少一些明显的特征。它有一些明显的局限性。但这是一个突破。</li><li>尝鲜者通宵在 Apple Stores 外排队购买。在线销售在推出后不久就会缺货数周甚至数月。</li><li>撇开早期的热情不谈，它是一款早期采用者产品，销量低于 Apple 的成熟产品。</li><li>几个月或一年后，痴迷于即时满足的商业媒体刊登了<a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/apple-watch-with-sizable-sales-cant-shake-its-critics-1461524901">文章</a>，宣称该产品是无用的。</li><li> Apple 发布了更好的第二代版本。销售额上升。消息继续传播。</li><li> Apple<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2010/05/this_is_how_apple_rolls">每年都会</a>发布改进的型号。添加了那些明显缺失的功能。删除了明显的限制。旧型号以较低的价格继续销售。它成为热门产品。</li><li>多年后，当 Apple 准备发布另一款全新产品时，最后一款产品——在第一年就被认为是无用的产品——从第一天起就被公认为轰动一时、轰动一时的产品。</li></ul><p> Aaron Tilley 和 Yang Jie 报告中的几段之后：</p><blockquote><p>对于 Apple 十年来的第一款主要新产品——Apple Watch 于 2014 年发布——首席执行官蒂姆库克有很多话要说，因为该设备试图主宰人们花时间工作或休闲的虚拟世界，称为元宇宙，尚未达到大规模采用或理解。</p><p>一些投资者和潜在的未来合作伙伴越来越怀疑消费者会在 metaverse 上花费金钱和时间。他们注意到一些早期采用者对这项技术感到失望。</p></blockquote><p>这也许是旁注，但我认为 AirPods 是一款重要的新产品——而 AirPods Pro 是第一款真正面向大众市场的增强现实设备。事实上，它们只是音频而非视觉，这让人们（抱歉）看不到它们是<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2019/10/airpods_pro_first_impressions">卓越的 AR 产品</a>这一事实。 Apple 没有公布单位销售额，但估计表明，如果 AirPods——只是 AirPods——是一家独立的公司，<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2010/05/this_is_how_apple_rolls">它的收入将超过</a>Nvidia、Adobe 或 Uber，并可能很快赶上 Netflix。但这是旁注。</p><p>更大的问题是，早在 10 月份，<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2022/10/26/stern-federighi-joz">在一次台上采访中</a>，Greg Joswiak 被要求完成“虚拟宇宙是……”这句话，他的回答是，“……一个我永远不会使用的词。 ”人们不使用甚至不知道元宇宙到底意味着什么这一事实与苹果的耳机无关。我不知道 Joz 如果当时不透露 Apple 的头戴式耳机，会说得更清楚——Apple<em>并没有制造与市场上其他公司已经拥有的产品一样的产品</em>。舞台上的采访是……<em>支票</em>……<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m-ugwoEOMvg">乔安娜·斯特恩在《华尔街日报》Tech Live 会议上</a>。这足以让你认为《华尔街日报》的记者不读《华尔街日报》。</p><p>迄今为止推出的 XR 头戴式耳机都没有在宇宙中产生太大的影响，但这并不表明苹果的努力是不幸的。这表明苹果有机会。从某种意义上说，苹果在进入一个新的产品类别时<em>确实</em>有一个传统：他们努力把<a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/40435064/what-alan-kay-thinks-about-the-iphone-and-technology-now">第一个产品做得好到可以被批评</a>。</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2023-05-18"><p>这是 2016 年 Wakabayashi 为该杂志发表的同一份报告中的预测年鉴的一段话：</p><blockquote><p>然而，也有一些批评者，例如风险投资公司 Union Square Ventures 的联合创始人弗雷德·威尔逊 (Fred Wilson)，他在 12 月宣布 Watch 是“失败的”。威尔逊先生通过一个基金持有 Fitbit 的股份，他早些时候预测 Watch 不会像 iPad、iPhone 和 iPod 那样成为“本垒打”，他说很多人不想在手腕上戴电脑。</p></blockquote><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2016/01/02/fred-wilson-predictions">Fred Wilson</a> ，<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2014/05/05/wilson">仅次于</a><a href="https://nypost.com/2023/03/10/cnbcs-jim-cramer-touted-silicon-valley-bank-stock/">Jim Cramer</a> 。 <a href="#fnr1-2023-05-18"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ Do Wall Street Journal Reporters Read The Wall Street Journal? </title></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/05/lets_check_in_on_supermicro" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/ut4" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023://1.39928</id><published> 2023-05-18T21:19:24Z</published><updated> 2023-05-18T22:17:56Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">多么可耻的故事的后记。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@kimahlberg/110386827166566142">Kim Ahlberg，在 Mastodon 上发帖</a>：</p><blockquote><p>在阅读<a href="https://mastodon.social/@gruber">@gruber</a>的帖子后，将一些资金投入到 SMCI 的帖子中，这些帖子在他们的废话故事中大声疾呼 Bloomberg¹ 到目前为止，这是一个很好的举措……</p><p> ¹ 彭博社当然是在 2018 年 10 月发表了“The Big Hack”一文的出版物——一个耸人听闻的故事，声称苹果、亚马逊和其他数十家公司的数据中心受到了中国情报部门的破坏。这个故事根本没有提供确凿的证据。</p></blockquote><p> Supermicro (SMCI) 是一家公司，其服务器主板被彭博社指控受到流氓芯片的损害，流氓芯片旨在偷偷打电话给中国情报服务器。彭博社当时提供了零实际证据，五年后，发现了这种流氓芯片的零证据。彭博社指控的每家公司都断然否认了该报告。布隆伯格从未撤回该报告，因此永远玷污了他们的新闻诚信。<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/10/bloomberg_the_big_hack">这是我对这个故事的第一份报告</a>，<a href="https://daringfireball.net/search/bloomberg+big+hack">这个搜索</a>应该会让你看到我的后续行动。</p><p>当彭博社发布他们引人注目但看似完全错误的报告时， <a href="https://www.wolframalpha.com/input?i=smci+stock+price+september+2018+to+november+2018">Supermicro 的股价暴跌近一半</a>，从每股 21.50 美元跌至 11.65 美元。</p><p>我不敢相信我从未想过要跟进他们的股价，因为我多年来一直热心地提醒人们，通过彭博社其他报道中的脚注，“The Big Hack”根据所有可用证据完全是胡说八道，但从来没有收回。</p><p>事实证明，Supermicro<a href="https://www.wolframalpha.com/input?i=smci+stock+price+september+2018+to+may+2023">在随后的几年里表现不错</a>。他们的股票今天收于 164.56 美元——比“大黑客”下跌后高出 14 倍多。对于 Ahlberg 和其他任何进行类似投资的人来说，这是<a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/05/supermicro-stock-2018-2023.jpeg">一笔可观的回报</a>。多么可耻的故事的后记。</p> ]]>;</content><title> ★ 让我们看看 Supermicro，彭博社“The Big Hack”的目标</title></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/05/gm_edsel" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/usv" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023://1.39919</id><published> 2023-05-17T02:27:30Z</published><updated> 2023-05-18T02:10:30Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">通用汽车到 2030 年实现 20-250 亿美元的服务收入目标感觉就像一个肯德尔·罗伊 (Kendall Roy) 的数字——有人凭空在 Excel 电子表格中编造数字，直到他们得到他们正在寻找的 SUM() 结果。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/05/09/gm-hires-ex-apple-exec-mike-abbott-to-lead-new-software-unit.html">Michael Wayland，上周为 CNBC 报道</a>：</p><blockquote><p>通用汽车已聘请前苹果公司高管迈克·阿博特领导底特律汽车制造商新成立的软件部门。 Apple 云服务部门前工程副总裁 Abbott 将加入通用汽车，担任软件执行副总裁，自 5 月 22 日起生效。他将向通用汽车首席执行官 Mary Barra 汇报工作。</p><p>雅培新设立的职位将汇集公司内部的三个独立职能：软件定义车辆和操作系统；信息和数字技术；以及公司的数字业务。 [...]</p><p>通用汽车的目标是到本十年末提高利润率并将收入翻一番，达到约 2800 亿美元。这包括新业务部门和软件的显着增长。</p></blockquote><p>我不熟悉 Mike Abbott，但听起来他的专长完全在于云服务，而不是面向用户的软件设计和工程。所以我不认为巴拉在想“ <em>Apple 创造了人们喜爱的优秀软件，所以我们应该从 Apple 聘请知道如何领导这样一个团队的人</em>”， <sup id="fnr1-2023-05-16"><a href="#fn1-2023-05-16">1</a></sup> ，而是更像是“ <em>Apple 已经建立了每年 800 亿美元的服务每个季度都在持续增长的部门，所以我们应该聘请知道如何领导这样一个团队的人</em>”。巴拉关注的是<a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2023/05/apple-q2-2023-results-94-8b-revenue-better-than-expected/">苹果的服务收入</a>，而不是苹果 CarPlay 的质量。</p><p>很好，也许像雅培这样的人正是通用汽车需要的人。但我不看这个聘用，并认为通用汽车更有可能为自己的平台提供 CarPlay 质量的界面。巴拉对通用汽车服务收入目标的一些粗略计算让我觉得迈克·阿博特的任务是设计一款嵌入式老虎机。</p><p>当<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/04/gm_carplay_iphones">通用汽车上个月宣布他们将从他们的电动汽车中删除 CarPlay 时</a>， <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/gm-plans-phase-out-apple-carplay-evs-with-googles-help-2023-03-31/">路透社报道</a>称“巴拉的目标是到 2030 年通过订阅获得 200 亿至 250 亿美元的年收入。”</p><p>这似乎雄心勃勃。</p><p>让我们看看通用汽车目前的订阅服务收入。 <a href="https://www.fool.com/investing/2022/07/24/why-wall-street-loves-this-new-car-option-that-dri/">这是 Larry Printz，去年 7 月为 Motley Fool 撰文</a>：</p><blockquote><p>据公司官员称，通用汽车在 2021 财年创造了近 20 亿美元的订阅服务收入和超过 70% 的息税前利润率。这家汽车制造商目前拥有超过 400 万用户。 2021 年，通用汽车的全球收入为 1270 亿美元，这意味着如果预测属实，OnStar 占通用汽车全球收入的 1.6%。虽然这看起来对利润的贡献微乎其微，但由于安吉星最近的加入，这个数字应该会增长。</p><p>通用汽车最近宣布了其 SuperCruise 自动驾驶功能的订阅计划，新车前三年免费。它还通过智能手机应用程序向非通用汽车的车主开放 OnStar，这应该会带来更多的订户和收入。</p></blockquote><p>到 2030 年，要从 20 亿美元增长到 200 亿美元（巴拉既定目标的低端），可以肯定的是，她预计这种增长将来自未来的汽车销售，而不是目前已经上路的通用汽车。</p><p> <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/225326/amount-of-cars-sold-by-general-motors-worldwide/">通用汽车每年销售约 600 万辆汽车</a>，但自 2016 年达到 1000 万辆的峰值以来，这一数字一直在下降。据推测，这些未来的服务将需要配备通用汽车新软件平台的车辆。现在他们声称该系统只会用于电动汽车，到 2022 年，<a href="https://insideevs.com/news/629611/us-gm-plugin-car-sales-2022q4/">通用汽车销售的汽车中只有 1.7% 是全电动汽车</a>。</p><p>因此，让我们大方地说，到 2030 年，通用汽车已售出 3000 万辆符合条件<em>并订阅</em>公司新服务的汽车。我认为 3000 万是非常慷慨的——如果不是离奇的话——并且要求他们也将新的软件平台安装到他们的汽油和混合动力汽车中。请记住，他们在 2021 年只有 400 万订户，而且他们的汽车销量正在下​​降。</p><p>来自 3000 万订户的 200 亿美元收入 = 666 美元/年/车辆 = 55 美元/月/车辆。这符合他们目前每个服务订户每年平均 500 美元的收入（根据上面的 Motley Fool，来自 400 万订户的 20 亿美元收入），但每个订户的收入是很多。我只是不明白他们如何从今天的 400 万用户增长到 2030 年的 3000 万或更多。</p><p>他们可以提供哪些新车购买者每月愿意支付超过 50 美元的服务？地图和导航？每个人的手机上都已经有了。音乐和播客？每个人的手机上都已经有了。崩溃检测？到 2030 年，每个人都将在他们的手机上拥有它（或者至少<a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT213225">如果他们拥有 iPhone</a> ，他们将会拥有，但我敢打赌，这也将很快成为 Android 手机的标准功能）。通用汽车想出售“基于行为的保险”（翻译：跟踪/监视），但<a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/autos-transportation/gm-set-launch-behavior-based-us-driver-insurance-q1-executive-2022-01-24/">据路透社报道</a>，到 2030 年，他们的保险目标仅为 60 亿美元/年。我发现很难看到其余的钱从哪里来.</p><p>通用汽车的高管可能会梦想购车者会向通用汽车支付费用，因为他们已经通过不支持 CarPlay 和 Android Auto 的手机获得了服务，但今天的现实表明，人们只需购买 5 美元的支架即可将手机连接到汽车的仪表盘上。如果所有其他汽车制造商都继续支持 CarPlay 和 Android Auto，那么这整个努力似乎将变成一个昂贵的骗局，将潜在的通用汽车买家引向其他品牌。</p><p> One idea that occurred to me is the equivalent of Apple&#39;s services revenue dark matter: payments from Google for default placement as Safari&#39;s search engine.苹果和谷歌都没有透露过这些数字，但<a href="https://9to5mac.com/2022/01/05/apple-default-search-engine/">最近的一项估计</a>将其定为每年 200 亿美元。至少，它是每年 100 亿美元。这些来自谷歌的付款进入了苹果季度业绩中的“服务”。 Apple 现在报告每个<em>季度</em>的服务收入为 200 亿美元——因此其中大部分来自 App Store，然后是客户对 iCloud Plus、Apple Music 等的订阅，但其中大约 20-25% 来自谷歌付费成为 Safari 中的默认搜索引擎。通用汽车即将推出的内部软件系统不支持 CarPlay 或 Android Auto，而是与谷歌合作（基于谷歌名称混乱的<a href="https://source.android.com/docs/devices/automotive/start/what_automotive">Android Automotive</a>平台），大概谷歌地图（和/或<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/8/23499734/google-maps-waze-development-teams-combined-productivity">Waze</a> ？）将是唯一的选择地图和导航，也许谷歌会为这种特权向通用汽车支付费用？对于音乐等其他服务的默认位置？不过，即使达成协议，我也看不出它如何使通用汽车每年的服务收入接近 200 亿美元。 Apple 从 Google 获得 15-200 亿美元用于在<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/27/22253162/iphone-users-total-number-billion-apple-tim-cook-q1-2021">超过 10 亿部</a>iPhone、iPad 和 Mac 上的 Safari 中放置默认搜索引擎。即使是我最仁慈、最乐观的估计，到 2030 年符合条件的通用汽车汽车也只有 3000 万辆。谷歌向通用汽车支付每辆汽车以提供默认地图应用程序的费用会比他们为每部 iPhone/iPad/Mac 支付给苹果公司的费用多 30-40 倍吗？这对我来说没有意义，但我认为从理论上讲，映射监控数据对谷歌来说是有价值<em>的</em>。不过，我真的他妈的怀疑。</p><p>我能想到的唯一一件通用汽车可以为司机无法通过手机获得的订阅服务是半自动驾驶。通用汽车将其称为 Super Cruise，<a href="https://www.onstar.com/plans/premium">目前收费 25 美元/月</a>，或者对同时订阅 OnStar 的司机收取 15 美元/月的费用。 （OnStar 提供路边援助和碰撞检测——同样，到 2030 年，每个人都将免费使用他们的手机。）但 Super Cruise 可以作为独立的订阅功能存在<em>，同时</em>支持 CarPlay 和 Android Auto——事实上今天也是如此。为 Super Cruise 收取订阅费并不需要通用汽车放弃对 CarPlay 和 Android Auto 集成的支持。</p><p>我看不出这些大概数字有什么意义。这是一场反对电话在人们生活中的首要地位的巨大赌注，在任何行业中，还没有人在反对电话的赌注中获胜。通用汽车到 2030 年实现 20-250 亿美元的服务收入目标感觉就像一个<a href="https://succession.fandom.com/wiki/Kendall_Roy">肯德尔·罗伊 (Kendall Roy) 的数字</a>——有人凭空在 Excel 电子表格中编造数字，直到他们得到他们正在寻找的<code>SUM()</code>结果。</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2023-05-16"><p>我不认为这有任何可能发生，但想象一下如果通用汽车聘请斯科特福斯特尔领导他们的软件部门。那会很有趣。 <a href="#fnr1-2023-05-16"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.">↩︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ 通用汽车即将推出的内部软件平台的拟议名称（你知道，那个不支持 CarPlay 的平台）：Edsel </title></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/05/browser_and_os_market_share_trends_in_the_mobile_age" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/us8" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2023://1.39896</id><published> 2023-05-02T23:11:18Z</published><updated> 2023-05-18T02:25:38Z</updated><author><name> John Gruber</name><uri> http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text"> Windows 的衰落，以及 Safari 和 Mac 的缓慢而稳定的崛起。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jbenton/status/1653394051889082368">Joshua Benton 在推特上</a>链接到<a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share/desktop/united-states-of-america#monthly-202201-202303">Statcounter 的 3 月份美国浏览器共享数据</a>：</p><blockquote><p> Safari 在美国的桌面浏览器份额首次超过 20%</p><p>自去年 6 月以来，Chrome 下降了 6%（61.35% 至 55.28%），而 Safari 也上升了相似的幅度（15.58% 至 22.3%）。</p><p> Seems driven entirely by increased Mac market share. Over the same span, Windows is down 14% (67.57% to 53.43%) and macOS is up 6% (24.27% to 31.34%). ChromeOS went from 3.75% to 8.47% (though the school year makes that comp a bit unfair).</p></blockquote><p> <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share/desktop/worldwide/#monthly-202201-202303">Statcounter&#39;s latest <em>global</em> numbers</a> :</p><ul><li> Chrome: 66.1%</li><li> Safari: 11.9%</li><li> Edge: 11%</li><li> Firefox: 5.7%</li><li> Opera: 3.1%</li></ul><p> Looking at the <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share/desktop/worldwide/#monthly-202201-202303">global chart</a> , Chrome seems to be holding steady in the desktop market over the last year, but Safari does show an uptick from about 9.5 to just under 11 percent. As Benton points out, the most striking thing in Statcounter&#39;s report is the decline in Windows&#39;s desktop OS share over the last year, both <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/desktop/worldwide#monthly-202201-202303">globally</a> and <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/desktop/worldwide#monthly-202201-202303">in the US</a> I suspect Windows is losing share to <em>mobile</em> browsing just as much as or more than it is to MacOS and ChromeOS. Back when Windows had over 90 percent market share, a huge chunk of that was people who didn&#39;t really choose a Windows PC because of Windows, but who just wanted a “computer”. They took the default, and the default computer ran Windows.</p><p> Nowadays, Windows still gets most of the default <em>desktop</em> market (although it seem ChromeOS continues to eat into that, especially in K-12 education). But for more and more people, their default “computer” is their phone. They might have a PC, but they use it less and less.</p><p> Which brings me to another real eye-opener: Statcounter&#39;s OS market share numbers — across all devices, desktop and mobile — from 2009 until now.</p><p> <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share#monthly-200901-202303">Globally</a> :</p><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/05/StatCounter-os_combined-ww-monthly-200901-202303.png" class="noborder"><img
    src = "https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/05/StatCounter-os_combined-ww-monthly-200901-202303.png"
   width = 500
    alt="Chart showing Statcounter's global market share for operating system from January 2009 through March 2023."
  /></a></p><p> <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/all/united-states-of-america#monthly-200901-202303">United States</a> :</p><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/05/StatCounter-os_combined-US-monthly-200901-202303.png" class="noborder"><img
    src = "https://daringfireball.net/misc/2023/05/StatCounter-os_combined-US-monthly-200901-202303.png"
   width = 500
    alt="Chart showing Statcounter's U.S. market share for operating system from January 2009 through March 2023."
  /></a></p><p> Globally, Windows was surpassed by Android back in 2017. The decline in Windows&#39;s dominance has been precipitous: in 2009 Statcounter pegged its share at 95 percent; today it&#39;s 28 percent. In the US, Windows is effectively neck-and-neck with iOS, each hovering around 30 percent for the last few years. It doesn&#39;t seem outlandish to project that Mac and iOS, combined, might soon surpass Windows and Android combined in Statcounter&#39;s share numbers for the US</p><p> The Mac, on the other hand, is clearly seeing impressive market share growth. We all kind of knew this was true from the Mac revenue numbers <a href="https://sixcolors.com/tag/quarterly/">Apple reports each quarter</a> , but Statcounter&#39;s data backs up Apple&#39;s claims that the Mac continues to gain new users. And that in turn leads to more desktop Safari users — even though recent switchers strike me as among the most likely Mac users to use Chrome, which they&#39;re likely familiar with. But if desktop Safari usage share is growing, it must mean Mac usage is growing.</p><p> The rise of iOS and Android as humanity&#39;s primary computing platforms has obliterated Windows&#39;s decades-long hegemony. To be fair, when your usage share was at one time 95 percent <em>of all web browsing</em> , there&#39;s nowhere to go but down. But today, Windows is just one of four major platforms — and is the only one of the four that is in obvious decline, both in usage and relevance. The Mac, on the other hand, has seemingly been <em>bolstered</em> by the rise of the iPhone. We talked a lot about <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2007/10/milhouse">the “halo effect” of the iPod</a> on Mac sales in the mid-2000s, but it&#39;s more true today with the iPhone and iPad. Mac unit sales are up and its share of desktop computing is <em>way</em> up. People who don&#39;t care about desktop computing are just using their phones and tablets for everything; people who do care are more likely than ever to be using a Mac.</p><p> One more nugget, just for kicks — <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/mobile/united-states-of-america#monthly-202201-202303">US</a> and <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/os-market-share/mobile/worldwide#monthly-202201-202303">worldwide</a> numbers for iOS and Android in the mobile market:</p><table><thead><tr><th></th><th>我们</th><th>Global</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td> iOS</td><td> 60</td><td> 30</td></tr><tr><td> Android</td><td> 40</td><td> 69</td></tr></tbody></table><p> It&#39;s also worth noting on the charts above that in hindsight, it wasn&#39;t clear that mobile browsing would surpass desktop browsing until 2013 or 2014 — six or seven years after the debut of the iPhone. That&#39;s a timeframe worth keeping in mind for — oh, just to pick a random up-and-coming product category — AR/VR headsets. The iPhone did change everything, but it took a while to show it outside the enthusiast / early-adopter market.</p> ]]>;</content><title> ★ Browser and OS Market Share Trends in the Mobile Age</title></entry></feed><!-- THE END -->