<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>大胆的火球</title><subtitle>约翰·格鲁伯</subtitle><link href="https://daringfireball.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/main" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><id> https://daringfireball.net/feeds/main</id><updated> 2024-02-02T06:00:48Z</updated><rights>版权所有 © 2024，约翰·格鲁伯</rights><entry><title>PCalc、Fantastical 和超过 598 个其他原生 VisionOS 应用程序将于发布当天在 App Store 中提供</title><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/02/apple-announces-more-than-600-new-apps-built-for-apple-vision-pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vaj" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/02/01/pcalc-and-599-other-visionos-apps" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40555</id><published> 2024-02-01T23:52:55Z</published><updated> 2024-02-01T23:52:56Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>苹果新闻编辑室：</p><blockquote><p>借助 Apple Vision Pro 上的 NBA 应用程序，篮球迷可以通过多视图直播或点播多达 5 个直播节目，关注实时球员和球队统计数据，并轻松浏览其他比赛和比分。 MLB 让用户沉浸在棒球场中，可以看到本垒板的视图和每个球场的统计数据。 Red Bull TV 显示比赛的 3D 地图，并配有高质量视频和身临其境的环境。足球迷可以在美国职业足球大联盟 (Major League Soccer) 的主场 Apple TV 应用程序上访问 MLS Season Pass。兼容来自顶级有线电视服务公司（包括 Charter Spectrum、Comcast Xfinity、Cox Contour、Sling TV 和 Verizon Fios）以及体育广播公司（包括 ESPN、CBS、Paramount+、NBC、NBC Sports、Peacock、FOX Sports 和 UFC）的应用程序Vision Pro 用户始终拥有室内最好的座位。</p><p>除了 Disney+ 之外，顶级娱乐应用程序还利用 Apple Vision Pro 的独特功能，为观众提供观看他们喜爱的电影、节目等的全新方式。 IMAX 为 2D 和 3D 内容提供令人惊叹的观看体验，其中以 IMAX 扩展宽高比的<em>《深空》</em>等流行纪录片为特色。</p><p>华纳兄弟探索频道 (Warner Bros. Discovery) 的 Max 提供热门电影和连续剧、新鲜原创作品、家庭最爱、突发新闻和体育直播，其中精选影片提供 4K 和杜比全景声 (Dolby Atmos) 空间音频。 HBO 和 Max Content 董事长兼首席执行官 Casey Bloys 表示：“借助 Apple Vision Pro 的 Max 应用程序，粉丝们可以利用铁王座房间环境改造他们的空间，获得身临其境的体验，将观众带入标志性的红堡。” “错综复杂的坦格利安时代的装饰会让粉丝们感觉他们正在观看维斯特洛麦克斯在统治鼎盛时期播放的节目。”</p></blockquote><p>尽管 Netflix 和 YouTube 在发布时决定完全避开该平台，但事实是，在发布时有<em>很多</em>原生 VisionOS 应用程序，以及无数兼容的 iPad 应用程序。还有<a href="https://mastodon.social/@jamesthomson/111858221733883492">一个很棒的计算器应用程序</a>和<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ccsMSGVBoxQ">一个很棒的日历应用程序</a>。</p><p> （Apple 在 VisionOS 中没有内置计算器应用程序，而内置日历应用程序是兼容模式下的 iPad 应用程序，这使得 PCalc 和 Fantastical 成为 App Store 中<em>唯一</em>同类的原生应用程序。）</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“PCalc、Fantastical 和超过 598 个其他原生 VisionOS 应用程序将于发布日在 App Store 中提供”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/02/01/pcalc-and-599-other-visionos-apps">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/the_vision_pro" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vai" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2024://1.40554</id><published> 2024-01-30T20:00:35Z</published><updated> 2024-02-02T06:00:48Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">耳机、空间生产力平台和个人娱乐设备。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>在过去的六天里，我一直在同时测试苹果公司的三款全新产品。第一个是带有眼球追踪控制的 VR/AR 耳机。第二个是革命性的空间计算生产力平台。第三是突破性的个人娱乐设备。</p><p>耳机、空间生产力平台和个人娱乐设备。</p><p>我相信你已经明白了。这些不是三个独立的设备。它们是一个：Apple Vision Pro。但如果你能原谅对史蒂夫·乔布斯著名的 iPhone 介绍的无耻致敬，我认为这三个角度是考虑它的最佳方式。</p><h2>硬件</h2><p>Vision Pro 的盒子大得出奇。我原本期待一个与 HomePod 盒子大小差不多的包裹；相反，Vision Pro 零售盒<a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2024/01/homepods-v-vision-pro.jpeg">比<em>两个</em>堆叠在一起的 HomePod 盒要大得多</a>。 （我拥有的 HomePod 比大多数人都多。）</p><p>里面有很多东西。包装的上半部分包含 Vision Pro 耳机本身，以及已安装的轻质密封件、轻质密封垫和默认的 Solo 针织表带。下半部分包含电池、充电器 (30W)、电缆、双环带、入门书（精美的全彩印刷、精美的纸张 - 感觉就像纪念品）、抛光布<sup id="fnr1-2024-01-30"><a href="#fn1-2024-01-30">1</a></sup> 、和一个额外的轻质密封垫。</p><p>要打开 Vision Pro，请将外部电池组的电源线连接到 Vision Pro 的电源连接器，然后将其旋转四分之一圈以将其锁定到位。耳机一毛钱大小的电源插座上有一些小点，显示如何对齐电缆连接器的小 LED。 Vision Pro 打开时，LED 会闪烁。 （我怀念苹果发光的电源指示灯 LED — 这是一种非常令人愉悦的触感。）当 Vision Pro 完成启动并准备使用时，它会发出令人愉悦的欢迎声音。</p><p>然后戴上 Vision Pro。如果您使用的是 Solo 针织表带，则可以使用右耳后面的表带上的旋钮来收紧和松开它。 VisionOS 会指导您适当升高或降低耳机，将其放置在您脸部相对于眼睛的正确高度。如果Vision Pro认为您的眼睛离显示器太近，它会建议您切换到“+”尺寸的光密封垫。您会得到两个轻质密封垫，但它们并不相同：我的标有“W”和“W+”。 “+”的宽度相同，以匹配您的光密封，但会在您的眼睛和 Vision Pro 内的显示屏之间增加一点点空间。对我来说，默认的（非“+”）就很合适。</p><p>然后，该软件将引导您通过一系列屏幕来校准眼动追踪。这一切都非常明显，而且很有趣。这几乎就像一个简单的游戏：你盯着圆圈中的一系列点，并在盯着每个点时捏住你的食指和拇指。您会在三种不同的人工照明条件下经历三次这样的过程：黑暗、中等和明亮。在首次运行体验即将结束时，系统会提示您将 iPhone 或 iPad 放在附近，就像设置新 iPhone 或 iPad 时一样。这允许您的 Vision Pro 获取您的 Apple ID 凭据和 Wi-Fi 密码，而无需手动输入任何内容。这是一个非常顺利的入职过程。就这样，您就进入并使用了 Vision Pro。</p><p> Vision Pro 硬件的一些基本问题是无法回避的。</p><p>首先，它使用通过电源线连接的外部电池组。电池本身的宽度和高度与 iPhone 15/15 Pro 差不多，但更厚。而且电池很重：约 325 克，而 iPhone 15 Pro 为 187 克，15 Pro Max 为 221 克。它的厚度和重量更接近<em>两部</em>iPhone 15，而不是一部。而且拴着的电源线可能会很麻烦。 Vision Pro 没有内置备用电池 - 从耳机上拔下电源线，耳机会立即关闭。它牢固地卡入到位，因此不存在意外断开连接的风险。但如果你花<a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MW283LL/A/apple-vision-pro-battery">200 美元购买一块额外的 Vision Pro 电池</a>，你就不能热插拔它们——你需要先关机。</p><p>其次，Vision Pro<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/vision-pro-weight">很重</a>。我一次使用它几个小时，没有任何不适，但仅从重量来看，疲劳感确实出现了。你永远不会忘记你戴着它。与 Vision Pro 的重量相关的是它相当大。你脸上戴着一副又大又重的护目镜。无论是从你佩戴它的第一人称视角，还是从你佩戴它时其他人看着你的第三人称视角来看，它都没有什么微妙之处。</p><p> Apple 关于调整 Vision Pro 在脸部位置的建议之一是平衡前额和脸颊之间脸部的重量/压力。我发现这是个好建议。最初，我的直觉是将其放置在我脸上稍微太低的位置，这导致系统建议将其放置得更高。它需要正好放置在您的脸上，以便您通过其显示屏看得清楚，并且它可以通过 Optic ID（Vision Pro 相当于 Face ID）看到您的眼睛，用于解锁设备并确认需要身份验证的操作（例如访问来自钥匙串或购买应用程序的密码）。一两天之内，我就很自然地穿上它，无需为合身而大惊小怪。</p><p>默认的弹力单圈针织带不仅适合我，而且从舒适性和便利性方面来说，我更喜欢它，而不是双环带。使用 Solo 针织带时，您可以将其戴上并通过扭转上述旋钮来收紧。当你把它取下来时，你先松开它。您希望它在脸上足够紧，以至于每次戴上/脱下时不必收紧/松开它是不切实际的。这有点像习惯新的表带——一开始感觉很挑剔，但你很快就会形成肌肉记忆。除了了解将 Vision Pro 放在脸上的高度之外，尝试一下 Solo Knit Band 在<em>后脑勺</em>上的高度对于获得一致的贴合度至关重要。</p><p>为什么 Vision Pro 配备了完全不同的双环带设计？ Apple 的入门指南用一种美妙的委婉说法描述了其目的：“Apple Vision Pro 还配备了双环表带，如果您想要不同的佩戴方式，这是一个不错的选择。”翻译：如果 Solo 针织带不舒服，您应该尝试一下。 Vision Pro 是一款非常个人化的设备。它不仅在你的脸上，因为它对感觉和触觉非常敏感，而且它很重，需要与你的眼睛精确对齐。您还确实希望光密封能够隔绝光线。<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/VisionPro/comments/19ardw5/all_light_seal_sizes/">这篇 Reddit 帖子</a>建议光密封有 28 种不同的尺寸。 28！ （我认为 N 和 W 分别代表<em>窄</em>和<em>宽</em>。）根据您的脸型、头部大小和头发量，单人针织带可能效果不佳。双环带有两条尼龙搭扣带 - 一条穿过后脑勺，另一条穿过顶部。使用双环带的用户每次佩戴和摘下 Vision Pro 时可能都需要松开和收紧两条带子。</p><p>如果这一切听起来有点繁琐，那是因为它确实如此。但没有办法解决这个问题：它需要精确的配合才能保证舒适度和光学对准。</p><p>许多人注意到，对于一家推出健身相关设备（Watch）和服务（Fitness+）的公司的产品来说，Vision Pro 没有健身相关的营销角度。实在是太重了。没有人愿意将 650 克的设备绑在脸上进行锻炼。有一天，苹果会推出一款适合健身的 Vision 耳机；这个Vision Pro不是吗。</p><p>另一个需要一些时间来适应的方面是简单地操作 Vision Pro。您需要学会通过设备本身周围的铝框而不是光密封来固定它。尝试握住它或通过光密封将其拿起，密封将会弹出。光密封件通过磁性附着在 Vision Pro 上，光密封垫通过磁性附着在密封件上。它们很容易安装和拆卸，并自动卡入到位 - 但如果您使用轻型密封件（或垫子）来拾取组合单元，它们就会拆卸。 （适用于眼镜佩戴者的蔡司镜片插件也可以通过磁性卡入到位，并且插入和取出都很简单。）</p><p>您无需在摘下 Vision Pro 前将其置于睡眠状态，也无需在佩戴时将其唤醒。您只需将其脱下并戴上，系统就会自动检测您是否正在使用它。您可以永久保留电池。</p><p>我怀疑Vision Pro的正面很容易被划伤。这是一种需要小心处理的设备。苹果公司的说明建议每次使用完后盖上盖子，就像喝完碳酸饮料后将盖子盖回瓶子上一样。我认为它本身并不精致，但它绝对不坚固。</p><p>我的评测套件包括<a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MW2F3LL/A/apple-vision-pro-travel-case">Apple 价值 200 美元的旅行箱</a>。与 Vision Pro 零售盒一样，我发现它大得出奇。它会占用大多数笔记本电脑背包内的大部分内部空间，事实上，旅行箱本身的大小大约相当于一个小孩的背包。我非常期待在旅行时使用 Vision Pro，但您需要计划一下您的行李。 <sup id="fnr2-2024-01-30"><a href="#fn2-2024-01-30">2</a></sup></p><p>在两周前的一篇短文中——在我在家评测这个设备之前，但在纽约与苹果公司进行了另一次动手演示之后——<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/vision-pro-battery">我写道</a>：</p><blockquote><p>几乎每一个第一代产品都存在这样的问题——由于技术的限制而存在明显的缺陷。最初的 Mac 的 RAM (128 KB) 和存储空间（单个<a href="https://lowendmac.com/2016/floppy-disk-compatibility-and-incompatibility-in-the-mac-world/">400 KB 单面软盘驱动器</a>）太少。最初的 iPhone 仅支持 2G EDGE 蜂窝网络，速度<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enhanced_Data_rates_for_GSM_Evolution#:~:text=EDGE%20can%20carry%20a%20bandwidth,much%20traffic%20as%20standard%20GPRS.">慢得不可思议</a>，而且在语音通话时根本无法使用。最初的 Apple Watch 速度非常慢，一次充电很难坚持一整天。第一代 Vision Pro 的外部电池组仅提供 2 至 2.5 小时的电池续航时间。此外，Vision Pro 耳机本身（没有任何内置电池）仍然太大太重。</p><p><a href="https://paulgraham.com/really.html">保罗·格雷厄姆有一句精彩的格言</a>：</p><blockquote><p>不要担心人们会说什么。如果您的第一个版本令人印象深刻，以至于巨魔不会取笑它，那么您等待发布的时间太长了。</p></blockquote></blockquote><p> Vision Pro 还没上市，就已经受到嘲笑。 （发货前的 iPhone 也是如此；最初的 Macintosh 也是如此。）几年后，在几代产品之后，我们<em>都会</em>在回顾第一台 Vision 设备时大笑。我们会嘲笑外部电池，我们会嘲笑设备的尺寸和重量，最终我们会嘲笑它的价格。无可否认，对它的批评都是真实的：它对每个人来说都太重、太大，而且对大众市场来说太贵。</p><p>但是，就像第一代 iPhone 和之前的第一代 Macintosh 一样，第一代 Vision Pro 并不是开玩笑。</p><h2> VisionOS平台</h2><p>早在 6 月份，在 WWDC 上进行了 30 分钟的 Vision Pro 演示后，我写道：</p><blockquote><p>苹果<a href="https://twitter.com/tim_cook/status/1665806600261763072">将</a>​​ Vision Pro 的发布宣传为“空间计算时代”的到来。这个词感觉很完美。这不是 AR、VR 或 XR。这是空间计算，空间计算的某些<em>方面</em>是AR或VR。</p><p>对我来说，麦金塔电脑更像是一个<em>地方</em>，而不是一个<em>东西</em>。不是我身体上去的地方，而是我思想上智力上去的地方。当我工作或玩耍时，总感觉 MacOS 就是我<em>所在的</em>地方。我在Mac上。当我在 Mac 上工作时，干扰（例如门铃或电话铃声）会暂时让我迷失方向，因为我被拉出了那个世界，进入了现实世界。 iOS 也有类似的效果，但我总觉得它没那么深刻。部分原因是 iOS 的本质，它不像 MacOS 那样对我说话。我认为这在很多方面解释了为什么我在 iPad 上的感觉不像在 Mac 上那样<em>流畅</em>，即使显示屏尺寸相同。但对于 iPhone，尤其是屏幕尺寸是一个重要因素。我认为<em>任何</em>假想的手机操作系统都不可能像 MacOS 那样具有沉浸感，因为即使是最大的手机显示屏也很小。在手机上看电影的体验不如在大电视机上看电影，甚至在大电视上看电影也比在漂亮的剧院看电影的体验差。我们人类是视觉动物，我们的视野会影响我们的重要性感。大小事项。</p><p>可以说，MacOS 和 iOS（或 Windows、Android 或其他）的<em>世界</em>是由它们运行的​​显示器定义和限制的。如果说 MacOS 是我工作时精神上所去的地方，那么这个地方就通过 Mac 的显示屏来体现。这就像体育运动中的比赛场地或球场——它有非常清晰、坚硬和快速的矩形边界。它具有固定的大小和形状，我在那个世界中所做的一切都发生在这些显示边界的范围内。</p><p> VisionOS 很可能会成为一个类似于工作场所的概念性场所。但没有任何显示。没有界限。 VisionOS 应用程序呈现的智能“场所”是您使用设备的现实世界场所，或者是您选择的广阔虚拟环境。你所坐的房间就是画布。整个房间。 Mac 或 iOS 设备上的显示屏对我来说就像一个门户，一个进入明确定义的虚拟世界的矩形窗口。借助 VisionOS，虚拟世界就是您周围的现实世界。</p><p>就像 iPhone 引入的多点触控消除了一层概念抽象一样 — 您只需触摸屏幕上的对象，而不是触摸鼠标或触控板将屏幕上的指针移动到屏幕上的对象 — VisionOS 消除了空间抽象层。使用 Mac 时，您位于一个物理位置，该位置前面有一个显示器，该显示器上有应用程序窗口。使用 VisionOS，您所在的物理位置只有应用程序窗口。周一，我并排打开了 Safari、消息和照片，每个窗口都像电影海报一样大小，也就是说，窗口中的每个应用程序都比我见过的任何实际计算机显示器都大用过的。一切并排。 <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2023/06/introducing-apple-vision-pro/">Apple Newsroom 帖子中介绍 Vision Pro 的一些视频</a>就说明了这一点。但是，在这种环境中看到演员的照片并不能真正亲身体验它，因为显示这种环境的照片本身已经定义了矩形边框。</p><p>这并不令人困惑或复杂，但感觉很深刻。</p></blockquote><p>这可能是我在文章中包含的最长的块引用。但在使用 Vision Pro 近一周后，我现在无法比当时更好了。在最初 30 分钟的经历之后，我的预感是完全正确的。</p><p>第一代 Vision Pro<em>硬件</em>受到当前技术限制的严重限制。苹果已经通过多种方式突破了这些限制，但这些限制是显而易见的。 Vision Pro 是一款落地耳机，定义了沉浸式耳机技术的最新技术水平。但随着岁月的流逝，这块土地将在后视镜中消失。就像 Mac 的 9 英寸单色 512⁠×⁠342 像素显示屏一样。就像 iPhone 的 EDGE 蜂窝调制解调器一样。</p><p>但VisionOS的概念设计为交互设计的全新方向奠定了基础。就像最初的 Mac 界面的基本概念是完全正确的一样，并且至今仍然如此。就像最初的 iPhone 定义了现在世界上每部手机的工作方式一样。</p><p>没有实用的方法可以让 Mac 或 PC 周围有多个外部显示器，从而为自己提供 VisionOS 中工作区大小的工作区画布。 VisionOS 工作空间不是<em>无限的</em>，但它感觉尽可能接近无限大。这是你周围的世界。</p><p>而且非常有<em>空间感</em>。窗户仍然固定在您周围的世界中。设置几个窗户，然后站起来走开，当你回来时，那些窗户就在你离开的地方。穿过它们真是不可思议。 （从后面看，它们看起来是白色的。）您可以做看似疯狂的事情，例如将 VisionOS 应用程序窗口放在现实世界窗口之外。</p><p>窗口也保持它们相对于彼此的位置。按一下数字表冠按钮即可调出 VisionOS 主视图。长按数字表冠按钮可根据您当前的视线重新调整视图。因此，举例来说，如果一切在您看来都显得太低，请向上看，然后按住数字表冠。所有打开的窗口都将重新集中在您当前的视野中。但当你站起来移动时，这也有效。</p><p>你可以开始在厨房等地方工作。打开“消息”、“Safari”和“便笺”。从左到右排列您周围的三个窗口。站起来，走到客厅。这些窗户仍然在你的厨房里。坐在沙发上，按住数字表冠。现在，这些窗户移动到您的客厅，重新以您当前的视线为中心，但彼此之间的位置和大小完全相同。这就像拥有一个多显示器设置，您可以轻松移动到您想去的任何地方。</p><p>几十年的 Mac 使用经验让我认为窗口控件位于窗口的顶部。在 VisionOS 中，它们位于底部。这花了我一两天的时间来适应——当我想到“我想关闭这个窗口”时，我的眼睛自然会转向左上角。 VisionOS 窗口实际上只有三个控件：一个关闭按钮和下面的“窗口栏”，以及每个角落的调整大小指示器。一旦你开始使用它，就很容易明白为什么苹果把窗口栏放在底部而不是顶部：如果它在顶部，当你拖动窗口来移动它时，你的手和手臂会遮挡窗口内容。由于该栏位于底部，因此移动窗口内容时根本不会被遮挡。</p><p> VisionOS 工作空间看起来如此广阔的部分原因是它完全自然地使用 Z 轴（深度）。拖动窗口时，将其拉近或推远就像向左或向右移动一样容易。旋转它们，将窗口排列在您周围的半圆形中，也是完全自然的。这就像科幻小说一样令人兴奋。 Mac 自 40 年前诞生以来，一直有 Z 轴的概念，用于将窗口堆叠在一起，但有了 VisionOS，情况就完全不同了。在 VisionOS 中，窗口停留在您放置它们的深度，而在 Mac 上，当您激活它们时，窗口会弹出到堆栈的前面。</p><p>长按窗口的关闭按钮，您可以选择关闭所有其他打开的窗口，就像 Mac 应用程序菜单中的“隐藏其他”命令一样。 （长按在整个 VisionOS 中都很有用。）</p><p>您周围现实世界的直通视图意味着您可以在佩戴 Vision Pro 时站立并四处走动。它一点也不感觉不安全或迷失方向。事实上，这是异常自然的。但对于<em>使用</em>Vision Pro 来说，显然需要您保持静止，以固定的姿势坐着或站着。除了将 Vision Pro 用作相机之外，我想不出还有什么理由在走路时<em>使用</em>它。应用程序窗口相对于<em>您的</em>位置并不固定 - 它们相对于您周围的世界的位置是固定的。</p><p><a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-vision-pro/guided-tour/">苹果的导览视频</a>比任何书面描述都更能传达使用该平台的基本要点。最重要的是：你看着东西，然后点击你的食指和拇指来“点击”或抓住你正在看的东西。听起来如此简单明了，但却是交互设计的突破。 Mac 为我们提供了“点击”功能。 iPhone 给了我们“点击和滑动”的功能。 Vision Pro 为我们提供了“查看并点击”的功能。这种交互模型的一个方面并不立即直观，那就是——除了一些明显的例外——你不会伸手去戳你直接看到的东西。即使在读完本文之后，您一开始也会想要这样做。但它对大多数事情都不起作用，而且即使有效也会很快变得令人厌烦。相反，您只需将手放在腿上或桌面上即可，只要它们处于最舒服的休息位置即可。</p><p> VisionOS 的虚拟键盘是值得注意的例外之一。 （键盘，复数，包括 QWERTY 打字键盘和用于输入设备密码的数字键盘，如果 Optic ID 由于某种原因失败。）VisionOS 虚拟键盘有<em>两种</em>工作方式 — 您可以注视要按下的每个键并点击您可以用手指和拇指依次激活它们，也可以伸出手戳虚拟按键。这两种方法都适合输入一个或两个单词（或 6 位密码）；这两种方法都不适合实际写作。 Siri 听写非常适合较长的文本输入，但如果您想在没有听写的情况下进行任何书写，则需要配对蓝牙键盘。虚拟键盘比在 Apple Watch 上打字要好，但也好不了多少。</p><p>使用蓝牙键盘的一个不可思议的方面是 VisionOS 在键盘上呈现虚拟 HUD。此 HUD 包含自动完成建议，并在一行中显示您正在键入的文本。对于那些不看键盘就无法打字的人来说，这是一种方便。在带有物理键盘的 Mac 或 iPad 上，您实际上只需移动眼睛即可从查看显示屏转向键盘。在 VisionOS 上，您需要移动头部，因为窗户往往离您更远，而且空间更高。这个小 HUD 可以让您在盯着物理键盘的同时看到您正在输入的内容。这很奇怪，但以一种好的方式。一周过去了，拥有一个带有可点击自动完成建议的物理键盘仍然让我脸上露出笑容。</p><p> VisionOS 还可以与 Magic Trackpad 或蓝牙鼠标配合使用。鼠标光标是一个圆形，就像 iPadOS 中的一样。您在窗口之间的空间中看不到光标；它只会出现在您正在查看的任何窗口内。</p><p> Mac 虚拟显示功能既实用又直观。如果您有 MacBook，只需打开 MacBook 盖子，VisionOS 就会在 MacBook 打开的显示屏上方显示一个弹出窗口，其中有两个按钮：“连接”和一个关闭按钮。点击“连接”按钮，您将获得一个与 Studio 显示屏大小相当的虚拟 Mac 显示屏。您可以像 VisionOS 中的任何其他窗口一样移动此窗口并调整其大小。虽然您无法增加它所代表的像素数量，但您可以将其放大到非常大。它非常有用，在连接时，您的 MacBook 键盘和触控板也可以在 VisionOS 应用程序中使用。您还可以使用 VisionOS 中的控制中心手动启动 Mac 虚拟显示模式（您可以通过点击视图顶部的一个小 V 形图标，向上看天花板或天空来访问该控制中心）。</p><p>上周我已经多次使用这种模式，唯一的问题是我不断发现自己想要使用 VisionOS 的“凝视和点击”与虚拟 Mac 显示屏内的元素进行交互。那是行不通的。因此，当我的手放在物理键盘和触控板上时，Mac（虚拟 Mac 显示屏内）和 VisionOS 应用程序上的一切都可以正常工作，但是当我的手离开物理触控板时，我用手指到拇指敲击在 VisionOS 应用程序窗口中，每次我将注意力转回虚拟 Mac 显示屏中的 Mac 应用程序时，我都会发现自己徒劳地用手指敲击来激活或单击我正在查看的任何内容。这类似于从 iPad 切换到 MacBook 并尝试触摸屏幕，但更糟糕的是，因为使用 VisionOS 中的虚拟 Mac 显示屏，您需要在 Mac 环境和 VisionOS 应用程序之间不断进行上下文切换。触控板在这两种情况下都能完美工作； “查看并点击”仅适用于 VisionOS（或仅用于移动、调整大小或激活虚拟 Mac 显示屏，而不是与其中的 Mac UI 交互）。</p><p> VisionOS 已经是 1.0.1 版本（当我设置它时，1.0.0 版本的软件更新已经可用），并且有一堆 1.0 错误。我不得不多次强制退出应用程序（包括“设置”）。 （同时按住顶部按钮和数字表冠按钮几秒钟，您会看到 MacOS 风格的“强制退出”对话框；继续按住这两个按钮，您可以强制重新启动系统。）</p><p>目前还没有很多原生 VisionOS 应用程序，但 iPad 应用程序确实运行良好。原生 VisionOS 应用程序和 iPad 应用程序之间的主要区别并不在于 VisionOS 应用程序运行得更好，而在于它们看起来更酷。在我看来，VisionOS 是自 iOS 1-6 中最初的拟物化 iPhone 界面以来苹果公司推出的最美观的操作系统。实际深度和阴影——真是个好主意。</p><p> VisionOS 主视图上的应用程序无法手动组织——即使在 1.0 版本中，这也是一个奇怪的遗漏。 （尤其是考虑到 Apple 吹嘘拥有无数兼容的 iPad 应用程序。）所有 iPad 应用程序（包括 Apple 本身的一堆内置应用程序，包括新闻、图书、日历和地图）都放在“兼容的应用程序”中。 Apps”文件夹，并有圆形图标。本机 VisionOS 应用程序位于应用程序视图的根级别，并具有圆形图标。</p><p> VisionOS 的基本交互模型感觉将被所有未来的 VR/AR 耳机复制，就像所有台式电脑都像 Mac 一样工作，而现在所有手机和平板电脑都像 iPhone 一样工作。当这种情况发生时，有些人会争辩说，当然他们都是这样工作的，因为否则他们怎么能工作呢？但在 Mac 出现之前，个人电脑并没有点击式 GUI，而在 iPhone 出现之前，手机也没有“这只是一个大触摸屏”的界面。目前还没有其他耳机具有“只需看着目标，然后点击手指和拇指”的界面。我怀疑几年后他们都会这么做。</p><h2>硬件，再次，A/V 版</h2><p>这让我回到 Vision Pro 的硬件。显示器非常出色，但我已经开始发现它们还不够好。眼动追踪非常好，但没有我希望的那么精确。这些相机很好，但它们无法达到您实际视力的动态范围。有时，您的视野周边会出现色边，具体取决于照明情况。您身边的光源（例如白天的窗户）会显示条纹。当你移动头部时，真正穿越的幻觉就被打破了——你可以看出你正在观看通过摄像机镜头展示世界的显示器。只需四处走动就足以打破现实世界自然穿越的错觉。事实上，在某些方面，沉浸式 3D 环境（山顶、湖畔、月球表面（！））在视觉上比实际的现实世界更加真实，因为平移视线时的延迟和剪切更少。</p><p>我使用过最初的 PlayStation 5 VR 耳机 HTC Vive Pro，并拥有一台 Meta Quest 3。Vision Pro 的显示质量使这些耳机看起来像是来自不同时代。 Vision Pro 处于不同的领域，玩着不同的游戏。在分辨率方面，Vision Pro 令人惊叹。我从来没有看到像素。我看到文字就像在现实生活中一样清晰。读起来很舒服。 （尽管很奇怪，但一周后，Safari 窗口看起来有 6 或 7 英尺高）。但我已经可以想象出<em>更好的</em>Vision 耳机显示屏。我已经可以想象摄像机镜头和我眼前的显示器之间的延迟会更低。我已经可以想象更大的动态范围，就像白天从昏暗的房间内向窗外看一样。</p><p> Vision Pro 的显示屏令人惊叹，但显然还不够好。</p><p>另一方面，扬声器简直令人惊叹。我从来没有经历过像他们这样的事情。我预计它们听起来不错，但不如 AirPods Pro 或 Max。相反，我发现它们听起来比我戴过的任何耳机都要好得多。这是因为它们实际上是扬声器，最佳位置位于您的耳朵前面。总有一个问题，Vision Pro 扬声器的问题是它们根本不是私人的。坐在您旁边的人可以听到您所听到的声音；您附近的人可以听到您听到的大部分内容。在公共场所或靠近其他人的地方使用 Vision Pro 时，出于隐私和礼貌的考虑，您需要佩戴 AirPods，而不是出于音频质量的考虑。</p><p>扬声器还传达出一种不可思议的空间现实感。</p><p>最后，我在使用 Vision Pro 充满电的情况下始终获得了 3 个小时的电池续航时间。有时多一点。根据我的经验，Apple 声称的 2-2.5 小时电池续航时间只是一个下限，而不是上限。在长时间的训练中我也没有感到身体不适或恶心。 <sup id="fnr3-2024-01-30"><a href="#fn3-2024-01-30">3</a></sup></p><h2>我很想，但应该抵制，在本节标题中使用“不受欢迎的人”双关语</h2><p><em>人物角色</em>是 Vision Pro 的一大亮点。您的角色是您头部和肩膀的数字化身，在进行 FaceTime 通话或使用其他采用 API 的视频通话软件时，它会代替您出现。发布时已包括 Zoom、Webex 和 Microsoft Teams。</p><p>苹果公司将整个角色功能显着地标记为“测试版”，只要一看就知道为什么。人物角色很奇怪。他们处于<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uncanny_valley">恐怖谷</a>的深处。不会将角色与真实的人混淆。有时，他们看起来更像是电子游戏中的角色，而不是逼真的面容。在任何时候，他们看起来<em>都有点</em>像电子游戏角色。例如，我的头发看起来就像闪亮的塑料乐高假发。</p><p>即使捕捉到你的角色也很尴尬。您必须将 Vision Pro 从头上取下并转动它，以便摄像头（和激光雷达传感器？）可以看到您，但您无法获得摄像头所捕获内容的良好图像，因为前置 EyeSight 显示屏是分辨率相对较低。你的头发可能会被发带弄乱，你需要在镜子前检查一下自己，以确保你的衬衫光滑。</p><p>拍完我的照片后，我和我妻子进行了 FaceTime 通话，她的反应——完全不知道会发生什么——是“不，不，不——天哪，这是什么？”然后她就开始笑。测试结束时，她告诉我：“不要再这样叫我了。”她是在开玩笑（我认为），但角色在恐怖谷中是如此之深，以至于任何人第一次看到角色时，他们都会想要谈论它。</p><p>苹果在这个功能上陷入了困境。在目前的状态下，该功能显然值得突出的“测试版”标签。但你也可以明白为什么苹果需要在发布时包含该功能，无论它离“好”有多远。今天，您无法运送不能用于视频会议的生产力计算机。这就像电子邮件或网页浏览：必不可少。但这只剩下两个选择：卡通般的拟我表情，或者尝试照片写实主义。几乎可以肯定，苹果公司可以为此目的而将 Memoji 头像从公园中剔除，但我认为正确的决定是，这在大多数专业工作环境中是完全不合适的。你可以用拟我表情与你的家人和朋友进行 FaceTime，他们会不加评判地接受它，但专业同事或客户却不会。</p><p>为了保护现在存在的角色，我发现我在通话几分钟后就习惯了它们。 （我与 Apple 佩戴 Vision-Pro 的代表进行了 30 分钟的 FaceTime 通话，还与同行评审员乔安娜·斯特恩 (Joanna Stern) 和尼莱·帕特尔 (Nilay Patel) 进行了通话。）但我认为它们在角色与角色之间的效果最好——也就是说，比如说，两个（或更多）人都使用 Vision Pro。对于大多数通话来说，显然情况并非如此。随着越来越多的人购买和使用 Vision 耳机，并且苹果竞相将该功能提高到非测试版质量，这将变得正常化。但现在，如果你使用它，就期待谈论它。</p><p>您的角色还用于在 EyeSight 功能中展示您的眼睛。在苹果的产品营销中，EyeSight 是 Vision Pro 的一个头条功能。它在他们的网站和广告上占据显着位置。但在实践中这是非常微妙的。这是我用 EyeSight 拍摄的最好的自拍照：</p><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2024/01/eyesight-in-action.jpeg" class="noborder"><img
    src="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2024/01/eyesight-in-action.jpeg"
    alt="作者佩戴 Vision Pro，并激活了 EyeSight。"
    width = 500
  /></a></p><p>郑重声明，当我拍这张照片时，我的眼睛是睁着的。</p><p>在您使用 Vision Pro 的大部分时间里，EyeSight 都不会显示 - 仅当 Vision Pro 检测到您面前的人时（包括当您照镜子时），它才会打开。大多数时候您使用 Vision Pro 时，前显示屏根本不显示任何内容。</p><p> EyeSight 不是“<em>天啊，我能看到你的眼睛！”</em> ”功能，但更多的是“<em>哦，是的，既然你问了，我想我可以看到你的眼睛</em>”功能。苹果似乎不遗余力（并且花费了大量资金）来创建 EyeSight 功能，但到目前为止，我发现它的实用性非常可疑，即使只是因为它是如此微妙。这就像戴有色护目镜是为了<em>遮挡</em>你，而不是透明护目镜是为了清楚地显示你的眼睛。</p><h2>个人娱乐</h2><p>我把最好的留到了最后。 Vision Pro 是一种非凡的电影观看方式，3D 沉浸式体验令人惊叹。 Vision Pro 中的 3D 沉浸式体验比人们排队几个小时才能看到的迪士尼世界景点更引人注目。</p><p>首先是使用未针对 Vision Pro 本机更新的应用程序的电影。我使用 iPad 应用程序来提供 Paramount+ 和 Peacock 等服务。在此类应用程序中观看视频是一种很棒的体验，但并不令人惊叹。您只需得到一个包含视频内容的窗口，您可以将其设置为任意大小，但对于这些仅仅是“兼容”的应用程序来说，“大”大约是您房间中最大的墙壁的大小。当您进入“全屏”模式时，Safari 中的视频也是如此。它从浏览器窗口中分离出来，变成一个独立的视频窗口。 （Netflix.com 在 VisionOS Safari 中还可以，但 YouTube.com 就很糟糕了——这是一个 UI 目标的雷区，对于眼动追踪的精度来说太小了。）</p><p> Disney+ 和 Apple TV 应用程序更上一层楼，它们是专为 Vision Pro 设计的。这两款应用程序都提供身临其境的 360° 观看环境。 <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-previews-new-entertainment-experiences-launching-with-apple-vision-pro/">Disney+ 有四个</a>：“Disney+ 剧院，灵感源自好莱坞历史悠久的 El Capitan 剧院；皮克斯<em>《怪兽电力公司》</em>的恐怖地板；漫威的复仇者大厦俯瞰曼哈顿市中心；以及卢克·天行者的陆地飞行器的驾驶舱，面向星球大战星系塔图因行星上的双星日落。”通过电视应用程序，苹果提供了一个无干扰的虚拟剧院。</p><p>在这两个应用程序中观看电影的神奇之处在于，虚拟电影屏幕看起来非常巨大，就好像您真的在电影院中一样，独自看着一个 100 英尺的屏幕。苹果在电视应用程序中的演示特别好，让您可以选择模拟剧院前面、中间或后面以及地板或阳台的视角。 （就像 Siskel 和 Ebert 一样，我想我更喜欢阳台。）“<em>天啊，这个屏幕看起来绝对巨大</em>”的效果在苹果的电视应用程序中特别好。不知何故，Vision Pro 内的这些邮票大小的显示屏能够让您的大脑相信您正坐在巨大的电影院屏幕前的房子里最好的座位上。 （尽管 Disney+ 的观看体验非常身临其境，但在使用 TV 应用后，我发现自己希望能够离 Disney+ 的大屏幕更近一些，或者把屏幕做得更大。） 其实我从来都不是 3D 电影的粉丝电影院，但在 Vision Pro 中，深度感觉自然，不会分散注意力，并且您不会因佩戴有效的太阳镜而遭受任何亮度损失。</p><p>然后是 3D 沉浸式体验。 Apple 已委托开发了<a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-previews-new-entertainment-experiences-launching-with-apple-vision-pro/">一些原创游戏</a>，这些游戏在发布时作为 Vision Pro 独家游戏免费提供。我确信还有更多的事情正在路上。目前还没有足够的游戏推荐它们作为购买 Vision Pro 的理由，但这少数游戏对未来的承诺是令人难以置信的。 （我也期待以 3D 沉浸式方式观看体育赛事，但目前这完全是未来的事情。但希望在不久的将来。）</p><p>但我<em>建议</em>购买 Vision Pro 仅用作个人影院。几年前，我花了 5,000 美元购买了 77 英寸 LG OLED 电视。 Vision Pro 提供了更加引人注目的体验（包括更加引人注目的空间环绕声）。当你看到我的电视机时，几乎肯定会同意这是一台很棒的大电视。但在 Disney+ 和电视应用程序中观看电影会让您惊叹不已！这些是我从未想象过的经历，我可以在自己的家里（或者，比如说，在乘坐飞机穿越这个国家时）获得这些体验。</p><p>唯一的问题是 Vision Pro 完全是个人化的。戴上耳机本质上是一种孤立——就像耳机一样，但更是如此，因为眼神交流对所有灵长类动物来说都是至关重要的。如果您不经常自己观看电影、节目或体育比赛，那么购买只有您可以看到的设备就没有意义。就在这个周末，我在 Vision Pro 上的 Paramount+ 应用程序中观看了酋长队与乌鸦队比赛上半场的大部分内容，窗口大小与我的整个客厅墙壁一样大。这真是令人着迷。缩放到这个尺寸后，图像质量有点颗粒感（我相信电视广播只有 1080p 分辨率），但它比在电视上观看要好，因为它太大了。但我想和我的妻子一起坐在沙发上观看剩下的比赛（以及随后的狮子队与 49 人队的比赛）。总的来说，我很高兴与她分享这段经历，但如果我的 77 英寸电视没有突然显得太小，那该死的。</p><p> VisionOS 中的空间计算是实实在在的。它现在是一个合法的生产力计算平台，而且只会变得更好。这听起来像是炒作，但我坚信这是一个里程碑式的突破，就像 1984 年的 Macintosh 和 2007 年的 iPhone 一样。</p><p>但是，如果您要使用 Vision Pro 尝试做一件事（仅做一件事），那就必须是在电视应用程序中以影院模式观看电影。尝试一下，无论您之前对 Vision Pro 的价格标签有多怀疑，您的手都会开始慢慢靠近您的钱包。</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2024-01-30"><p>这是一种与 Studio Display 和 Pro Display XDR 附带的<a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MM6F3AM/A/polishing-cloth">19 美元 Apple 抛光布</a>完全不同的抛光布，更精细、更柔软。这些显示器的抛光布非常像麂皮。新款 Vision Pro 抛光布轻盈细腻，就像丝绸衬衫的面料一样。 <a href="#fnr1-2024-01-30"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 1。">↩︎</a></p></li><li id="fn2-2024-01-30"><p>旅行箱还覆盖着白色织物，我怀疑它很容易弄脏和弄脏。它看起来不像是一种适合放在飞机座椅下地板上的材料，尽管事实上它是一种显然会在飞机座椅下地板上来回滑动的产品。我还没有带着它离开家，所以也许这种面料具有令人惊讶的防污能力，但我的直觉是，这是一款苹果产品，专为一个理想的、完全干净的、整洁的世界而设计，而这个世界在外界是不存在的。苹果营销摄影。 <a href="#fnr2-2024-01-30"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 2。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn3-2024-01-30"><p> Vision Pro 的蔡司镜头插件在卡片上附有类似 QR 的代码。当您设置 Vision Pro 时，如果您使用镜头插件，则可以通过查看代码来扫描该代码。这种配对让 Vision Pro 准确了解您的镜片处方，并相应地调整其眼球追踪。 Apple 发送给我的审查单元包中包含正确的镜头插件，但这些镜头的代码卡不正确。这个错误是我的审查单位特有的，苹果告诉我，这对客户来说不会是问题。苹果通过电子邮件通知我这个错误，并附上了要扫描的正确代码。但我在前两天的测试中使用了未正确校准的镜片插件。视觉上一切看起来都很好（因为镜片适合我的处方），但眼球追踪功能却关闭了。并非无法使用，但肯定不如我在前几个月的无数实践演示中所体验到的准确。而且，在苹果通知我这个错误并向我发送正确的镜头代码的前一天，在使用 Vision Pro 几个小时后，我出现了剧烈的头痛，最终还出现了一点恶心。</p><p>使用正确的镜片代码重新校准后，我连续使用的时间更长，没有头痛或不适，也绝对没有恶心。我将这个轶事放在这里只是为了证明针对您的特定视力校准 Vision Pro 似乎是必要的。 <a href="#fnr3-2024-01-30"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 3。">↩︎︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ 视觉专业版</title></entry><entry><link href="https://workos.com/?utm_source=daringfireball&amp;utm_medium=display&amp;utm_campaign=q12024" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vah" rel="shorturl"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2024/01/workos_5" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/feeds/sponsors//11.40553</id><author><name>大胆火球商务部</name></author><published>2024-01-30T03:51:37Z</published><updated> 2024-01-30T03:51:37Z </updated><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>WorkOS 是一个现代身份和用户管理平台，使 B2B SaaS 公司能够加速企业采用。 WorkOS 可释放多达 100 万个 MAU，为 B2B Auth 提供模块化方法，并具有 SSO、SCIM 和用户管理等企业级功能。</p><p>这些 API 灵活且易于使用，旨在为您的第一个用户一直到最大的企业客户提供轻松的体验。</p><p>如今，数百个高增长的扩展项目已经由 WorkOS 提供支持，其中包括您可能知道的 Vercel、Webflow 和 Loom。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“WorkOS”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2024/01/workos_5">★</a></div> ]]>;</content><title> [赞助] WorkOS</title></entry><entry><title>关于苹果核心技术费的另外两个观察</title><link href="https://developer.apple.com/support/core-technology-fee/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vag" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/29/two-additional-observations-regarding-apples-core-technology-fee" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40552</id><published> 2024-01-29T23:14:23Z</published><updated> 2024-01-29T23:14:23Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>来自苹果公司上周宣布的新核心技术费支持页面：</p><blockquote><p>根据 Apple 开发者计划的现有规则，获准<a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/membership-fee-waiver/">免除费用的</a>非营利组织、经认可的教育机构和政府实体可免交核心技术费。替代应用程序市场的开发人员将为其应用程序市场的每次首次年度安装（包括 100 万之前的安装）支付核心技术费。</p></blockquote><p>我认为核心技术费的一个问题是，它似乎与非注册非营利组织、教育机构或政府的开发人员完全免费的应用程序的概念不兼容。我们过去称之为免费软件。比如<a href="https://netnewswire.com/">NetNewsWire</a>怎么样？这是一个完全免费的开源应用程序，但它不是来自非营利组织、学校或政府。我觉得免费软件的开发者应该能够申请豁免。也许甚至只适用于开源免费软件？</p><p>上面引用的第二句话是我没有注意到的，直到<a href="https://www.manton.org/2024/01/28/reviewing-news-coverage.html">我的朋友 Manton Reece 在周末指出了它</a>。 Marketplace 商店应用程序不会获得 100 万次免费安装 - 它们在首次下载后开始支付 CTF。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“关于苹果核心技术费的两个额外观察”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/29/two-additional-observations-regarding-apples-core-technology-fee">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>第一天</title><link href="https://dayoneapp.com/download/daring-fireball/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vaf" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/28/day-one" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40551</id><published> 2024-01-28T21:23:44Z</published><updated> 2024-01-28T21:23:44Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>我感谢第一天上周对 DF 的赞助。大家都知道 Day One 是适用于 Mac、iPhone 和 iPad 的最佳日记应用程序。一个美妙的界面，以及安全、私密、值得信赖的同步。</p><p>上周，第一天推出了新的共享日记功能，为反思和联系提供了协作空间。从今天开始，享受 DF 读者专享的特别优惠。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接至“第一天”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/28/day-one">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Netflix 游戏继续受到关注，部分原因是《侠盗猎车手》游戏</title><link href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/01/10/netflix-games-gain-traction-with-installs-up-180-year-over-year-in-2023-thanks-to-gta-and-others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vae" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/27/netflix-games-gta" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40550</id><published> 2024-01-27T21:57:43Z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T21:57:44Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Sarah Perez 几周前为 TechCrunch 报道：</p><blockquote><p>就在两年多前，Netflix 宣布将进军新业务：游戏。在以免费游戏和广告支持的商业模式为主的移动游戏市场中，Netflix 的计划是免费提供无广告或应用内购买的游戏。这一策略现在可能开始获得回报。根据市场情报公司 Sensor Tower 的估计，2023 年 Netflix 游戏下载量同比增长超过 180%。 2023 年，这些游戏在 App Store 和 Google Play 上的全球下载量总计为 8120 万次，其中第四季度约占下载量的 53%。</p></blockquote><p>苹果更新的<a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=f1v8pyay">有关游戏流媒体（和“迷你游戏”——但 GTA 游戏肯定不是迷你游戏）的新政策</a>可能会在这方面帮助 Netflix。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“Netflix 游戏继续获得关注，部分原因是‘侠盗猎车手’游戏”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/27/netflix-games-gta">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/apples_plans_for_the_dma" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vac" rel="shorturl"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net,2024://1.40548</id><published> 2024-01-27T04:59:16Z</published><updated> 2024-01-30T05:44:45Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text">具有讽刺意味的是，苹果公司不知道这些大规模提案是否会被视为符合 DMA 规定，因为他们与欧盟委员会的交易听起来就像 App Store 开发者与苹果公司的交易一样。首先完成构建它的所有工作，然后才知道它是否通过了基本难以理解的规则。 </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Apple 昨天宣布了一系列广泛、广泛且复杂的新政策，旨在遵守 3 月 7 日生效的欧盟《数字市场法案》。这是 Sebastiaan de With 在 Twitter/X 上发布的，就在这一切宣布的<em>前一天</em>。</p><p>在对“Spotify 也想推出替代应用商店”这句话的屏幕<a href="https://twitter.com/sdw/status/1750288120904655154">截图</a>打趣“天啊，请不要”之后， <a href="https://twitter.com/sdw/status/1750291816602300812">de With 进行了这样的对话</a>：</p><p>德与：</p><blockquote><p>欧盟再次完全没有解决任何问题，并使科技领域的一切变得更糟。我得说，如果有的话，它们是高度一致的。</p></blockquote><p> “安东”：</p><blockquote><p>过于强大的寻租守门人似乎是一个问题。</p></blockquote><p>德与：</p><blockquote><p>我很高兴我无法判断你在这种情况下是在谈论欧盟还是苹果。</p></blockquote><p>我第二喜欢的观点来自同一条线索，<a href="https://twitter.com/maxrovensky/status/1750600510346817950">来自马克斯·罗文斯基（Max Rovensky）</a> ：</p><blockquote><p> DMA 不利于消费者。</p><p>这是反大企业的。</p><p>这些有时往往是一致的，这使得它很容易被公众接受，但实际上阅读 DMA，它非常有趣。</p></blockquote><p>我想进一步将 DMA 描述为反<em>美国</em>大企业，因为据我所知，DMA 中的任何内容都不会对任何欧洲科技公司产生不利影响，甚至不会惹恼任何欧洲科技公司。事实上，它的某些方面似乎是专门<em>为</em>Spotify 编写的。</p><p>但罗文斯基的框架抓住了这种二分法。反大企业监管和有利于消费者的结果往往确实齐头并进，但DMA暴露了其中的裂痕。我认为 DMA 不会发生太大变化（如果有的话），以便为欧盟的 iOS 用户（或欧盟的非 iOS 用户）提供更好的服务。就像<a href="https://gdpr.eu/cookies/">GDPR 的网站 cookie 规定</a>一样，我想如果它有什么实际效果的话，那就是让用户的事情变得<em>更糟</em>。这些选择对于开发人员来说是否更好似乎还不太清楚。</p><p>我<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2021/06/app_store_the_schiller_cut">经常说</a>，苹果的优先事项是一致的：苹果自己的需求第一，用户第二，开发者第三。欧盟委员会的优先事项将开发商放在第一位，用户放在第二位，而“看门人”则远远地排在第三位。 DMA 规定的不是双赢的框架，而是双赢-双输的框架。</p><p>苹果骄傲、固执、傲慢、控制欲强，并坚信自己将客户的最大利益放在心上。</p><p>欧盟委员会骄傲、固执、傲慢、控制欲强，并坚信自己将公民的最大利益放在心上。</p><p>自从大约两年前开始，关于 DMA 的这场冲突似乎不可避免，我就一直在努力想象结果会如何。每次我都会先问：哪一方更聪明？我的钱都花在苹果上了。我认为昨天的公告说明了原因。</p><h2> Apple 提议的变更</h2><p>很难总结苹果昨天宣布的所有内容，但我会尝试。从 Apple Newsroom 的主要新闻稿开始：“ <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-announces-changes-to-ios-safari-and-the-app-store-in-the-european-union/">Apple 宣布对欧盟 iOS、Safari 和 App Store 进行更改</a>”：</p><blockquote><p> “我们今天宣布的变化符合欧盟《数字市场法案》的要求，同时有助于保护欧盟用户免受该法规带来的不可避免的更多隐私和安全威胁。我们的首要任务仍然是为欧盟和世界各地的用户创造最好、最安全的体验。”Apple Fellow Phil Schiller 说道。 “开发人员现在可以了解可用于替代应用程序分发和替代支付处理的新工具和条款、替代浏览器引擎和非接触式支付的新功能等等。重要的是，如果开发商愿意，可以选择保留目前相同的业务条款。”</p></blockquote><p>席勒是新闻稿中唯一引用的苹果高管，在我听来，整个声明中都是他的手笔。在 DMA 纳入法律之前，苹果公司就非常明确地<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2021/11/federighi_sideloading_keynote_at_web_summit">表示，他们认为 iOS 上的强制侧载对用户来说是一个坏主意</a>，而且他们昨天的声明并没有丝毫退缩，仍然宣称这是一个坏主意。</p><p>苹果还一贯辩称，他们寻求通过 iOS 平台的第三方开发获利，并且被迫改变当前的系统 - (a) 所有应用程序都必须来自 App Store； (b) 开发者从不为免费应用程序的分发支付任何费用； (c) 付费应用程序和应用程序内消费的数字内容的应用程序内购买必须通过苹果公司的应用程序内支付系统，该系统可自动收取苹果公司 30/15% 的佣金——这将使他们通过平台获利的方式变得非常复杂。现在，苹果公司公布了一套针对欧盟 iPhone 应用程序的极其复杂的规则和政策。</p><p> MG Siegler 有一篇精彩且有趣的帖子<a href="https://spyglass.org/apple-to-eu-drop-dead/">，逐行剖析了苹果的新闻稿</a>。西格勒总结道：</p><blockquote><p>老实说，我不确定我是否记得有一篇新闻稿充满了如此的蔑视。苹果公司甚至可能在上述许多点上都有道理，但它的框架似乎只是确保苹果公司将继续与欧盟就所有这一切发生争执，而且现在无疑还会更多。通常情况下，如果你打算做出一些改变并认为事情已经结束，那么你不会在这样做的同时大力举起中指。</p><p>其中一些变化确实看起来不错且有用，但大多数<a href="https://www.threads.net/@mgsiegler/post/C2iRgI8LH-H?ref=spyglass.org">看起来只是</a>令人费解的变化，以确保现状实际上不会发生太大变化（如果有的话）。请记住，“重要的是，如果开发人员愿意，他们可以选择保留目前相同的业务条款。”你认为苹果更喜欢什么？</p></blockquote><p>苹果试图解决的难题是创建一个新政策框架 - 以及超过 600 个新的开发者 API 来实现这些政策 - 以遵守 DMA，同时保持开发者阻力和风险最小的路径不变：苹果自己的 App Store就这样。</p><p>因此，开发者的第一个选择就是什么也不做——根据现有条款，完全留在苹果的应用商店中。 （苹果昨天发布了一些在全球范围内生效的公告，而不仅仅是在欧盟，<a href="https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=f1v8pyay">例如有关流媒体游戏服务、迷你游戏和迷你应用程序规则的更改</a>。为了简洁起见 - 好吧，<em>尝试</em>简洁 - 我重点关注与 DMA 合规性相关的欧盟特定变化。）</p><p>令人困惑的一点是，Apple 提议的 DMA 合规性的某些方面适用于所有平台（iPhone、iPad、Mac、TV、Watch 以及即将推出的 Vision）的 App Store，但其他方面则特定于 iOS 平台 - 这是要说的，只有iPhone。 <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/alternative-browser-engines/" title="苹果：“在欧盟使用替代浏览器引擎”">使用非 WebKit 渲染引擎的</a>第三方<a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/alternative-app-marketplace-in-the-eu/" title="苹果：“开始作为欧盟的替代应用程序市场”">应用程序市场</a><sup id="fnr1-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn1-2024-01-26">1</a></sup>和网络浏览器仅在 iOS 上可用，这意味着它们仅适用于 iPhone， <sup id="fnr2-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn2-2024-01-26">2</a></sup>并且不适用于 iPadOS。 Apple <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-announces-changes-to-ios-safari-and-the-app-store-in-the-european-union/">昨天的主要新闻稿</a>分别列出了 iOS 更改和 App Store 更改，但我第一次阅读时并没有明确表示 iOS 更改不适用于 iPadOS。 <sup id="fnr3-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn3-2024-01-26">3</a></sup></p><p>以下是我根据苹果的提议，对欧盟开发者可用的选项的总结：</p><ol><li>仅根据当前（DMA 之前）规则保留在 App Store 中。采取此选项的开发人员：<ul><li>不允许使用欧盟提供的任何新<em>业务条款</em>，但允许欧盟使用新的<em>iOS</em>平台选项，例如备用浏览器引擎。 （因为他们需要被允许。）</li><li>由于此选项下没有任何与业务相关的变化，因此现有的全球规则适用于付费应用程序、订阅和应用内购买 (IAP)，包括向 Apple 收取 30/15% 的佣金以及应用程序只能使用 Apple 的 App Store 付款的要求系统。</li><li><em>不</em>收取核心技术费（CTF），因为业务条款没有改变。 （参见下文：CTF。）</li></ul></li><li>选择加入新的欧盟规则（此选择下可用的所有子选项都需要为在欧盟下载量超过 100 万次的每个应用程序支付核心技术费）：<ul><li>选择加入新的欧盟规则后，开发者可以选择留在 App Store，并且：<ul><li>使用Apple的App Store支付系统：20/13％的佣金+ CTF自动支付给Apple。</li><li>使用自定义的应用内支付系统（例如 Stripe）：17/10% 佣金 + CTF 支付给 Apple。</li><li>使用从内部应用程序到网络的外部链接进行付款和订阅：17/10% + 向 Apple 支付的 CTF。</li><li><em>后两个选项 - 使用自定义支付处理和/或外部网络链接 - 与<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/coming_to_grips_with_apples_seemingly_unshakable_sense_of_app_store_entitlement">上周宣布的外部支付链接权利政策</a>类似，涉及开发人员跟踪这些付款、每月向 Apple 报告销售情况并提交的义务接受 Apple 审核以确保合规性。</em></li></ul></li><li>在一个或多个第三方市场中分发应用程序：<ul><li>无法选择使用 Apple 的 App Store 付款处理，因为这些应用程序并非来自 App Store。</li><li>唯一欠苹果的钱是核心技术费——应用内交易或网络链接不收取佣金。</li></ul></li></ul></li></ol><p>在选项（2）（选择加入欧盟新规则的包罗万象）下，子选项并不相互排斥。选择加入新欧盟规则的开发者可以在应用程序商店中拥有（或保留）应用程序<em>，并</em>通过第三方应用程序市场分发这些相同的应用程序或不同的应用程序。或者，他们可以只留在 App Store 中（根据新的业务条款，佣金较低，但 CTF 也较低），或者可以通过应用市场专门进行分发。</p><p>只有选项 (1) 和 (2) 是互斥的。然而，一旦开发商选择接受新的欧盟规则，该决定就不可撤销。引用<a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/dma-and-apps-in-the-eu/#faq">苹果公司“欧盟分发的应用程序更新”文件</a>的问答部分：</p><blockquote><p>任何时候采用新业务条款的开发者都将无法为其欧盟应用切换回苹果现有的业务条款。 Apple 将继续提前通知开发者我们条款的变更，以便他们能够就业务的发展做出明智的选择。</p></blockquote><p> （整个常见问题解答部分是一个很好的总结，值得阅读。）</p><h2>核心技术费</h2><p><a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/dma-and-apps-in-the-eu/#faq">Apple 对 CTF 的描述</a>：</p><blockquote><p>核心技术费 (CTF) 反映了 Apple 对工具、技术和服务的投资，这些工具、技术和服务使开发人员能够构建并与 Apple 用户共享他们的应用程序。其中包括超过 250,000 个 API、TestFlight、Xcode 等等。这些工具为开发者创造了很多价值，无论他们是否在 App Store 上分享他们的应用程序。</p><p> CTF 仅适用于采用新条款进行替代分发和支付处理的开发人员，并且其应用程序达到了超乎寻常的规模。凭借 Apple 开发者计划的会员资格，符合新业务条款的合格开发者每年可为其在欧盟的每个应用程序获得 100 万次免费安装。请参阅<a href="https://developer.apple.com/contact/request/download/alternate_eu_terms_addendum.pdf">条款</a>了解更多详情。根据欧盟应用程序的新商业条款，Apple 估计只有不到 1% 的开发者会支付核心技术费。</p></blockquote><p>苹果在以下一点上的描述很明确，但值得重申：CTF 仅适用于超过 100 万次的下载，就像边际税率一样。因此，如果开发者的应用程序的欧盟用户下载量从 1,000,000 次增加到 1,000,001 次，则只需向 Apple 支付 0.50 欧元的核心技术费用。然而，CTF 每年都会重复举办，更新也算作下载。不过，在多台设备上安装同一个应用程序并不算作多次安装。 <sup id="fnr4-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn4-2024-01-26">4</a></sup> CTF 按用户、每个应用程序、每年计算。 （Apple 有一个<a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/fee-calculator-for-apps-in-the-eu/">CTF 计算器，</a>开发人员可以用它来计算价格、分发方法和下载次数的场景。）</p><p>简而言之，DMA 要求苹果将 App Store 的货币化与 iOS 平台的货币化分离开来。 Apple 现有的、纯粹基于佣金的 iOS 应用货币化方式隐含地将 App Store 和 iOS 提供的价值捆绑在一起。</p><p>因此，在选项（1）下——开发者选择现有的 App Store 分发规则，包括 App Store 独占权——没有任何变化，苹果从 App Store 交易中收取 30/15% 的佣金。</p><p>但在选项（2）下——开发者选择接受新的欧盟规则——苹果的 App Store 货币化与 iOS 平台本身的货币化是分离的。这就是为什么根据新的欧盟规则，对于通过 App Store 分发的使用 App Store 支付系统的应用程序，佣金费用降低至 20/13%；对于通过 App Store 分发的使用自定义支付处理的应用程序，佣金费用降低至 17/10%。实际上，苹果公司表示，他们在 App Store 分发中的公平份额为 17/10%，而苹果自己的 App Store 支付处理值得额外增加 3%。 （对于支付处理成本而言，3% 几乎毫无疑问是一个公平的估计。）</p><p>而且，这就是为什么在 App Store 之外分发的应用程序<em>只会</em>向 Apple 支付 CTF，而不收取销售佣金。欧盟新规定下的佣金仅适用于应用商店，因此来自市场的应用程序无需支付佣金。核心技术费是苹果提出的将 iOS 本身提供的价值货币化的方式。</p><p>所有选择加入欧盟新规则的开发者都必须遵守 CTF。根据现有政策留在 App Store 的开发者均不受 CTF 的约束。</p><h2>市场应用程序是应用程序商店之外的唯一发行版</h2><p>第三方市场应用程序是开发者在 App Store 之外的欧盟地区分发应用程序的唯一途径。苹果的提案没有提供从开发者网站直接下载应用程序的选项。苹果对谁可以成为应用程序市场有规定。你必须是一家公司，而不是个人。您必须“向 Apple 提供来自 A 级（或标准普尔、惠誉或穆迪的同等评级）金融机构的 1,000,000 欧元的备用信用证，以建立足够的财务手段，以保证对您的开发者和用户的支持。” <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/alternative-app-marketplace-in-the-eu/" title="苹果：“开始作为欧盟的替代应用程序市场”">和更多</a>。简而言之，资格并不简单，但也不过分复杂。</p><p>但市场应用程序必须是真正的“商店”。市场可以决定专门分发某个类别（例如游戏）的应用程序，但必须对同一类别的任何开发者提交的内容开放。 XYZ 公司无法创建仅分发 XYZ 自己的应用程序的市场。这不是一个合适的类别。苹果也不认为这是一个合适的类别，比如“由哈佛辍学生创办的公司的应用程序，其起源在亚伦·索金的有趣电影中描述过。”</p><p>对于希望通过多个商店（包括 Apple 的 App Store）进行分发的开发人员来说，一个关键限制是：来自一个商店的安装不能覆盖来自另一商店的同一应用程序的现有安装。用户必须先手动从旧商店删除安装，然后从其他商店重新安装该应用程序。苹果声称——也许合理——这一限制是因为他们不知道从不同商店进行的全新安装是否会保留通过之前商店安装的应用程序的数据。</p><p>但这也意味着，如果 Meta 开始通过第三方市场（可能是他们自己的 Meta Store）分发应用程序，并希望鼓励 iOS 用户从 App Store 安装切换到 Meta Store 安装，那么每个用户这样做必须先删除现有的 Meta 应用程序安装，然后再安装新应用程序。</p><p>第三方市场应用程序（实际的应用程序商店应用程序）将不允许出现在 Apple 的应用程序商店中。要安装市场应用程序（第三方应用程序市场<a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/appdistribution/creating-an-alternative-app-marketplace/">本身就是应用程序</a>），用户必须访问市场应用程序的网站。 Safari（以及其他采用新 API 的网络浏览器）将在用户确认他们确实想要安装后提供安装市场应用程序的功能。该<a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/appdistribution/creating-an-alternative-app-marketplace/">确认恐慌表</a>和后续安装由系统提供。</p><p> DMA 之所以成为一项可怕的法律（据笔者估计），部分原因在于它的模糊性和难以理解的语言。目前完全不清楚苹果仅允许通过市场应用程序在应用程序商店之外分发应用程序的提议是否合规。 DMA 的许多支持者一直坚信 DMA 要求 iOS 等看门平台允许直接从网络下载应用程序（例如在 PC 和 Mac 上）。这是 DMA 第 6 条第 4 节，添加了粗体全大写强调：</p><blockquote><p> 4. 网守应允许<b>并</b>在技术上启用使用其操作系统或与其互操作的第三方软件应用程序<b>或</b>软件应用程序商店的安装和有效使用，并允许通过除该网守的相关核心平台服务。在适用的情况下，网守不得阻止下载的第三方软件应用程序<b>或</b>软件应用程序商店提示最终用户决定是否要将下载的软件应用程序<b>或</b>软件应用程序商店设置为其默认值。网守在技术上应使决定将下载的软件应用程序<b>或</b>软件应用程序商店设置为默认值的最终用户能够轻松地执行该更改。</p></blockquote><p>通过苹果的解释，如果DMA要求iOS支持第三方市场<em>和</em>直接安装单个应用程序和游戏，则所有这些<em>或</em><em>和/或</em>和<em>和</em>和有关此解释的不确定性，请参见下文。</p><h2>苹果仍将查看所有应用程序，但规则却大不相同</h2><p>iOS的所有应用都需要一个Apple开发人员计划帐户。 <sup id="fnr5-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn5-2024-01-26">5</a></sup>所有应用程序和每个更新仍然必须提交给Apple进行公证。经过审查后，苹果将将应用程序转发到分发应用程序的每个市场。通过市场应用程序分发的应用程序的审核策略与应用商店完全不同。再次<a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/dma-and-apps-in-the-eu/#faq">从苹果的常见问题解答</a>：</p><blockquote><p>开发人员可以提交单个二进制文件，并能够在App Store Connect中选择替代分发选项。 iOS应用的公证将检查：</p><ul><li>准确性 - 应用程序必须准确代表用户的开发人员，功能和成本。</li><li>功能 - 二进制文件必须可以进行审查，没有严重的错误或崩溃，并且与当前版本的iOS兼容。他们无法以对用户体验产生负面影响的方式操纵软件或硬件。</li><li>安全 - 应用程序无法促进用户或公众的身体伤害。</li><li>安全性 - 应用程序无法启用恶意软件或可疑或不必要的软件的分发。他们无法下载可执行的代码，在容器外部读取，也不能指导用户降低其系统或设备上的安全性。此外，应用程序必须提供透明度并允许用户同意使任何一方访问系统或设备，或重新配置系统或其他软件。</li><li>隐私 - 如果没有用户的知识或与软件的既定目的相反，应用程序就无法收集或传输私人，敏感的数据。</li></ul></blockquote><p>在过去两天中，我多次介绍了Apple代表，他强调，适用于App Store中分布的应用程序的<em>内容</em>限制将不适用于欧盟市场上的分布式限制。以成人内容和色情制品为例：应用商店中永远不会允许色情应用程序，但不会被Apple拒绝以在市场上分发。这将取决于每个市场。</p><p>苹果的审查过程将继续涉及自动检查和人类审查。<em>不允许</em>使用私人API使用。苹果认为，根据第6条第4条的另一项规定，该限制是DMA下的犹太限制，该规定：</p><blockquote><p>在严格必要和相称的范围内，不得阻止守门人采取措施，以确保第三方软件应用程序或软件应用商店不会危害由Gatekeeper提供的硬件或操作系统的完整性（提供）这类措施是由看门人正当合理的。</p></blockquote><p>因此，由于使用私人API或<a href="https://blog.eidinger.info/system-programming-interfaces-spi-in-swift-explained">SPI</a>的使用，也将阻止任何第三方应用程序出现在App Store中，也将被阻止出现在第三方市场中。试图规避沙箱限制，背景处理限制等的应用程序将被Apple考虑“危害硬件或操作系统的完整性”。</p><p>一个奇怪的是，DMA对看门人的基于内容的限制的禁令是，不允许苹果拒绝盗版或侵犯版权的应用程序或游戏。如果Rando的无名开发人员在第三方市场上提交发行的游戏，其中包括Buzz Lightyear，Donald Duck，Mario和Donkey Kong进行杀人杀死的<em>大杀害大杀害的式</em>鲜血（除其他身体上的液体） ）横冲直撞，不允许苹果以侵犯版权的理由拒绝它。他们也可能不允许拒绝名为“蒂姆·库克是混蛋”或“苹果主题演讲”的应用程序。 DMA清楚地表明，看门人只能出于技术原因而不是内容原因拒绝或阻止应用程序，无论内容是否非常非法。在DMA下，由政府实体和各个市场取决于内容。</p><h2> CTF提高了期望，似乎是苹果的防御能力，以防止对iOS的控制权。</h2><p>苹果对DMA的战略关注之一是保护它从第三方iOS应用程序中获得的大量（且仍在增长）的收入。 （duh。）另一个正在保护其客户的隐私，安全性和用户体验。</p><p>但是苹果的关注肯定是<em>控制的</em>。控制涵盖了苹果的所有问题，从自己的收入到用户的经验。对DMA的任何形式遵守一定都意味着苹果失去了对iOS平台的某种控制权。 （任何从Safari或任何其他基于WebKit的浏览器切换到使用Google Chrome的眨眼或Mozilla的Firefox/Gecko渲染引擎的用户，<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2015/07/31/safari-chrome-battery-life">几乎</a><a href="https://daringfireball.net/2017/05/safari_vs_chrome_on_the_mac#fn2-2017-05-24">可以肯定</a>会看到对电池寿命的不利打击。但是苹果必须允许第三方允许第三方欧盟iPhone上的Web渲染引擎，包括通过<sup id="fnr6-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn6-2024-01-26">AppStore。6</a></sup> ）</p><p>我认为，CTF是苹果公司从最大的竞争对手中竞争市场商店的风险的方式：Meta，Google，Microsoft和Amazon（可能是按此顺序）。 EC痴迷于付款处理和IAP的苹果委员会。苹果的立场是从2008年到今天的App Store成立，就是他们仅通过购买付费应用的购买委员会来使iOS平台获利，因为这是他们通过该平台获利的唯一途径，这是使用的原因之一他们自己的App Store支付系统是强制性的。 （苹果还认为，有许多默欲的观点，用户对使用App Store付款有利益。我最喜欢的示例是他们的订阅政策，包括强制性续订通知和轻松取消。）您可以同意或不同意这是一个是一个良好的政策，包括苹果应该试图以与Macos <sup id="fnr7-2024-01-26"><a href="#fn7-2024-01-26">7</a></sup>货币化的方式不同的基本假设，即以任何方式“货币化” iOS平台 - 但这就是苹果的立场。</p><p> DMA是对苹果整个货币化策略的直接攻击。它要求替代付款处理可用于欧盟中的应用程序，即使是在苹果自己的应用商店中，也可以使用允许链接到网络的链接进行付款，并允许允许从App Store外部分发应用程序。<em>攻击</em>是一个强烈的词，但是DMA的大部分显然是针对一个平台：iPhone/iOS。</p><p>我认为，EC对付款处理和委员会的痴迷使他们蒙蔽了这些事实，即苹果公司始终还有其他选择的货币化选择。这是基于安装而不是购买的核心技术费用，就是其中之一。</p><p> CTF破坏了苹果最大的竞争对手和竞争对手使用的免费/免费增值模型。 Meta的应用程序都是免费的：WhatsApp，Instagram，Facebook和现在的线程。梅塔（Meta）有效地为这些应用程序支付了苹果。 YouTube应用程序提供IAP订阅，但Google大多数受欢迎的iOS应用程序都是完全免费的，因此Google不付钱。 Spotify拥有5亿个全球用户，<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/04/25/spotify-now-has-more-than-500m-users/">在付费和免费（支持）之间分配40-60</a> 。这意味着Spotify可能在iOS上拥有大约1亿免费用户，而Spotify不付钱。</p><p>如果这些公司中有数亿美元的欧盟用户选择了新的欧盟规则（因此选择退出现有的App Store规则），他们将挂在挂钩上支付苹果数亿美元（好吧，欧元 - 但每年大约是1：1）。</p><p>我第一次做这件事的数学后，我的想法是CTF是一种毒药。当然，这些公司都没有支付苹果以通过应用程序商店分发其应用程序的公司会选择进入一个新系统，该系统将要求他们每年每年支付数亿美元。正确的？但是后来我意识到这些公司的经营量如此巨大，以至于“数亿美元”对他们来说并不荒谬。</p><p>简单地考虑Google每年支付苹果20亿美元的$ 20击金，以使Google搜索成为Safari的默认搜索引擎。他们很可能会考虑每年仅支付苹果10亿美元，以便在欧盟运营自己的iOS市场。同样，对于Meta和Microsoft来说，像Google一样，盈利。但是，对于Spotify来说，可能不是<a href="https://www.engadget.com/spotify-grew-far-more-than-expected-but-is-still-losing-money-121553523.html">从未始终如一的盈利</a>。毫不奇怪，尽管Meta，Microsoft和Google避免了评论，但<a href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2024-01-26/apples-proposed-changes-reject-the-goals-of-the-dma/">Spotify感到震惊</a>- 令人震惊 - 对Apple提议的DMA遵守，将其描述为“勒索”和“完整而总的闹剧”。 （MG Siegler认为<em>Apple的</em>新闻稿滴落着不屑一顾。）</p><p> DMA说，Apple不能使App Store成为欧盟中iOS应用的独家发行源，并且也无法从App Store中使用其自己的Apps独家付款系统。但是我看不到DMA中的任何东西，说苹果无法向开发人员收取费用。</p><p>许多App Store评论家的假设就是这样：<em>我们不喜欢Apple当前的iOS App Store策略。 DMA要求苹果在欧盟改变这些政策。因此，苹果一定会将其在欧盟的政策更改为我们喜欢的东西，而苹果会讨厌。</em> （莫兹拉（Mozilla）列举了另一个关于苹果限制和政策的直言不讳的批评者，<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/26/24052067/mozilla-apple-ios-browser-rules-firefox">他进一步假设苹果将改变其在浏览器引擎上的全球政策</a>，以符合DMA中欧盟的要求。他们正在吸烟。）</p><p> DMA宣布苹果的现有术语不再可接受，这并不意味着苹果的唯一符合性响应将是割让对iOS的大多数控制。苹果本周提出的全面提出的表明，希望将iOS（以及所有平台上的App Store）保持在DMA的字母中尽可能地与Apple的愿望保持一致。任何认为苹果会提出不同的人<em>都</em>没有引起注意。</p><h2>这些只是建议</h2><p>我在整个本文中都强调了<em>建议</em>。这是关键，因为没有人，包括苹果在内，都知道欧盟委员会是否会找到任何或全部符合DMA。苹果在数年的DMA中与EC代表会见了数十次，但是EC的工作方式是（1）他们通过了法律； （2）公司从事所有工作以尝试遵守这些法律；直到（3）才能决定是否遵守。像苹果这样的公司不会超越EC的想法并获得大拇指或大拇指。他们必须构建它们，然后找出答案。</p><p>这使我回到了我的莱德（Lede），而塞巴斯蒂亚·德（Sebastiaan de）则与他的讽刺有关，他无法确定“过于强大的，寻求租金的看门人”是关于苹果还是欧盟的。</p><p>苹果公司不知道这些庞大，复杂的提议是否会被视为符合DMA的讽刺意味，他们与欧洲委员会的交易听起来完全像App Store开发商与Apple的交往一样。做所有的工作以首先建造它，<em>然后</em>才能确定它是否通过不露面的官僚解释的难以理解的规则来通过。</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2024-01-26"><p> “ App Marketplace”是Apple的第三方App Store术语。我正在采用它，因为（a）它是公平，普通，非宣传语言； （b）它巧妙地围绕苹果公司的第一方标题“ App Store”和第三方通用“ App Store”之间的混乱。例如，大概是因为Apple拥有“ App Store”的商标，Amazon的Android和Windows 11应用商店（<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2011/03/22/8-steps">自2011年以来就已经存在</a>，很少出现大张旗鼓，而且我认为很少有用户）被命名为<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/mas/get-appstore/android">Amazon AppStore</a> 。 <a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32022R1925#d1e2591-1-1">《欧盟数字市场法》的文本</a>将这些商店形式描述为“软件应用程序存储”。 <a href="#fnr1-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 1。">↩︎</a></p></li><li id="fn2-2024-01-26"><p>在2022年，iOS 16下降了对2019年发行的<a href="https://everymac.com/systems/apple/ipod/specs/ipod-touch-7th-gen-a2178-2019-specs.html">第7（也是最后）一代iPod Touch的</a>支持。因此，iOS 17中的这些变化也不会引起iPod Touch Holdouts。 <a href="#fnr2-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 2。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn3-2024-01-26"><p>让我想知道苹果<a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2019/06/03/ios-for-ipad-renamed-ipados/">在2019年6月</a>将iPad的iOS重命名为“ iPados”时是否想到了这一点。但是，我怀疑他们创建了iPados名称，只是为了反映两个平台之间功能的差异，例如并排的多任务处理和现在的舞台经理。 （这也是，许多新功能最终都在iPad提前一年都进入iPhone的事实，例如主屏幕窗口小部件和锁屏定制。 DMA。 <a href="#fnr3-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 3。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn4-2024-01-26"><p>从理论上讲，这给选择新欧盟规则的开发人员提供了一种不正当的激励措施：发布软件更新的频率少于每12个月。但是我认为那是不切实际的。哪个应用程序会变得如此受欢迎，以至于在欧盟中获得超过100万个下载量，但没有为错误修复，新功能和采用新的iOS平台功能发布常规软件更新吗？我玩的一些较旧的游戏<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/texas-holdem/id284602850">多年来没有发布更新</a>，但是这些游戏不是拥有数百万活跃用户的游戏。我认为这个漏洞纯粹是假设的，不值得担心。</p><p>还有一个攻击向量：有大量追随者的人可能会指导他们的粉丝下载竞争对手或敌人的免费应用程序，每次安装0.50欧元。<a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/dma-and-apps-in-the-eu/#dev-qa">苹果的常见问题解答</a>包含有关防止“安装轰炸”的整个部分。 <a href="#fnr4-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回正文中的脚注 4。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn5-2024-01-26"><p>这似乎排除了Epic，无法提供Epic Games商店，因为开发人员帐户在Fortnite上使用的Epic epic在违反了开发人员协议的条款与他们的应用程序内处理的特技违反了开发人员协议的条款。但是Epic的开发人员工具子公司<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2021/09/epic_apple_developer_accounts">仍然拥有虚幻引擎的开发人员帐户</a>，因此也许他们可以提供虚幻游戏商店？不清楚 - 与整个建议有关。 <a href="#fnr5-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 5。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn6-2024-01-26"><p>使用第三方渲染引擎的一项功能浏览器将无法“保存到主屏幕”。<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2007/06/wwdc_2007_keynote">自从iPhone推出的那天</a>（与本地第三方应用程序和App Store提前一年）以来，这就是iOS的功能，该功能允许将Web应用程序保存到Safari的主屏幕上，从而像应用程序一样行动。 （苹果甚至今年<a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/104996">以“添加到码头”的名称</a>将此功能带到了MacOS 14 Sonoma。）“渐进式网络应用程序”（PWAS）的网络开发人员支持者一直在呼吁iOS上的第三方渲染引擎，以便他们可以构建使用iOS上使用WebKit功能的Web应用程序不支持。他们需要将PWA与嵌入式的第三方渲染引擎（<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2018/12/electron_and_the_decline_of_native_apps">电子风格）</a>捆绑在一起，并通过欧盟市场应用程序分发它们，就像使用Swift和Objective-C编写的Big-Boy Native应用程序一样，如果他们想使用功能， Webkit不支持。 （或仅在包含非Webkit引擎的浏览器应用程序中的选项卡中运行。）</p><p>使用第三方渲染引擎的iOS浏览器将无法将PWA保存为主屏幕上的独立应用程序，这一事实似乎并未写在<a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/browserenginekit">Apple的有关BrowserEngineKit的文档</a>中，但不需要。根本没有启用它的API，也没有DMA中需要它的任何条款。我与一个信息良好的小鸟核对，他确认这是不可能的。与Apple DMA合规提案的几乎所有方面一样，那些期望PC/Mac风格的所有内容都可以安装任何东西 - 无论何时启用Want Wart-want ther-All  - 如果Apple对DMA的解释是正确的，那么非常失望。 <a href="#fnr6-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 6。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn7-2024-01-26"><p>到2009年 -  iPhone推出两年后，iOS App Store一年后，Apple以129美元的价格出售了Mac OS X版本升级。意思是您每次从10.2升级到10.3，然后再次从10.3升级到10.4时，您必须支付$ 129。 Mac粉丝将在Apple商店外面等待，在发布当天购买这些升级。从2009年的Mac OS X 10.6 Snow Leopard到2013年的Mac OS X 10.9 Mavericks，他们以29美元的价格出售了版本的升级，然后出售了19美元。许多长期开发人员都很难接受苹果公司为所有第三方iOS应用程序收取强制性销售委员会（或者现在是欧盟的核心技术费用），这将更加困难地制作当今的时iPhone用户接受iOS版本更新的费用为每年129美元。从某种意义上说，从iPhone开始，苹果通过向用户收取许可费的费用转变为向开发人员收取特权费用。 <a href="#fnr7-2024-01-26"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="在文本中跳回脚注7。">↩︎︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★苹果在欧盟中制定的DMA计划</title></entry><entry><title>陪审团命令特朗普向E. Jean Carroll支付8330万美元的诽谤</title><link href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/01/26/nyregion/trump-carroll-defamation-trial" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vab" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/26/trump-carroll-83-million" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40547</id><published> 2024-01-26T22：18：06Z</published><updated> 2024-01-26T22：18：07Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>纽约时报：</p><blockquote><p>周五，卡洛尔女士的律师罗伯塔·A·卡普兰（Roberta A.特朗普曾遭受攻击。</p><p>卡普兰女士还要求陪审团判给特朗普继续袭击卡洛尔女士的实质性惩罚性赔偿。卡普兰女士没有指定金额，但她指出，特朗普先生在陪审团播放的视频沉积中的摘录中估计，他的品牌仅价值“也许是100亿美元”，他认为他的价值他的房地产为140亿美元。</p><p>卡普兰女士对陪审团说：“唐纳德·特朗普（Donald Trump）价值数十亿美元。”</p><p>卡普兰女士说：“法律说，您可以考虑唐纳德·特朗普的财富以及他的恶意和恶意的持续行为，并持续进行评估。让他付出高昂的薪水。”</p></blockquote><p>使用特朗普自己对他的财富对他的财富，它一定很美味。</p><div> <a  title="永久性链接“陪审团命令特朗普为E. Jean Carroll支付8330万美元的诽谤$”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/26/trump-carroll-83-million">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>脱口秀节目：“便当盒上的星号” </title><link href="https://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow/2024/01/25/ep-393" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vad" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/26/the-talk-show-393" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40549</id><published> 2024-01-26T16：00：00z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T06：08：14Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Marco Arment返回演出。主题包括Apple Masimo专利纠纷Apple Watch血氧传感器，App Store的新外部付款链接等等。 </p><p><audio
    src = "https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/daringfireball/thetalkshow-393-marco-arment.mp3"
    controls
    preload = "none"
/></p><p>由...赞助：</p><ul><li> <a href="https://squarespace.com/talkshow">Squarespace</a> ：采取下一步行动。使用Code <strong>Talkshow</strong>可享受10％的折扣。</li><li><a href="https://www.drinktrade.com/thetalkshow">交易咖啡</a>：让我们更好地咖啡。免费订购免费的新鲜咖啡。</li></ul><div> <a  title="永久链接到“脱口秀节目：“在便当盒上的星号””"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/26/the-talk-show-393">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> “极其伟大：Apple Mac 40 周年”小组讨论</title><link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vl__10euTRo" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/vaa" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/insanely-great" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40546</id><published> 2024-01-25T02：59：02Z</published><updated> 2024-01-25T03：01：23Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>计算机历史博物馆：</p><blockquote><p>在Apple Macintosh发射40周年纪念日，CHM庆祝有史以来最具标志性和有影响力的产品之一。原始硬件，软件，设计和营销/公关团队的成员包括Bill Atkinson，Steve Capps，Andy Cunningham，Andy Hertzfeld，Bruce Horn，Susan Kare，Dan&#39;l Lewin和Mike Murray以及内部人士和专家Chriss和Chriss Chriss Espinosa，Guy Kawasaki，Steven Levy和David Pogue，分享故事并讨论Mac的影响。</p></blockquote><p>当我键入此句子时，太平洋时间晚上7点 /东部晚上10点直播。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“疯狂伟大：40”面板讨论的Apple Mac”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/insanely-great">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Steven Levy：“Apple 分享了为何 40 年前 Mac 仍然占据统治地位的秘密” </title><link href="https://www.wired.com/story/plaintext-apple-secret-40-year-old-mac-still-rules/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va9" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/levy-mac-still-rules" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40545</id><published> 2024-01-25T02：10：21Z</published><updated> 2024-01-25T06：05：40Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>史蒂文·列维（Steven Levy）在《纪念Mac成立40周年》的Wired方面表现出色，包括对众多苹果高管的采访：</p><blockquote><p>在过去的几年中，MacIntoshes的形式相当稳定。将来，Mac看起来会完全不同，就像iMac从篮球变成<a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/563365/imac-g4-design-memory-ergonomics.html">灯</a>的时候吗？</p><p>苹果工业设计领导者莫莉·安德森（Molly Anderson）说：“将来肯定有革命的可能性。” “当我们启动一个新项目时，我们并不是从考虑现有产品的受欢迎程度的限制开始。我们一直专注于尝试为工作设计最佳工具。”乔斯维亚克（Joswiak）补充说，一直勇于继续更改Mac以保持最前沿 - 当然总是以故意的方式。他说：“通往科技地狱的道路是由做事的人铺平的，因为他们可以，不是因为他们应该这样做。”</p></blockquote><p>乔尼·艾夫（Jony Ive）曾经告诉我，苹果的指导原则之一绝不是为了改变而改变。如果一个想法不能使产品变得更好，他们就不会这样做。如果这意味着某些产品仅在十年或两倍的形式中发生根本变化，那就这样吧。良好的设计应该经受时间的考验。</p><p> Levy还包括<a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-news/the-birth-of-the-mac-rolling-stones-1984-feature-on-steve-jobs-and-his-whiz-kids-243516/">他在原始发布中为滚石乐队写的文章</a>的摘录：</p><blockquote><p>如果您在个人计算机上有任何以前的经验，那么您可能希望看到的是某种不透明的代码，称为“提示”，由朦胧的背景上的磷光绿色或白色字母组成。 Macintosh看到的是发现者。在宜人的，轻便的背景下，出现了称为“图标”的小图片，代表您可用的选择。单词处理程序可能由笔表示，而允许您绘制图片的程序可能具有画笔图标。文件将代表存储的文件 - 书籍报告，信件，法律摘要等。要查看特定文件，您将移动鼠标，这又将光标移至所需的文件。您将两次点击鼠标上的一个按钮，并且文件的内容将出现在屏幕上：灯光上的深色，就像一张纸一样。</p><p>这似乎很简单，但是大多数个人计算机（包括IBM PC）无法做到这一点。</p><p> “当您向MAC展示绝对的新手时，” MAC团队22岁的出版物Chris Espinosa说：“他认为这是所有计算机的工作方式。那是我们最高的成就。我们使几乎所有被制成的计算机看起来都完全荒谬。”</p></blockquote><p> Espinosa可能是苹果公司唯一<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2022/03/22/espinosa-45">可以说</a>“ 40周年？没什么。”</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“史蒂文·利维（Steven Levy）：“苹果分享了为什么40岁的Mac仍然统治的秘密”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/levy-mac-still-rules">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> “向我展示更多 Mac”：有史以来的每台 Macintosh </title><link href="https://mac40th.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va8" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/zufi-more-macs" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40544</id><published> 2024-01-25T01：46：42Z</published><updated> 2024-01-25T01：46：43Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>乔纳森·祖菲：</p><blockquote><p>为了庆祝这一里程碑， <em>Mac40th.com</em>展示了每一个Macintosh桌面和便携式苹果有史以来制作了数百张照片，作为创作咖啡桌的一部分拍摄的照片<em>标志性的一部分：对苹果创新的摄影贡献</em>（第三版<a href="https://iconicbook.com/">现在可用</a>截至2023年底）。该网站还包括我在过去14年中收集的<a href="https://www.getoffworld.com/">凯文·泰勒（Kevin Taylor）</a> ，<a href="https://www.forest-mcmullin.com/">森林·麦克穆林（Forest McMullin</a> ）等人（包括视频）拍摄的照片。</p><p>该网站易于使用：您会看到连续的随机Mac流 - 只需继续单击“向我展示更多Mac”，这就是您所获得的。如果您是Hard Core Mac粉丝，则此网站应该让您忙得很长时间。</p></blockquote><p>美丽的。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“向我展示更多Mac”：有史以来每个Macintosh都"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/zufi-more-macs">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>哈里·麦克拉肯 (Harry McCracken) 谈初代 Macintosh </title><link href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91013403/40-years-later-the-original-mac-is-more-amazing-than-ever" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va7" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/mccracken-original-macintosh" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40543</id><published> 2024-01-25T01：42：08Z</published><updated> 2024-01-25T01：42：08Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>哈里·麦克拉肯（Harry McCracken），在快速公司写作：</p><blockquote><p>该原始Mac中最著名的部分是其软件界面，尽管<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/gilpress/2017/01/15/steve-jobs-steals-from-xerox-to-battle-big-brother-ibm/?sh=6b939dc012e0">懒惰的传统智慧</a>仅仅模仿了<a href="https://zurb.com/blog/steve-jobs-and-xerox-the-truth-about-inno">Xerox的Parc Lab所做的工作，但</a>它充满了新想法。但是目前，我最着迷于其工业设计。由杰里·马诺克（Jerry Manock）和特里·奥扬（Terry Oyama）创建的那个娇小的米色盒子与任何人在那之前见过的东西都不同，至少在厨房外面。 [...]</p><p>但是，如果所有第一个Mac启发的都是怀旧之处，那么我们将看不见它的大胆。与Apple的第一台大片PC <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/90614203/watch-a-tv-news-report-on-the-wacky-apple-ii-knockoffs-of-the-1980s">（Apple II）</a>不同，它具有内置显示屏，但没有集成的键盘。它还牺牲了Apple II的大多数定义功能，例如其令人眼花colormand图形和扩展插槽。</p><p>回想起来，它是苹果有史以来最胆的gambits之一。想象一下，该公司推出了一款新智能手机，该智能手机几乎与iPhone无关。您不能 - 或者至少会使我的想象力造成影响。</p></blockquote><p>这就是让我无法<em>获得</em>Mac直到我拥有的原因。 Apple II定义了我认为的计算机，并且因为Mac并没有<em>任何方式</em>类似于Apple II（它甚至没有运行Apple II软件的兼容模式），这对我来说似乎是其他的。某种设备，而不是<em>计算机</em>。</p><p>事实证明，这是任何人设计的计算机的最佳概念。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接到“原始Macintosh上的Harry McCracken”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/mccracken-original-macintosh">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Jason Snell：“Mac 40 岁了” </title><link href="https://www.theverge.com/24048479/apple-mac-40-anniversary" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va6" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/snell-mac-40" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40542</id><published> 2024-01-25T01：32：31Z</published><updated> 2024-01-25T01：32：31Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>杰森·斯内尔（Jason Snell），为《边缘》写作：</p><blockquote><p>二十年前，在Mac成立20周年，我<a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/169580/themacturns20jobs.html">问史蒂夫·乔布斯（Steve Jobs）</a> ，Mac在iPod时代是否仍然与苹果有关。他嘲笑Mac并不重要的前景：“当然”是。</p><p>然而，十年后，苹果的收入越来越由iPhone主导，而新iPad的最新成功为公司提供了另一种横幅产品。当我采访苹果执行人菲尔·席勒（Phil Schiller）成立30周年时，我发现自己也问他有关Mac的相关性。 <a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/222761/apple-executives-on-the-mac-at-30-the-mac-keeps-going-forever.html">他还嘲笑</a>：“我们的观点是，Mac一直在继续前进，”他说。</p><p>自乔布斯（Jobs）在库比蒂诺（Cupertino）的一场活动中揭开了原始的麦金托什（Macintosh）以来，今天就标志着40年，这再次感觉到Mac的下一步是正确的。</p></blockquote><p> Snell片段上的副标题将其钉住：</p><blockquote><p>苹果运行时间最长的产品在该公司业务中所占的比例越来越小。然而，它从未如此成功。</p></blockquote><p>斯内尔（Snell）在六种颜色上进行了六种颜色，其中包括<a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2024/01/mac-40-a-quick-qa-with-greg-joswiak/">对格雷格·乔斯维克（Greg Joswiak）的采访</a>，并分别深入<a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2024/01/mac-at-40-the-eras-tour/">研究了Mac历史上的主要时代</a>，将它们除以处理器架构。从那件作品中：</p><blockquote><p> IBM PC和新兴的DOS PC克隆标准不是这里唯一的敌人。早期存在许多其他平台，包括产生大部分苹果收入的Apple II的平台。</p><p>历史倾向于将所有内容变成简单的叙述，因此您可能会期望在引入Mac的那一刻，Apple开始偏离Apple II。那<em>没有</em>发生。苹果直到Mac的存在将近十年才停止最后一个Apple II模型。引入Mac后，Apple不断引入新的Apple II模型：三个月后的紧凑型IIC和两年后的16位IIG。</p></blockquote><p> Mac对我来说是一种好奇心，在1980年代长大 - 有趣，但是当时是Apple II平台引起了我的注意（和心脏）。然后，当我终于在1991年获得了我的第一台Mac（Macintosh LC，带有4 MB的RAM和40 MB硬盘），我<em>明白了</em>。就像在黑暗的房间里打开光线一样。我终于明白了。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“ Jason Snell：“ Mac转40”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/snell-mac-40">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>乔恩·斯图尔特将重返《每日秀》 </title><link href="https://www.nbcnews.com/pop-culture/jon-stewart-returns-daily-show-rcna135483" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va5" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/jon-stewart-returns" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40541</id><published> 2024-01-24T23：22：48Z</published><updated> 2024-01-24T23：22：49Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Angela Yang和Diana Dasrath，报告NBC新闻：</p><blockquote><p> “每日秀”的长期观众很快将在托管椅上看到一张熟悉的面孔。 NBC News确认，乔恩·斯图尔特（Jon Stewart）于1996年至2015年主持了该节目，他将重返该计划。 [...]</p><p>根据Comedy Central的新闻稿，Stewart将在2024年大选中举办周一晚上，然后继续担任每集执行制片人，直到今年年底和下一集。在斯图尔特（Stewart）没有举办的几天里，“每日秀”将继续依靠一支旋转的通讯员团队。</p></blockquote><p>我很久以来听到的最好的电视新闻。<em>乔恩·斯图尔特（Jon Stewart）在Apple TV+上的问题</em>是该节目很无聊。与斯图尔特主持的<em>每日演出从来</em>都不是无聊的。</p><div> <a  title="永久链接“乔恩·斯图尔特（Jon Stewart）正在返回“每日秀”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/jon-stewart-returns">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Spotify 公布其在欧盟后 DMA 时代侧载的计划</title><link href="https://newsroom.spotify.com/2024-01-24/the-dma-means-a-better-spotify-for-artists-creators-and-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va4" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/spotify-dma-plans" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40540</id><published> 2024-01-24T23：11：21Z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T22：04：24Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Spotify：</p><blockquote><p>多年来，即使在我们自己的应用程序中，苹果也有这些规则，我们无法告诉您有关要约，成本或什至在哪里或如何购买的规则。我们知道，很疯狂。 DMA意味着我们<em>最终</em>能够分享有关欧盟交易，促销和更好价值付款选项的详细信息。对于您来说，对您来说，这对艺术家，作家和创作者来说意味着好事，他们希望建立听众，演唱会和喜欢有声读物的粉丝的观众。更重要的是？现在，所有这些都可以出现，而苹果征收的强制性约为30％，而苹果则在DMA下禁止。</p></blockquote><p> Spotify对iOS上的侧载如何工作的假设显然与今天《华尔街日报》中<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/wsj-apple-sideloading">苹果计划的描述</a>相矛盾。该期刊没有说明苹果公司计划收取的百分比委员会或费用，但听起来Spotify认为他们将提供iOS应用程序，通过该应用程序，他们根本不会为Apple支付任何苹果的应用程序。他们的博客文章有一系列前后的屏幕截图，“后”屏幕截图显示了苹果对“读者”应用程序权利所需的任何警告或sareSheets所需的任何警告或saresheets，荷兰约会应用程序，荷兰约会应用程序，或新的外部购买链接权利。</p><p> Spotify甚至计划使用多个应用程序运营自己的应用商店。 （似乎不清楚iOS的Spotify App Store是否会托管其他开发人员的游戏和应用程序，或者仅来自Spotify本身的一套应用程序。）</p><p> Spotify或多或少地假设他们将摆脱所有苹果的限制和佣金，并且可以随意将苹果的政策作为“漂亮的坚果”和“荒谬”：</p><blockquote><p>对于<em>各地的</em>每个Spotify客户来说，应该很容易。但是，如果您居住在某些市场之外，则由于苹果的荒谬规则，您将继续遇到令人沮丧的障碍。</p></blockquote><p>我们还不知道苹果的计划，但很快就会。但这听起来像苹果和Spotify对DMA所需的内容<em>完全</em>不同且完全不兼容。似乎一侧或另一侧是一个很大的惊喜。</p><div> <a  title="与“ Spotify”的永久性链接揭示了其在欧盟中遇难后的DMA时代的计划。”"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/spotify-dma-plans">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> 《华尔街日报》报道苹果在欧盟推出 iOS 侧载计划</title><link href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/apple-plans-new-fees-and-restrictions-for-downloads-outside-app-store-f464f426?mod=hp_lista_pos1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va3" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/wsj-apple-sideloading" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id>标签：daringfireball.net，2024：/linked//6.40539</id><published> 2024-01-24T22：51：28z</published><updated> 2024-01-26T17：03：55Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Aaron Tilley，Salvador Rodriguez，Sam Schechner和Kim Mackrael，《华尔街日报》（<a href="https://apple.news/AoSzTgHGXSpKQnmjAQTcSig">新闻+链接</a>）：</p><blockquote><p> Meta Platforms、Spotify 和其他公司正在为客户准备新的下载选项，以应对新规则。 Meta 正在考虑建立一个允许人们直接从 Facebook 广告下载应用程序的系统。据该公司称，Spotify 计划让用户能够直接从其网站下载部分 iPhone 应用程序。微软过去曾考虑推出自己的第三方游戏应用商店。 [...]</p><p>苹果公司对欧盟法律的态度将有助于确保该公司对在应用程序商店之外下载的应用程序保持密切监督，这一过程称为侧载。该公司将赋予自己审查在其应用商店之外下载的每个应用程序的能力。知情人士称，苹果还计划向在 App Store 之外提供下载的开发商收取费用。该公司尚未宣布其计划，并且可能会改变。</p><p>这些限制和费用可能会再次导致与应用程序开发商的紧张关系，其中一些开发商原本希望新法律允许他们向用户提供应用程序，而不受苹果的限制或他们认为的高额佣金。 Spotify欧洲政策高级董事Olivia Regnier说，新的欧洲法律“是一项有牙齿的法规，有可能申请罚款，并有可能拥有调查权。”</p></blockquote><p>该期刊的故事很详细，但听起来苹果正计划像上周的<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/coming_to_grips_with_apples_seemingly_unshakable_sense_of_app_store_entitlement">外部购买链接权利</a>一样，开发人员仍将在其中支付苹果27/12％的佣金。此审核过程如何适用于未通过应用商店分发的应用程序？</p><p>从一开始，我认为DMA对此根本不清楚这很奇怪。在这里，我们正处于生效生效的风口浪尖上，我们似乎仍然不知道欧洲委员会和苹果是否注视着DMA对合规要求的需求。</p><p> Clearly, the most strident critics of Apple&#39;s App Store policies believe that the DMA requires opening iOS to something akin to how the Mac works: where the App Store is one method of software distribution, but users are free to simply download apps directly from developers&#39; websites, so long as those apps are signed. According to the Journal, Apple is planning to announce something not like that at all.</p><p> I have a feeling that fireworks are going to fly when Apple announces their compliance plans, but I don&#39;t know. Maybe Apple has shared their plans in detail with the EC and the EC is fine with it. But if that&#39;s the case, I don&#39;t see how the DMA “has teeth” when it comes to sideloading.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘The Wall Street Journal on Apple’s Plans for iOS Sideloading in the E.U.’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/wsj-apple-sideloading">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Signal Will Cost $50 Million Per Year to Run </title><link href="https://signal.org/blog/signal-is-expensive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va2" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/signal-50m" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40538</id><published> 2024-01-24T22:50:27Z</published><updated> 2024-01-24T22:50:27Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Meredith Whittaker and Joshua Lund, writing for the Signal blog back in November:</p><blockquote><p> Instead of monetizing surveillance, we&#39;re supported by donations, including a generous initial loan from Brian Acton. Our goal is to move as close as possible to becoming fully supported by small donors, relying on a large number of modest contributions from people who care about Signal. We believe this is the safest form of funding in terms of sustainability: ensuring that we remain accountable to the people who use Signal, avoiding any single point of funding failure, and rejecting the widespread practice of monetizing surveillance.</p><p> But our nonprofit structure doesn&#39;t mean it costs less for Signal to produce a globally distributed communications app. Signal is a nonprofit, but we&#39;re playing in a lane dominated by multi-billion-dollar corporations that have defined the norms and established the tech ecosystem, and whose business models directly contravene our privacy mission. So in order to provide a genuinely useful alternative, Signal spends tens of millions of dollars every year. <em>We estimate that by 2025, Signal will require approximately $50 million dollars a year to operate — and this is very lean compared to other popular messaging apps that don&#39;t respect your privacy.</em></p></blockquote><p> Signal funds itself through voluntary donations. Most of its competitors are funded through advertising. But iMessage is funded through <em>device sales</em> . If it costs $50 million per year to operate Signal, I&#39;d guess it costs Apple more than that to run iMessage.</p><p> I know the <a href="https://daringfireball.net/search/beeper">Beeper thing</a> is last month&#39;s news, but the fact that iMessage costs a lot of money to operate is generally overlooked by those who think Apple should be forced to “open it up”, whatever that might mean.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Signal Will Cost $50 Million Per Year to Run’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/24/signal-50m">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://dayoneapp.com/download/daring-fireball/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va1" rel="shorturl"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2024/01/day_one_journal_app" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/feeds/sponsors//11.40537</id><author><name>大胆的火球商务部</name></author><published>2024-01-23T01:00:55Z</published><updated> 2024-01-23T01:00:56Z </updated><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Day One has launched its new Shared Journals feature, providing a collaborative space for reflection and connection.从今天开始，享受DF读者独有的特别优惠。</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Day One Journal App’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/feeds/sponsors/2024/01/day_one_journal_app">★</a></div> ]]>;</content><title> [Sponsor] Day One Journal App</title></entry><entry><title> Upgrade: 40th Anniversary of the Macintosh </title><link href="https://www.relay.fm/upgrade/496" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/va0" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/22/upgrade-mac-40" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40536</id><published> 2024-01-23T00:58:32Z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T06:13:00Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Myke Hurley hosting, with panelists Jason Snell, John Siracusa, Shelly Brisbin, Stephen Hackett, Dan Moren, and yours truly. Great topic list:</p><ul><li> First Mac owned</li><li> Favorite/best Mac</li><li> Favorite/best Mac software ever</li><li> Favorite/best Mac accessory or hardware</li><li> Hall of Shame: worst accessory, Mac, or moment</li></ul><p> There&#39;s even <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eNebqs-oPUg">a video version</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Upgrade: 40th Anniversary of the Macintosh’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/22/upgrade-mac-40">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Hey Calendar </title><link href="https://hey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9y" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/hey-calendar" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40534</id><published> 2024-01-20T23:27:00Z</published><updated> 2024-01-21T02:35:26Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>My thanks to Hey for sponsoring this week at DF to promote their new Hey Calendar.</p><p> Back in 2020 Hey launched their email service with a completely fresh take on a category that hadn&#39;t seen anything new in forever. I&#39;ve been subscribed since it launched, and still find it like nothing else. Their “screener” feature alone is worth it: get an email from someone you never want to see email from again? Just screen them out with a single thumbs-down button click. Those emails aren&#39;t trashed, and they aren&#39;t flagged as spam — they&#39;re screened out of your inbox (or in Hey&#39;s terms, <em>imbox</em> ), but they remain in a “Screened Out” mailbox just in case. Every email app should have something like this.</p><p> Now they&#39;ve done the same with calendaring. The all-new Hey Calendar brings flexibility, personality, and a radical new point of view to the boring old grid of dates.</p><p> So Hey is now both email and a calendar, all-in-one. As you <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/09/hey-calendar-now-in-app-store">may have heard</a> , they&#39;ve got an all-new mobile app for Hey Calendar.也。 Check out how much better things can be at <a href="https://hey.com/">HEY.com</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Hey Calendar’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/hey-calendar">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Spotify Attacks Apple&#39;s &#39;Outrageous&#39; 27 Percent Commission From External Links </title><link href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-68018618" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9z" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/spotify-app-store-outrage" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40535</id><published> 2024-01-20T23:26:42Z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T22:06:15Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Tom Gerken, writing for BBC News:</p><blockquote><p> On Wednesday, Apple announced it would permit app developers to sell products in places other than its own store — but only if they still paid commission. Spotify said that was “outrageous” and accused Apple of “stopping at nothing” to protect its profits. It is urging the British government to prevent similar fees being levied in the UK. [...]</p><p> Spotify has reacted with fury, saying the policy “flies in the face” of the US court&#39;s attempt to enable greater competition. “Once again, Apple has demonstrated that they will stop at nothing to protect the profits they exact on the backs of developers and consumers under their app store monopoly,” it said in a statement.</p></blockquote><p> I can see why Spotify doesn&#39;t like this, but I&#39;m not sure why Spotify doesn&#39;t qualify under the “reader” app category that can link to external web pages without paying Apple any commission at all. Also, I think Spotify is barking up the wrong tree while complaining about Apple&#39;s compliance with this US court order under the guise of Apple abusing a monopoly — Judge Gonzales specifically ruled that the App Store <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/09/10/epic-games-failed-to-prove-apple-is-a-monopolist-rules-judge.html">does not constitute a monopoly</a> .</p><p> Here&#39;s a simple thought I had today regarding whether Apple&#39;s new External Purchase Links entitlement policy is a good faith effort to comply with Judge Gonzales&#39; order: Will any developers actually choose to use it? Remember, to use this entitlement, developers must:</p><ul><li> <em>Still</em> offer in-app purchases through Apple&#39;s system, alongside external payment links.</li><li> Pay Apple a 27/12 percent commission on sales through external links.</li><li> Report monthly sales to Apple and submit to audits on demand.</li><li> Track users who follow those links so they can determine which sign-ups they owe Apple commission payments for.</li><li> Follow Apple&#39;s <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/storekit-external-entitlement-us/">strict design guidelines</a> for presenting those links.</li></ul><p> Or, they could just stick to using IAP exclusively. I&#39;m curious whether any developers at all will consider the new External Payment Links worth implementing. If not, how could it be a reasonable policy? It may well be <em>legal</em> , but bad faith and spite aren&#39;t illegal.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Spotify Attacks Apple’s ‘Outrageous’ 27 Percent Commission From External Links’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/spotify-app-store-outrage">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Apple Finally Reveals Vision Pro&#39;s Weight </title><link href="https://9to5mac.com/2024/01/19/vision-pro-weight-comparirson-meta-quest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9x" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/vision-pro-weight" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40533</id><published> 2024-01-20T22:37:21Z</published><updated> 2024-01-20T22:57:23Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Chance Miller, 9to5Mac:</p><blockquote><p>正如您所看到的，Vision Pro 肯定比市场上其他耳机重，Meta Quest Pro 除外。 But it&#39;s also important to remember that, other than the Valve Index, these other headsets have their batteries built-in, while Vision Pro relies on an external battery pack.</p><p>考虑到这一点，Vision Pro 实际上比其他没有集成电池的主要耳机更轻。</p></blockquote><ul><li> Vision Pro: 600–650 grams (depending on light seal and headband)</li><li> Meta Quest Pro: 722 grams</li><li> Meta Quest 3: 515 grams</li><li> PlayStation VR2: 560 grams</li></ul><p> Also on the <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-vision-pro/specs/">tech specs page</a> is the RAM: 16 GB for all models. <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/08/vision-pro-preorders">As I predicted</a> , there are multiple storage tiers: 512 GB for +$200, 1 TB for +$400.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Apple Finally Reveals Vision Pro’s Weight’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/vision-pro-weight">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> &#39;Making Apple Vision Pro&#39;</title><link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=luFGI13Mv8o" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9w" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/making-apple-vision-pro" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40532</id><published> 2024-01-20T20:55:40Z</published><updated> 2024-01-20T20:55:41Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Behind-the-scenes teaser video from Apple showing bits of how Vision Pro is manufactured and assembled. I could watch an hour of this.</p><p> Also of note: the YouTube version is presented in widescreen 16:9 aspect ratio, but Tim Cook posted a version of the same video to Twitter/X in the tall 9:16 ratio. Works perfectly both ways. ( <a href="https://www.threads.net/@prolost/post/C2VRzfGvMDa">Via Stu Maschwitz</a> .)</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘‘Making Apple Vision Pro’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/making-apple-vision-pro">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> &#39;没有什么。 There Ain&#39;t Nothing in Room 237.&#39; </title><link href="https://www.instagram.com/archdigest/p/C2Sm14Hu1Cb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9v" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/aint-nothing-in-room-237" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40531</id><published> 2024-01-20T20:54:01Z</published><updated> 2024-01-20T20:54:43Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>File this away for the next time you remodel a bathroom.华丽的。</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘‘Nothing. There Ain’t Nothing in Room 237.’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/aint-nothing-in-room-237">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> I&#39;m Imagining Bill Hader as Stefan: &#39;Ikea&#39;s Latest Vision Pro Accessory Has It All…&#39; </title><link href="https://www.threads.net/@danielraffel/post/C2TnbnWrHmd" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9u" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/ikea-head-lamp" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40530</id><published> 2024-01-20T19:34:19Z</published><updated> 2024-01-20T19:39:10Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Daniel Raffel on Threads:</p><blockquote><p> This IKEA table lamp in the shape of a mannequin head is probably going to be the hottest Vision Pro accessory.</p></blockquote><p> Vision Pro really does raise a “Where do you keep it?” question, and <a href="https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/iskaerna-led-table-lamp-multicolor-90510403/">the $40 Iskärna might be a fun answer</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘I’m Imagining Bill Hader as Stefan: ‘Ikea’s Latest Vision Pro Accessory Has It All…’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/20/ikea-head-lamp">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Tim Bray: &#39;Mourning Google&#39; </title><link href="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2024/01/15/Google-2024" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9t" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/bray-google-kagi" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40529</id><published> 2024-01-20T01:57:34Z</published><updated> 2024-01-20T22:52:04Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Tim Bray:</p><blockquote><p> But those Ten Blue Links surfaced by the PageRank-that-was had a special magic. I found them intensely human, a reflection of the voices populating what remains of the Web, the only platform without a vendor. This was true when I was there and I said so, but was laughed at.</p><p> And now, in Anno Domini 2024, Google has lost its edge in search. There are plenty of things it can&#39;t find. There are compelling alternatives. To me this feels like a big inflection point, because around the stumbling feet of the Big Tech dinosaurs, the Web&#39;s mammals, agile and flexible, still scurry. They exhibit creative energy and strongly-flavored voices, and those voices still sometimes find and reinforce each other without being sock puppets of shareholder-value-focused private empires.</p></blockquote><p> That line: <em>the Web&#39;s mammals, agile and flexible, still scurry</em> .</p><p>这引起了共鸣。 I&#39;d expand that to <em>indie</em> mammals, whether writing web or native apps — or often now, both. One of the indie mammals today, one that fits the bill for a “compelling alternative” to Google Search, is <a href="https://kagi.com/">Kagi</a> . I&#39;d been using DuckDuckGo for many years as my primary search engine, but I switched to Kagi in the summer of 2022 and haven&#39;t looked back. I&#39;ve been paying $10/month for a <a href="https://blog.kagi.com/unlimited-searches-for-10#ultimate">Professional plan</a> (unlimited searches per month, unlimited access to Kagi&#39;s FastGPT and Universal Summarizer) and I&#39;m <em>this close</em> to upgrading to the $25/month Ultimate plan just to support this crazy company.</p><p> Kagi search isn&#39;t just good for a Google alternative, I flat out prefer its results to Google&#39;s. Better results in a far better presentation. The only thing I find myself resorting to Google Search for are <em>old</em> links — when searching for news or specific articles that are, I don&#39;t know, maybe more than 10 years old, no search engine seems able to compete with Google. But for everything else, I prefer Kagi. I go weeks at a time not using Google Search.</p><p> Kagi has no ads — it&#39;s entirely supported by users paying for their excellent service. It&#39;s never going to topple Google, but the man behind Kagi, Vladimir Prelovac, isn&#39;t trying to. He&#39;s just trying to make the best search engine — <a href="https://kagi.com/orion/">and web browser!</a> - 可能的。 Just trying to make something great <em>for users</em> .</p><p> I know: of all the things you thought you&#39;d never pay for, a search engine is probably near the top of the list. But try Kagi out for yourself.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Tim Bray: ‘Mourning Google’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/bray-google-kagi">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> YouTube and Spotify Are Not Launching Vision Pro Apps Either </title><link href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-01-18/youtube-and-spotify-join-netflix-in-not-launching-apple-vision-pro-apps" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9s" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/youtube-spotify-vision-pro" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40528</id><published> 2024-01-19T08:33:35Z</published><updated> 2024-01-20T00:39:22Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Gurman and Ashley Carman, reporting for Bloomberg (Gurman has been killing it this week on the Vision Pro apps beat — he&#39;s breaking all of these stories):</p><blockquote><p> Google&#39;s YouTube and Spotify Technology SA, the world&#39;s most popular video and music services, are joining Netflix Inc. in steering clear of Apple Inc.&#39;s upcoming mixed-reality headset.</p><p> YouTube 在周四的一份声明中表示，它不打算为 Apple Vision Pro 推出新的应用程序，也不会让其长期存在的 iPad 应用程序在该设备上运行——至少目前是这样。 YouTube, like Netflix, is recommending that customers use a web browser if they want to see its content: “YouTube users will be able to use YouTube in Safari on the Vision Pro at launch.”</p><p> Spotify also isn&#39;t currently planning a new app for visionOS — the Vision Pro&#39;s operating system — and doesn&#39;t expect to enable its iPad app to run on the device when it launches, according to a person familiar with matter. But the music service will still likely work from a web browser.</p></blockquote><p> Spotify&#39;s fuck-you to Apple I don&#39;t find surprising, given the <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2022/01/27/spotify-airplay">longstanding animosity</a> between them. But YouTube is a surprise to me, and it&#39;s a sign of how profoundly different the relationship is between Google and Apple today from the pre-Android era. In 2007, before third-party apps were even supported on iOS, YouTube was a built-in app on the original iPhone. (Apple designed and made the app; Google provided the back-end APIs and, obviously, the content.) Then-Google-CEO (and then-Apple-board-member!) Eric Schmidt was invited on stage by Steve Jobs to demo the YouTube app and sing the praises of both the iPhone and the Apple-Google partnership. That Apple-made Google-supported YouTube app was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPhone_OS_3">still a built-in default app on iOS when the iPad launched in 2010</a> .</p><p> So for both the original iPhone and iPad, YouTube was part of the system software. For Vision Pro, there&#39;s no app at all, not even the iPad app.</p><p> Regarding Netflix&#39;s pass on Vision Pro, a little birdie informed me that until this week, the Netflix iPad app was available for those with access to Vision Pro hardware, and it worked just fine. This birdie still has the Netflix iPad app installed on their Vision Pro. Perhaps people at Netflix would disagree with just how well it worked — I don&#39;t know — but I get the strong impression that the decision was political/strategic/spiteful, not technical. Entertainment is not the sole purpose of Vision Pro, but it&#39;s a major one — and surely the primary one for many buyers — and it&#39;s launching without the two biggest video entertainment apps in the world. Apple expected Netflix&#39;s iPad app to be there on launch day.</p><p> This isn&#39;t a dealbreaker — watching Netflix through Safari should be OK (albeit without offline downloads, a huge factor for using Vision Pro on airplanes), and many people think of YouTube as a website, not an app. But there&#39;s no way around it: this is a bad look for Apple, not for Netflix or Google. The buck stops with Tim Cook on this. He should have been on the horn with Ted Sarandos and Sundar Pichai and worked this out. It&#39;s his company that&#39;s launching a $3,500 headset.</p><p> It&#39;s also worth pointing out that these corporate pissing matches are reciprocal. They work in <em>both</em> directions. I doubt we&#39;ll see any calls for Netflix, YouTube, or Spotify to be investigated by antitrust regulators over their refusal to allow their iPad apps to run on Vision Pro. But imagine if Netflix and Spotify <em>wanted</em> to be on Vision Pro on launch day and Apple refused, to leave more room in the spotlight for Apple TV+ and Apple Music. Or what happens if the Vision platform becomes a huge hit, and only then do Netflix, YouTube, and Spotify submit native apps — and Apple turns them down, on the grounds of “Where were you when we needed you?” People would lose their shit. We might even get <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2023/12/beep_beep">a testy tweet from Elizabeth Warren</a> .</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘YouTube and Spotify Are Not Launching Vision Pro Apps Either’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/youtube-spotify-vision-pro">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>电池？ What Battery? Oh, That Battery. </title><link href="https://www.wired.com/story/one-part-of-apple-vision-pro-apple-doesnt-want-you-to-see/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9r" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/vision-pro-battery" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40527</id><published> 2024-01-19T07:03:00Z</published><updated> 2024-01-31T00:22:57Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Lauren Goode, writing at Wired:</p><blockquote><p> Apple seems to not want you to notice the battery. The external battery pack barely appears on the <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-vision-pro/">product page</a> on Apple&#39;s website, showing up only at the end of a photo gallery at the bottom of the page. And in demo sessions this week, Apple told journalists they were not allowed to snap photos or capture any video of the hardware, an unusual rule for a press briefing. Instead, the company had its own photographer take photos during the Vision Pro demos. Every photo you&#39;ve seen this week of reporters sitting on a couch while wearing the headset were shot by Apple.</p><p> Notably, the battery pack doesn&#39;t appear in any of them. One attendee chose to run the attached cable down the back of his sweatshirt. In <a href="https://www.threads.net/@reckless1280/post/C2K7mzQxXru?hl=en">another shared image</a> , of The Verge&#39;s Nilay Patel, the cable is clearly visible, but the photo is cropped to avoid showing the battery pack. Chokkattu experienced this too; he set the Vision Pro&#39;s battery pack on the couch cushion next to him during his demo, but in the photo Apple shared with us, the offending pack is cropped out of the frame.</p></blockquote><p> To Apple&#39;s credit, they weren&#39;t at all cagey about this when they took <a href="https://mastodon.social/@gruber/111767493035111862">my picture</a> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@gruber/post/C2LKPu5P0Wu">using Vision Pro</a> Tuesday. They asked if I&#39;d like photos taken by their photographer (who used an iPhone 15 Pro), I said sure, and they suggested draping the battery cable behind my back. It&#39;s not just Apple being weird about the external battery; it&#39;s that the external battery <em>is</em> weird. So of course their photography is going to de-emphasize it.</p><p> Almost every first-generation product has things like this <sup>*</sup> — glaring deficiencies dictated by the limits of technology.最初的 Mac 的 RAM (128 KB) 和存储空间（单个<a href="https://lowendmac.com/2016/floppy-disk-compatibility-and-incompatibility-in-the-mac-world/">400 KB 单面软盘驱动器</a>）太少。 The original iPhone only supported 2G EDGE cellular networking, which was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enhanced_Data_rates_for_GSM_Evolution#:~:text=EDGE%20can%20carry%20a%20bandwidth,much%20traffic%20as%20standard%20GPRS.">unfathomably slow</a> and didn&#39;t work at all while you were on a voice call.最初的 Apple Watch 速度非常慢，一次充电很难坚持一整天。第一代 Vision Pro 的外部电池组仅提供 2 至 2.5 小时的电池续航时间。此外，Vision Pro 耳机本身（没有任何内置电池）仍然太大太重。</p><p><a href="https://paulgraham.com/really.html">保罗·格雷厄姆有一句精彩的格言</a>：</p><blockquote><p>不要担心人们会说什么。如果您的第一个版本令人印象深刻，以至于巨魔不会取笑它，那么您等待发布的时间太长了。</p></blockquote><p> <small>* The original iPod is the exception that proves the rule. That little thing was, as <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Perfect-Thing-Shuffles-Commerce-Coolness/dp/0743285239/?tag=df-amzn-20">Steven Levy&#39;s excellent book aptly declared</a> , perfect.</small></p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Battery? What Battery? Oh, That Battery.’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/vision-pro-battery">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> More on Apple&#39;s Software Workaround for the Apple Watch Import Ban </title><link href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT211027" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9q" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/more-on-apple-watch-software-workaround" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40526</id><published> 2024-01-19T06:27:05Z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T22:11:28Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>From an updated footnote in Apple&#39;s “How to Use the Blood Oxygen App on Apple Watch” support page:</p><blockquote><p> The ability to measure Blood Oxygen is no longer available on Apple Watch units sold by Apple in the United States on or after January 18, 2024. These are indicated with part numbers ending in LW/A.</p></blockquote><p> Apple refuses to say so, but it seems clear that this is a <em>software</em> change. These new watch units still have the blood-oxygen sensor, but the sensor is disabled by software. This workaround definitely does <em>not</em> apply to already-sold watches, even after those watches upgrade to future versions of WatchOS. The reason why is that the ITC injunction is an import ban. Apple is banned from importing watches that violate Masimo&#39;s patents. Units that have already been sold aren&#39;t affected by an import ban.</p><p> The software workaround is clearly distinguishing which watches can continue to use the blood-oxygen sensor and which can&#39;t by checking the device identifiers or serial numbers or something. This is why it took Apple a few weeks to come up with this solution: they needed to retool production to produce units with distinguishable part numbers. It would have been trivial to just disable the sensor on all watches, old and new alike, with a WatchOS update. (Although existing owners would likely refuse to update.)</p><p> Apple also refuses to say so, but it seems clear that these new units will have the blood-oxygen sensors enabled in a future software update if and when they win on appeal or otherwise settle with Masimo. I&#39;m pretty sure that&#39;s just a question of <em>when</em> , but <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/masimo-ceo-better-off-without">maybe it&#39;s an <em>if</em></a> .</p><p> (Because the ban was instituted by the International Trade Commission, I believe Apple could tell Masimo to go fuck themselves if Apple Watch Series 9 and Ultra 2 were manufactured in America, because an import ban wouldn&#39;t matter.)</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘More on Apple’s Software Workaround for the Apple Watch Import Ban’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/more-on-apple-watch-software-workaround">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Masimo CEO on Apple Watch Blood-Oxygen Sensor: &#39;I Really Feel Wholeheartedly That Consumers Are Better Off Without It&#39; </title><link href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-01-18/masimo-ceo-says-users-are-better-off-without-apple-s-oxygen-tool" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9p" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/masimo-ceo-better-off-without" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40525</id><published> 2024-01-19T06:15:31Z</published><updated> 2024-01-19T06:15:31Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Gurman and Edward Ludlow, reporting for Bloomberg:</p><blockquote><p> Customers should buy pulse oximeters from Masimo or others instead, [Masimo CEO Joe] Kiani said in an interview Thursday on Bloomberg TV. “Apple is masquerading what they are offering to consumers as a reliable, medical pulse oximeter, even though it is not,” he said. “I really feel wholeheartedly that consumers are better off without it.”</p><p> Apple said that Kiani&#39;s claims are false and that its watch&#39;s blood oxygen feature is accurate, works very well for customers and in some cases can save lives.</p></blockquote><p> Tell us what you really think, Joe.</p><blockquote><p> Masimo&#39;s CEO said he hasn&#39;t spoken to Apple personally about a settlement, and that nobody from Apple has reached out about coming to an agreement.</p><p> “There are court-ordered mediations that I cannot get into that have been held before,” he said. “And there will be additional meetings probably in the future.”</p><p> Kiani added that he doesn&#39;t consider those meetings to be steps toward settling litigation. Apple disputed Kiani&#39;s characterization that nobody from Apple has reached out, saying that the company has held a mediation and that a future meeting has been set.</p></blockquote><p> One of the most frequent questions I&#39;ve been getting from readers this week is basically, “Why the hell hasn&#39;t Apple paid to settle this, or just bought the entire company?” I have no idea, but the above sounds like neither side is close to settling.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Masimo CEO on Apple Watch Blood-Oxygen Sensor: ‘I Really Feel Wholeheartedly That Consumers Are Better Off Without It’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/19/masimo-ceo-better-off-without">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/the_sixth_finger" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9o" rel="shorturl"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024://1.40524</id><published> 2024-01-19T00:08:22Z</published><updated> 2024-01-27T05:42:30Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text"> Apple doesn&#39;t have to make a platform-destructive money-grab policy change to ruin the Mac. They can ruin it simply by planting the seed of doubt that they *might*. </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Brent Simmons, “ <a href="https://inessential.com/2024/01/17/corporations_are_not_to_be_loved">Corporations Are Not to Be Loved</a> ”:</p><blockquote><p> Apple doesn&#39;t care about you personally in the least tiny bit, and if you were in their way somehow, they would do whatever their might — effectively infinite compared to your own — enables them to deal with you.</p><p> Luckily, Apple has just provided us all with a reminder. Just like the sixth finger in an AI-rendered hand, Apple&#39;s policies for <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/storekit-external-entitlement-us/">Distributing apps in the US that provide an external purchase link</a> are startlingly graceless and a jarring, but not surprising, reminder that Apple is not a real person and not worthy of your爱。</p></blockquote><p> <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/coming_to_grips_with_apples_seemingly_unshakable_sense_of_app_store_entitlement">I wrote yesterday</a> about Apple damaging their brand and reputation with this policy. I&#39;m friends — close friends, in many cases, perhaps <a href="https://daringfireball.net/search/vesper+brent+simmons">especially</a> in Brent&#39;s case — with many longtime indie Mac developers. I&#39;m up to at least half a dozen instances now where group chat discussions have turned to concerns that Apple might assert the same demand for a 27 percent cut of all Mac software. Meaning not just apps in the Mac App Store, but apps from outside the Mac App Store — even apps that are <em>only</em> available outside the Mac App Store. Even apps from developers who don&#39;t have any apps in the Mac App Store. There&#39;s now genuine concern that Apple is going to declare that they want a 27/12 percent revenue cut from all Mac software, full stop.</p><p> I&#39;m disappointed by Apple&#39;s decision to demand their commission from sales on the web linked from within iOS apps, but not surprised. But I can&#39;t emphasize enough how flabbergasted many developers are — nor how offended. (Brent was too polite to point out that Apple&#39;s external links policy is also a proverbial third finger.)</p><p> Prior to MacOS 10.12 Sierra, MacOS had three options in the Security &amp; Privacy panel of System Preferences (as it was <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2022/06/basic_app_guy_mac_settings">then named</a> <sup id="fnr1-2024-01-18"><a href="#fn1-2024-01-18">1</a></sup> ) for the sources of apps permitted to run: “App Store”, “App Store and identified developers”, and “Anywhere”. <em>Identified developers</em> means apps from outside the App Store that are cryptographically signed by both Apple and a developer with an Apple developer account. Starting with 10.12 Sierra, <a href="https://512pixels.net/projects/aqua-screenshot-library/macos-10-12-sierra/#jp-carousel-16675">the “Anywhere” option was removed</a> . You can still re-enable the ability to run unsigned software, but <a href="https://macpaw.com/amp/how-to/allow-apps-anywhere">you need to run an administrator-authenticated command</a> in Terminal ( <code>sudo spctl --master-disable</code> ).</p><p> So, practically speaking, commercial Mac software must be signed, and Apple controls signing. That means Apple <em>could</em> , technically, attempt to demand such a commission (along with the arduous monthly accounting of sales, and the profoundly intrusive option to demand an audit at any time).</p><p> I am convinced that Apple has no such intention. I think I understand how Apple views iOS (including its sibling derivatives iPadOS, tvOS, and now VisionOS) as an altogether different type of platform than the Mac. If it were up to Apple, the External Purchase Link Entitlement on iOS wouldn&#39;t exist, because they&#39;re only allowing external purchase links in apps because a court decision demanded it — and thus isn&#39;t an indication of what they want to do与Mac。 The general-purpose-computing flexibility and power of the Mac is <em>necessary</em> , not just <em>nice to have</em> , or <em>the way things have always been</em> .</p><p> Back in 2010, when the iPad was just six months old (and ran “iOS”), I wrote a piece titled “ <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2010/12/future_of_the_mac_in_an_ios_world">The Future of the Mac in an iOS World</a> ”. The whole thing holds up and is worth a re-read (or first read, if you didn&#39;t read it then). But I&#39;ll quote the nut of it here:</p><blockquote><p> For all the aforementioned growth in Mac sales — remarkable by any measure, but especially so for a 25-year-old platform — the iPad, just six months old, is already outselling the Mac. Here&#39;s the short version of the “Mac is doomed” scenario: iOS is the future, Mac OS X is the past, and Apple, unlike most major tech companies, is strongly inclined to abandon the past in the name of the future.</p><p> You can&#39;t really argue with that, can you? But the premise that the end is near for the Mac presupposes quite a bit about the near-term future of iOS. [...]</p><p> The central conceit of the iPad is that it&#39;s a portable computer that does less — and because it does less, what it does do, it does better, more simply, and more elegantly. Apple can only begin phasing out the Mac if and when iOS expands to allow us to do everything we can do on the Mac. It&#39;s the heaviness of the Mac that allows iOS to remain light.</p><p> When I say that iOS has no baggage, that&#39;s not because there is no baggage. It&#39;s because the Mac is there to carry it. Long term — say, ten years out — well, all good things must come to an end. But in the short term, Mac OS X has an essential role in an iOS world: serving as the platform for complex, resource-intensive tasks.</p></blockquote><p> If there&#39;s one thing I wish I had added to that description of the Mac&#39;s essential role in the entire Apple ecosystem, it&#39;s that it&#39;s also <em>the</em> platform for whatever software developers can imagine and build, with no limits or rules other than the APIs — public or private — available in the system itself. And the only mistake I made in that column was thinking the Mac might have then only had a 10-year window of relevance remaining. The Mac today, at 40 years old, <sup id="fnr2-2024-01-18"><a href="#fn2-2024-01-18">2</a></sup> is if anything stronger and more essential than it was at 25. The move from Intel to Apple silicon is proof to my mind that Apple remains fully committed to the Mac. I now think it&#39;s a forever platform, where <em>forever</em> is at least as far into the future as I can imagine. Decades, plural.</p><p> Essential to the Mac&#39;s continuing relevance is that it is continuously evolving. Much has changed since 2010, and much will surely change between now and the Mac&#39;s 50th anniversary in 2034. But one thing that can&#39;t change without destroying it is its openness to software outside Apple&#39;s control. The Mac is a PC. The others, to borrow a term, are post-PC devices. I am convinced that every executive at Apple who needs to understand that does, and that a scheme along the lines of iOS&#39;s <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/storekit-external-entitlement-us/">External Purchase Link Entitlement</a> has never even been <em>considered</em> for the Mac. Everyone I know at Apple, from the trenches to the executive ranks, <em>loves</em> the Mac. Most of them went to work at Apple because of the Mac. They know that the Macintosh without Adobe, without Microsoft, without the indie developers who craft software that can only exist outside the Mac App Store, wouldn&#39;t be the Macintosh at all. And there&#39;s zero chance Adobe, Microsoft, or any of the indie shops I know would agree to <em>any</em> sort of mandatory revenue share, let alone a hefty one. <sup id="fnr3-2024-01-18"><a href="#fn3-2024-01-18">3</a></sup></p><p> But I don&#39;t sell Mac software. Among those who do, not only do they not share my confidence that Apple would do no such thing — they&#39;re genuinely concerned that it might be inevitable. “You don&#39;t need a weatherman to know which way the wind blows” is one of Bob Dylan&#39;s best lines, and this week&#39;s External Purchase Link Entitlement policy for iOS is a gust of foul-smelling wind so strong it demands a weather advisory.</p><p> Developer uncertainty regarding the viability of selling Mac software is the last thing needed for a platform that is already facing a dearth of new original native software. Apple doesn&#39;t have to make a platform-destructive money-grab policy change to ruin the Mac. They can ruin it simply by planting the seed of doubt that they <em>might</em> .</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2024-01-18"><p> Not only has System Preferences been renamed (and redesigned) as Settings, the panel then called “Security &amp; Privacy” is now “Privacy &amp; Security”.细节。 <a href="#fnr1-2024-01-18"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 1。">↩︎︎</a></p></li><li id="fn2-2024-01-18"><p> Lost in the hubbub surrounding the imminent launch of the Vision spatial computing platform is the fact that the Mac&#39;s 40th anniversary comes next week, Wednesday January 24. I am to understand that this anniversary will be celebrated by Apple <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2014/01/24/apple-reflects-on-the-mac-at-30-with-new-video-and-website-retrospective/">much like the Mac&#39;s 30th was</a> , and that Apple might also use the occasion to reveal its compliance plans for the EU&#39;s Digital Markets Act, which comes into effect March 7. <a href="#fnr2-2024-01-18"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 2。">↩︎</a></p></li><li id="fn3-2024-01-18"><p> I am heartened too by <a href="https://www.inverse.com/tech/mac-gaming-apple-silicon-interview">Apple&#39;s avowed interest in reinvigorating AAA gaming on the Mac</a> in the Apple silicon era. Sure, they&#39;d love for all the best Mac games to be in the Mac App Store, but they must know that just as with productivity apps, some PC game publishers are only willing to sell directly to customers. That&#39;s not to mention the essential role of third-party game stores like <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/">Steam</a> . The Mac&#39;s chances of becoming a serious gaming platform may well be slim, but those chances would be nil — zilch, zero, non-existent, nada — in a world where Apple attempted to extract console-like sales commissions from Mac software outside the App店铺。 Executives at Apple might be greedy, but they&#39;re not stupid. <a href="#fnr3-2024-01-18"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 3。">↩︎︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ &#39;Like the Sixth Finger in an AI-Rendered Hand&#39;</title></entry><entry><title> Netflix Has No App for VisionOS </title><link href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-01-17/watching-netflix-on-apple-vision-pro-you-ll-have-to-use-the-web" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9n" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/18/netflix-has-no-app-for-visionos" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40523</id><published> 2024-01-18T05:11:37Z</published><updated> 2024-01-19T09:31:18Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Gurman:</p><blockquote><p> Netflix Inc. isn&#39;t planning to launch an app for Apple Inc.&#39;s upcoming Vision Pro headset, marking a high-profile snub of the new technology by the world&#39;s biggest video subscription service.</p><p> Rather than designing a Vision Pro app — or even just supporting its existing iPad app on the platform — Netflix is essentially taking a pass. The company, which competes with Apple in streaming, said in a statement that users interested in watching its content on the device can do so from the web. [...]</p><p> The fact that Netflix isn&#39;t even willing to support the iPad approach suggests that it&#39;s taking a wait-and-see stance with the headset. It&#39;s also a bit of a reversal for the company, which <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2023-07-23/apple-vision-pro-will-developers-sell-visionos-apps-for-the-3-499-device-lkfg5b1l?sref=9hGJlFio">said in July</a> that it would support its iPad app on the Vision Pro. Even then, though, Netflix didn&#39;t plan to release software specifically for the headset&#39;s operating system, visionOS.</p></blockquote><p> “Said in July” links to a report from Gurman himself, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2023-07-23/apple-vision-pro-will-developers-sell-visionos-apps-for-the-3-499-device-lkfg5b1l?sref=9hGJlFio">which states</a> :</p><blockquote><p> But the biggest streamer of all, Netflix Inc., will take a pass. I&#39;m told that the company has no current plans to develop a native app for the Vision Pro. Of course, Netflix will still let its iPad app run on the headset unmodified.</p></blockquote><p> “当然”！</p><p> Here&#39;s the statement from Netflix:</p><blockquote><p> “Our members will be able to enjoy Netflix on the web browser on the Vision Pro, similar to how our members can enjoy Netflix on Macs,” Los Gatos, California-based Netflix said in the statement.</p></blockquote><p> Mac users sure do <em>enjoy</em> <a href="https://help.netflix.com/en/node/54816">not being able to download Netflix movies or shows</a> for offline viewing — you know, like in an airplane, one of the most obvious and common places where Vision Pro will be used.</p><p> Not having a native VisionOS app is one thing. Apparently having no current plans to make one is another. But it really feels like pure corporate spite — a pissing match — that Netflix is refusing to allow their iPad app to run on VisionOS. The iPad-app-on-Vision experience is actually pretty good, and for streaming apps in particular, ought to be fine. Not impressive, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/disney-plus-visionos">like the native VisionOS Disney+ app</a> , but just fine. I&#39;ll bet that Netflix is the <em>only</em> major streaming service without an app on VisionOS — iPad or native — on day one. Perhaps Netflix is using this as a negotiating tactic for something in return from Apple?</p><p> In addition to the fact that only being available through the web means no offline viewing, it might also mean that VisionOS users will not be able to launch Netflix from their home screens. I&#39;m not sure if VisionOS Safari has an “Add to Home Screen” feature, but if it doesn&#39;t, that&#39;s going to be an annoyance for Vision Pro users who want to watch Netflix. Telling Siri to open “netflix dot com” might be the only way to get there from your home screen.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Netflix Has No App for VisionOS’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/18/netflix-has-no-app-for-visionos">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Apple Will Begin Selling Series 9 and Ultra Watches With Blood Oxygen Sensors Disabled Tomorrow </title><link href="https://9to5mac.com/2024/01/17/apple-watch-series-9-ultra-2-without-blood-oxygen-sensor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9m" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/17/apple-watch-series-9-ultra-2-disabled-sensors" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40522</id><published> 2024-01-18T04:32:36Z</published><updated> 2024-01-18T04:32:36Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Apple, in a statement to Chance Miller at 9to5Mac:</p><blockquote><p> Apple&#39;s appeal is ongoing, and we believe the US Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit should reverse the USITC&#39;s decision. We strongly disagree with the USITC decision and resulting orders.</p><p> Pending the appeal, Apple is taking steps to comply with the ruling while ensuring customers have access to Apple Watch with limited disruption.这些步骤包括在美国推出不带血氧功能的 Apple Watch Series 9 和 Apple Watch Ultra 2 版本。 There is no impact to Apple Watch units previously purchased that include the Blood Oxygen feature.</p><p> Apple Watch Series 9 and Apple Watch Ultra 2 without the Blood Oxygen feature will become available from apple.com starting 6am PT on January 18, and from Apple Stores starting January 18.</p></blockquote><p> Without the <em>feature</em> — not without the <em>sensor</em> , <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/apple-workaround-itc-import-ban">as Aaron Tilley of The Wall Street Journal reported</a> in a story that <em>still</em> has not been corrected.</p><p> Apple.com&#39;s product pages for <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-series-9/">Series 9</a> and <a href="https://www.apple.com/apple-watch-ultra-2/">Ultra 2</a> now have <a href="https://daringfireball.net/misc/2024/01/apple-watch-blood-oxygen-feature-banner.png">a prominent banner at the top</a> that reads “Apple Watch Series 9 and Ultra 2 no longer include the blood oxygen feature.”</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Apple Will Begin Selling Series 9 and Ultra Watches With Blood Oxygen Sensors Disabled Tomorrow’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/17/apple-watch-series-9-ultra-2-disabled-sensors">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Apple Set to Collect $73 Million in Legal Fees From Epic Games </title><link href="https://twitter.com/games_fray/status/1747504304695484810?s=20" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9l" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/17/apple-epic-legal-fees" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40521</id><published> 2024-01-17T22:39:02Z</published><updated> 2024-01-17T22:47:03Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Apple, a court filing spotted by <a href="https://twitter.com/Florian4Gamers/status/1738673544572162438">Florian Mueller</a> at Games Fray:</p><blockquote><p> Please take notice that on March 5, 2024 at 10:00 am, or as soon thereafter as the matter may be heard by the Court, at the courtroom of the Honorable Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers, [...] Apple Inc. (“Apple”) will and hereby does move that this Court, pursuant to the mandate of the Ninth Circuit, enter judgment ordering Epic Games, Inc. (“Epic”) to pay Apple $73,404,326, plus additional amounts Apple is incurring during this ongoing litigation, under the indemnification provision of the Developer Program License Agreement.</p></blockquote><p> This is not simply about Epic having sued Apple and lost; it&#39;s about the fact that this whole saga started with Epic&#39;s Fortnite in-app payment processing stunt, blatantly violating <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/terms/apple-developer-program-license-agreement/#ADPLA10">the Developer Program License Agreement</a> . This wasn&#39;t like an edge case or technicality; Epic deliberately violated the clear rules of the DPLA as a publicity stunt to launch their antitrust lawsuit. File under “Fucking Around and Finding Out”.</p><p> Mueller writes:</p><blockquote><p> Early into the litigation, Epic accepted that if it loses on its antitrust claims (as it did), it owes damages. If Epic had prevailed on antitrust, the contract clause wouldn&#39;t have been enforceable. [...]</p><p> Apple does this as a matter of principle. They won&#39;t leave an amount in the tens of millions on the table. And their overall treatment of Epic, such as not putting Fortnite back, is meant to discourage other app makers from challenging Apple and from breaching the DPLA.</p></blockquote><p> It&#39;s unsurprising but worth noting that <em>Fortnite</em> is seemingly never coming back to iOS, unless Epic sells the franchise to another company. iOS <em>Fortnite</em> players are like the children in an ugly divorce.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Apple Set to Collect $73 Million in Legal Fees From Epic Games’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/17/apple-epic-legal-fees">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/coming_to_grips_with_apples_seemingly_unshakable_sense_of_app_store_entitlement" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9k" rel="shorturl"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024://1.40520</id><published> 2024-01-17T21:59:34Z</published><updated> 2024-01-17T23:02:23Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text"> No matter what the sport, no matter what the letter of the rulebook says, it&#39;s never a good idea to piss off the refs. </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1747280541362102287/">Tim Sweeney, on Twitter/X, yesterday at 10:30am</a> :</p><blockquote><p> As of today, developers can begin exercising their court-established right to tell US customers about better prices on the web. These awful Apple-mandated confusion screens are over and done forever.</p></blockquote><p> That take didn&#39;t last long.</p><p> <a href="https://twitter.com/TimSweeneyEpic/status/1747408148799881390">Sweeney, yesterday at 7:00pm</a> , after Apple released <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/apple-guidelines-external-purchase-links">the details of its intended compliance</a> with the anti-steering ( <em>anti-anti-steering</em> ?) mandate from the Epic v. Apple case:</p><blockquote><p> A quick summary of glaring problems we&#39;ve found so far:</p><ol><li> Apple has introduced an anticompetitive new 27% tax on web purchases. Apple has never done this before, and it kills price competition. Developers can&#39;t offer digital items more cheaply on the web after paying a third-party payment processor 3-6% and paying this new 27% Apple Tax.</li></ol><p> [Sweeney&#39;s points 2–4, complaining about Apple&#39;s stringent design, presentation, and privacy demands regarding external links, omitted.]</p><p> Epic will contest Apple&#39;s bad-faith compliance plan in District Court.</p></blockquote><p> Sweeney&#39;s description makes it sound as though Apple is demanding its commission from all web sales for apps and services that have an iOS app.他们不是。 They&#39;re only demanding the commission from web sales that occur within 7 days of a user tapping through to the web from <a href="https://developer.apple.com/support/storekit-external-entitlement-us/">the new External Purchase Links entitlement</a> in an app. Any app or service that already sells over the web, without paying a cent to Apple, can continue to do so in exactly the same way.</p><p> Also, Apple <em>has</em> done this before: what they announced yesterday is almost exactly in line <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2022/02/going_dutch">with their compliance with Netherlands regulations pertaining to dating apps in 2022</a> .</p><p> Before yesterday:</p><ul><li> iOS app developers could sell digital content and subscriptions over the web, without paying Apple any commission.</li><li> iOS apps outside <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2021/09/01/apple-anti-steering-relaxation">the “reader” category</a> could not link to, nor even tell users about, those web purchases from within their apps.</li></ul><p> After yesterday:</p><ul><li> Apps that wish to link to — or, I think, even inform users about — web purchasing options from within their iOS apps must (a) still offer Apple&#39;s IAP for those items; (b) pay Apple its adjusted 27/12 percent commissions on web sales that come from inside iOS apps; (c) send Apple sales data monthly and submit to audits of their sales; and (d) follow Apple&#39;s stringent design edicts for these in-app links to the web.</li><li> Apps that do not link out to their web stores from within their iOS apps using Apple&#39;s new External Purchase Links entitlement can continue whatever they were doing before yesterday. For apps that do nothing new, Apple is collecting nothing new.</li></ul><p> I&#39;m only surprised that Sweeney was seemingly surprised by any of this. He genuinely seemed to think that Apple not only would, but <em>had to</em> allow links from within apps to the web for purchases without collecting any commission on those sales, and that developers could present those links however they chose.</p><p> I&#39;m glad that Sweeney and Epic plan to contest this, because I&#39;m genuinely curious whether Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers sees Apple&#39;s solution as complying with her injunction against their prior anti-steering rules. But I think it <em>does</em> comply.</p><hr /><p> To be clear, I think Apple should allow apps <em>other than games</em> to just tell users they can pay/buy/subscribe/whatever on the web, without any commission. That the rules which have applied only to “reader” apps since early 2022 should be extended to all apps other than games, perhaps alongside a requirement (which doesn&#39;t apply to “reader” apps) that apps taking advantage of this <em>also</em> offer in-app purchasing.</p><p> I&#39;d draw an exception for games — an exception that surely Sweeney would disagree with completely, given that he&#39;s in the games business — because games are different, and hefty un-circumventable revenue commissions to platform owners are clearly standard for the video game industry 。 The iPhone and iPad are not PCs; they&#39;re consoles for games and apps.</p><p> But I&#39;m not sure at all that Apple is doing anything contrary to the law. Sweeney (and other critics of Apple&#39;s stewardship of iOS as a tightly controlled console) believe Apple both shouldn&#39;t and <em>legally can&#39;t</em> comply with the anti-steering injunction this way. I only believe Apple shouldn&#39;t, not that they legally can&#39;t.</p><p> Most critics of Apple&#39;s control over all iOS software are seemingly of the view that iPhones and iPads should, on principle, be largely like the Mac, where the App Store is an option, not the only game in town for software distribution. Personally, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2021/06/annotating_apples_anti-sideloading_white_paper">I am on the record wishing that Apple would allow some sort of “expert” or “developer” mode</a> — chock full of warnings, perhaps even requiring a developer account to enable — that would basically offer the same options for installing third-party software on iOS as there are on the Mac. That&#39;s me, personally, an expert user. But even setting aside every penny of revenue generated by the App Store, <sup id="fnr1-2024-01-17"><a href="#fn1-2024-01-17">1</a></sup> I see and understand many of the reasons why Apple wouldn&#39;t want to do this. There are a lot of Mac users whose Macs are overrun by adware and other scammy software. I&#39;m not talking about viruses or malware, even — but apps that just abuse the largely free-for-all nature of the Mac platform.</p><p> Basically, there&#39;s an argument that iOS devices should be more like traditional PCs (including the Mac), on ethical or moral grounds. The “ <em>it&#39;s my device, I should decide and control what software runs on it</em> ” argument.我得到它。 But I also get that most consumers&#39; Windows PCs, and many Macs, <sup id="fnr2-2024-01-17"><a href="#fn2-2024-01-17">2</a></sup> are riddled with bad software (privacy invasive, resource hogging, and all sorts of <a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2021/12/22/grammarly-disables-spell-checking-globally/">anti-user shenanigans</a> you&#39;d never think of) that App Store policies forbid. App Store review is far from perfect — I mean come on, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/search/app+store+rejection">that should go without saying</a> — but it is undeniable that adversarial software is not a problem for <em>any</em> typical users on iOS. Nothing you install from the App Store can damage your iPhone or iPad experience. Nothing you install from the App Store is difficult to uninstall if you don&#39;t like it. The same is true of dedicated game consoles like Switch, PlayStation, and Xbox — and to a lesser degree (because Google&#39;s Play Store review seems comparatively lax) for Android.</p><p> But the cynical take is that it&#39;s all about the money for Apple. Maybe the cynics are right! Let&#39;s just concede that they are, and that Apple will only make decisions here that benefit its bottom line. My argument remains that Apple <em>should not</em> be pursuing this plan for complying with the anti-steering injunction by collecting commissions from web sales that initiate in-app. Whatever revenue Apple would lose to non-commissioned web sales (for non-games) is not worth the hit they are taking to the company&#39;s brand and reputation — this move reeks of greed and avarice — nor the increased ire and scrutiny of regulators and legislators on the “anti-Big-Tech” hunt.</p><p> Apple should have been looking for ways to <em>lessen</em> regulatory and legislative pressure over the past few years, and in today&#39;s climate that&#39;s more true than ever. But instead, their stance has seemingly been “ <em>Bring it on.</em> ” Confrontational, not conciliatory, conceding not an inch. Rather than take a sure win with <em>most</em> of what they could want, Apple is seemingly hell-bent on trying to keep <em>everything</em> . To win in chess all you need is to capture your opponent&#39;s king. Apple seemingly wants to capture every last piece on the board — even while playing in a tournament where the referees (regulators) are known to look askance at blatant poor sportsmanship (greed).</p><p> Apple&#39;s calculus should be to balance its natural desire to book large amounts of revenue from the App Store with policies that to some degree <em>placate</em> , rather than antagonize, regulators and legislators. No matter what the sport, no matter what the letter of the rulebook says, it&#39;s never a good idea to piss off the refs.</p><p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol></p><p><li id="fn1-2024-01-17"></p><p> That&#39;s a metric buttload of pennies to set aside, to be sure. <a href="#fnr1-2024-01-17"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 1。">↩︎</a></p><p></li></p><p><li id="fn2-2024-01-17"></p><p> iOS App Store policy critics often point to the Mac as all the evidence they need that Apple could open up software distribution on iOS with no ill effects to users. I wrote about this back in 2021, in a piece titled “ <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2021/06/annotating_apples_anti-sideloading_white_paper">Annotating Apple&#39;s Anti-Sideloading White Paper</a> ”. Quoting from that column, which begins with a quote from <a href="https://www.apple.com/privacy/docs/Building_a_Trusted_Ecosystem_for_Millions_of_Apps.pdf">Apple&#39;s white paper</a> :</p><blockquote><p>第 9 页：</p><blockquote><p> iPhone is used every day by over a billion people — for banking, to manage health data, and to take pictures of their families. This large user base would make an appealing and lucrative target for cybercriminals and scammers, and allowing sideloading would spur a flood of new investment into attacks on iPhone, well beyond the scale of attacks on other platforms like Mac.</p></blockquote><p> Here Apple dances around the elephant in the room — the question of why iOS shouldn&#39;t just work like the Mac with regard to non-App Store software. Apple&#39;s deft argument is that there are far fewer Macs than iOS devices, making the Mac a less enticing target for scammers and crooks (including privacy crooks). That&#39;s more or less the argument Windows proponents used to explain the profound prevalence of malware on Windows compared to the Mac back in the day, whilst Apple (and Mac proponents) argued otherwise, that the Mac actually was far more secure at a technical level.</p><p> But the truth Apple won&#39;t come out and say is that it&#39;s <em>both</em> . The Mac <em>was</em> more secure by design, but <em>also</em> a far less enticing target because of how many more users were (and still are) on Windows. And, today, iOS <em>is</em> more secure and private than the Mac. That&#39;s the nature of the Mac as a full PC platform.</p><p> I&#39;ll admit it: if Mac-style sideloading were added to iOS, I&#39;d enable it, for the same reason I enable installing apps from outside the App Store on my Mac: I trust myself to only install trustworthy software. But it doesn&#39;t make me a hypocrite to say that I think it would be worse for the platform as a whole.</p><p> The Mac is fundamentally designed for users who are at least <em>somewhat</em> technically savvy, but tries its best to keep non-savvy users from doing things they shouldn&#39;t. But you can always hurt yourself, sometimes badly, with any true power tool. The iPhone is the converse: designed first and foremost for the non-savvy user, and tries to accommodate power users as best it can within the limits of that primary directive.</p></blockquote><p><p> All the more pertinent today, <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/vestager_cook">as Apple faces down the March 7 deadline for compliance with the EU&#39;s Digital Markets Act</a> that ostensibly mandates sideloading on iOS. <a href="#fnr2-2024-01-17"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 2。">↩︎︎</a></li></p><p></ol></div></p> ]]>;</content><title> ★ Coming to Grips With Apple&#39;s Seemingly Unshakable Sense of Entitlement to Its Commissions From Third-Party iOS Apps</title></entry><entry><title> Apple&#39;s Workaround for the ITC&#39;s Import Ban on Apple Watch Series 9 and Ultra 2: Disabling the Blood-Oxygen Sensor in Software </title><link href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/01/apple-watch-redesigned-without-blood-oxygen-monitoring-to-avoid-import-ban/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9j" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/apple-workaround-itc-import-ban" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40519</id><published> 2024-01-17T04:14:41Z</published><updated> 2024-01-17T18:23:58Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Scharon Harding, reporting for Ars Technica:</p><blockquote><p> Apple has developed a backup plan for if the Apple Watch Series 9 and Ultra 2 are import banned again. As it currently appeals the US International Trade Commission&#39;s (ITC&#39;s) ruling that its watches violate a patent owned by Masimo, Apple has come up with a software workaround that strips its current smartwatches of their controversial blood oxygen monitoring capabilities.</p></blockquote><p> That&#39;s a good summary of Apple&#39;s workaround from a writer who understands what she&#39;s talking about. Apple will disable blood-oxygen monitoring via software.</p><p> Compare and contrast with Aaron Tilley&#39;s report for The Wall Street Journal, under the jacktastically-wrong headline “ <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/apple-watch-ban-united-states-update-cd069ab4">Apple to Remove Blood-Oxygen Sensor From Watch to Avoid US Ban</a> ” ( <a href="https://apple.news/A0oSSFm6wTy2vmPERu7MhRQ">News+ link</a> ):</p><blockquote><p> Apple is removing a blood-oxygen sensor from some of its smartwatches to get around a patent dispute related to the technology, a step likely to avoid further sales disruptions but one that may raise questions about the company&#39;s push into health. [...]</p><p> The US Customs and Border Protection agency, which is responsible for enforcing import bans, on Friday approved technical changes to the watches, including the removal of the blood-oxygen sensor, according to a Masimo filing on Monday. A decision on Apple&#39;s request for a permanent stay on the US ban during its appeal is expected in the coming days.</p></blockquote><p> Ars includes <a href="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Masimo-letter-January-15.pdf">a link to Masimo&#39;s filing</a> ; the WSJ does not. Needless to say, Masimo&#39;s filing does <em>not</em> say that Apple is removing the blood-oxygen sensor from these watches, because they&#39;re not. They&#39;re just disabling the sensors via software for watches sold in the US — the only country where the import ban applies.</p><p> This is no little mistake on Tilley&#39;s and the Journal&#39;s part. Disabling a feature via software is one thing, and not that big a deal. Designing, engineering, and manufacturing entirely different hardware models without the physical sensors would be extraordinary. That&#39;s just not how Apple works — they&#39;re not set up to change manufacturing like that. Plus, if Apple merely disables the sensor via software, they can re-enable it via a software update in the future, once the dispute is settled. If they were to start selling Series 9 and Ultra 2 watches that didn&#39;t have the sensor, those watches would <em>never</em> gain the functionality, even after the dispute is settled.</p><p> Aaron Tilley isn&#39;t just a tech reporter for the Journal: his entire beat is covering Apple. And he seemingly has no idea how the company functions, because if he did, he&#39;d have quadruple checked this “they&#39;re removing the sensors” take before publishing it. But here it is a day after publication and his report has yet to be corrected. Pure jackassery.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Apple’s Workaround for the ITC’s Import Ban on Apple Watch Series 9 and Ultra 2: Disabling the Blood-Oxygen Sensor in Software’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/apple-workaround-itc-import-ban">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Post-SCOTUS Ruling, Apple Releases Guidelines for &#39;External Purchase Links&#39; in iOS Apps (Spoiler: They Still Demand the Same Commissions) </title><link href="https://developer.apple.com/support/storekit-external-entitlement-us/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9i" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/apple-guidelines-external-purchase-links" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40518</id><published> 2024-01-17T03:22:20Z</published><updated> 2024-01-17T03:37:36Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Apple Developer News:</p><blockquote><p>除了使用 Apple 方便、安全、可靠的应用内购买系统外，美国 App Store 上提供应用内购买的应用还可以使用 StoreKit 外部购买链接权利（美国）来包含指向开发者网站，告知用户购买数字商品或服务的其他方式。要使用该权利，您需要提交请求，在 Xcode 中启用该权利，并使用所需的 StoreKit API。 Apple 将审核您的应用程序，以确保其符合权利的条款和条件，以及 App Store 审核指南和 Apple 开发者计划许可协议。 [...]</p><p>您的应用必须根据开发者计划许可协议和应用商店审核指南提供应用内购买，并且不得阻止最终用户进行应用内购买。</p></blockquote><p> Apple clearly had these updated guidelines ready to go, pending this week&#39;s decision from the US Supreme Court <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/scotus-epic-apple">rejecting the remaining petitions from Apple and Epic</a> .</p><p> Scroll down the page, then scroll some more, and you&#39;ll get to the section on “Commission, transaction reports, and payments”:</p><blockquote><p> Apple is charging a commission on digital purchases initiated within seven days from link out, as described below. This will not capture all transactions that Apple has facilitated through the App Store, but is a reasonable means to account for the substantial value Apple provides developers, including in facilitating linked transactions.</p><p> Apple&#39;s commission will be 27% on proceeds you earn from sales (“transactions“) to the user for digital goods or services on your website after a link out (ie, they tap “Continue” on the system disclosure sheet), provided that the sale was initiated within seven days and the digital goods or services can be used in an app. This includes (a) any applicable taxes and (b) any adjustments for refunds, reversals and chargebacks. For auto-renewing subscriptions, (i) a sale initiated, including with a free trial or offer, within seven days after a link out is a transaction; and (ii) each subsequent auto-renewal after the subscription is initiated is also a transaction.]</p><p> If you&#39;re a participant in the Small Business Program, or if the transaction is an auto-renewal in the second year or later of an auto-renewing subscription, the commission will be 12%.</p><p> These commission rates apply to all amounts paid by each user net of transaction taxes charged by you. You will be responsible for the collection and remittance of any applicable taxes for sales processed by a third-party payment provider.</p><p> If you adopt this entitlement, you will be required to provide transaction reports within 15 calendar days following the end of each calendar month. Even if there were no transactions, you&#39;re required to provide a report stating that is the case.</p></blockquote><p> I&#39;ve said it before, I&#39;ll say it again now, and I&#39;m sure I&#39;ll have to say it again in the future: Apple&#39;s 30/15 percent commissions from App Store purchases and subscriptions are <em>not</em> payment processing fees. They <em>include</em> payment processing fees, but most of those commissions are, in Apple&#39;s view, their way of monetizing their intellectual property. And they see the entire iOS platform as their IP.</p><p> So developers who want to process payments on their own websites are still on the hook to pay Apple the same effective commissions, minus only 3 percent for the actual payment processing. And the truth is most of the time credit card processing costs more than 3 percent overall, after chargebacks and fraud are taken into consideration. Do more work and save no money — sounds appealing, no?</p><p> <strong>See also:</strong> <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2024/01/16/us-app-store-alternative-purchase-option/">MacRumors has PDF copies</a> of Apple&#39;s “notice of compliance” filing, and App Store VP Matthew Fischer&#39;s declaration of compliance, both submitted to Judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Post-SCOTUS Ruling, Apple Releases Guidelines for ‘External Purchase Links’ in iOS Apps (Spoiler: They Still Demand the Same Commissions)’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/apple-guidelines-external-purchase-links">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Disney Has a Good Disney+ App for VisionOS (and, by the Way, I Got Another 30-Minute Hands-On Experience With Vision Pro) </title><link href="https://thewaltdisneycompany.com/disney-on-apple-vision-pro-ushers-in-a-new-era-of-storytelling-innovation-and-immersive-entertainment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9h" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/disney-plus-visionos" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40517</id><published> 2024-01-17T01:00:46Z</published><updated> 2024-01-17T03:41:58Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>迪士尼：</p><blockquote><p> At launch, viewers can transform their space into one of four Disney+ environments, bringing them even closer to the story. Each environment includes animations and sounds that make the space feel alive, and Easter eggs from films and franchises that will surprise and delight fans.</p><p> Available only on Apple Vision Pro, Disney+ subscribers will be able to stream the entire catalog — including thousands of TV shows and films, plus access to Hulu content for eligible Disney Bundle subscribers — from iconic environments with vivid details, including: the Disney+ Theater, inspired by the historic El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood; the Scare Floor from Pixar&#39;s Monsters Inc.;漫威的复仇者大厦俯瞰曼哈顿市中心； and the cockpit of Luke Skywalker&#39;s landspeeder facing a binary sunset on the planet Tatooine from the Star Wars galaxy.</p></blockquote><p> I got to try this during <a href="https://mastodon.social/@gruber/111767493035111862">another hands-on Vision Pro demo</a> <a href="https://www.threads.net/@gruber/post/C2LKPu5P0Wu">in New York today</a> . (Follow those links to Mastodon and Threads, where I&#39;ve tried to answer every question asked by my followers.)</p><p> It&#39;s 100 percent a gimmick, but it&#39;s a really good fun whimsical gimmick, and the detail is extraordinary. It looks like you are there on Tony Stark&#39;s helipad penthouse deck, with a towering view of Manhattan in front of you, and Stark&#39;s apartment behind you. These are 360° environments. The Tatooine view in the landspeeder is right outside Mos Eisley, at dusk.</p><p> Does it make the movie you&#39;re watching any better to see it while sitting in an immersive fantasy environment?不，当然不。 But it&#39;s a lot of fun, because it&#39;s so intricately detailed and well-done. Did the Mac OS X Aqua user interface make Mac users more productive? Did the original iPhone work better because its interface looked so damn cool? No. But those UIs sure did make Mac OS X and the original iPhone more fun.</p><p> I don&#39;t know why people lose sight of the fact that having fun is one of the very best parts of being a human. The Disney+ app for VisionOS is fun.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Disney Has a Good Disney+ App for VisionOS (and, by the Way, I Got Another 30-Minute Hands-On Experience With Vision Pro)’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/disney-plus-visionos">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Tim Sweeney on the SCOTUS Ruling </title><link href="https://twitter.com/timsweeneyepic/status/1747280528745624000?s=61&amp;t=16WqqI8uLOTkQieKK2aS4g" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9g" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/sweeney" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40516</id><published> 2024-01-16T19:59:19Z</published><updated> 2024-01-16T20:39:11Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Epic CEO Tim Sweeney:</p><blockquote><p> The Supreme Court denied both sides&#39; appeals of the Epic v. Apple antitrust case. The court battle to open iOS to competing stores and payments is lost in the United States. A sad outcome for all developers.</p><p> Now the District Court&#39;s injunction against Apple&#39;s anti-steering rule is in effect, and developers can include in their apps “buttons, external links, or other calls to action that direct customers to purchasing mechanisms, in addition to IAP”.</p><p> As of today, developers can begin exercising their court-established right to tell US customers about better prices on the web.</p></blockquote><p> It&#39;s sad for Epic, perhaps, and game developers in general, but I think overall this is a good day for developers, and a great day for users. In-app game purchases are already too predatory, as things stand — they&#39;d get far worse if games on iOS were free to circumvent Apple&#39;s system. If a developer wants users to sign up and pay on their website, they can now tell them so, in plain language, in the app.</p><p> The truth should never be against the rules. If you need to pay/subscribe on the app&#39;s website, the app should be able to tell you that you need to pay/subscribe on their website.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Tim Sweeney on the SCOTUS Ruling’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/sweeney">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Supreme Court Rejects Petitions in Epic v. Apple Antitrust Case, Largely a Win for Apple </title><link href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/16/24039983/supreme-court-epic-apple-antitrust-case-rejected" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9f" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/scotus-epic-apple" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40515</id><published> 2024-01-16T16:25:13Z</published><updated> 2024-01-16T16:25:14Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Adi Robertson, reporting for The Verge:</p><blockquote><p> The Supreme Court has denied a request to hear an antitrust dispute between Apple and <em>Fortnite</em> publisher Epic Games. It <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/orders/courtorders/011624zor_e1pf.pdf">rejected two petitions</a> , one from each company, this morning — leaving the case largely, but not entirely, a win for Apple. [...]</p><p> Even so, both rulings found that Apple had acted anticompetitively by barring developers from telling users about other payment methods. Apple was ordered to let them allow links and other “calls to action” that would bypass Apple&#39;s payment system, discontinuing what are known as anti-steering policies. But the company spent years delaying parts of the change with legal appeals, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/9/23826043/epic-apple-app-store-supreme-court-petition">winning a reprieve while</a> the Supreme Court considered the case. Today&#39;s denial seemingly runs out that clock, requiring Apple to reconsider the future of its anti-steering rules.</p></blockquote><p> Apple&#39;s intransigence on these anti-steering provisions has <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2019/01/netflix_itunes_billing">long baffled me</a> . I&#39;ve consistently argued that the rules should be simple: apps that want to accept in-app payments must use Apple&#39;s IAP system, but apps should be free to inform users that they can sign up and pay on the web, outside the app. In-app: Apple&#39;s platform, Apple&#39;s payments system. Out-app: the open web, and apps should be able to steer customers there. If Apple&#39;s in-app purchasing system is so easy to use, so reasonably priced for its benefits, and so trusted by users, it should be able to compete openly with the web. And I think Apple&#39;s in-app payments <em>do</em> compare favorably to leaving an app to pay on the web, especially for games. But with true competition from web purchases that apps can steer users to, Apple&#39;s commission rates, for apps other than games at least, would probably be lower. I&#39;d argue that it&#39;s unhealthy for a company to grow dependent on unnaturally high commissions protected by fiat policies, rather than set through open competition.</p><p> Perhaps Apple&#39;s thinking was that they might as well try to hold the line on these anti-steering provisions for as long as they could, thinking that today&#39;s outcome was the worst case scenario. But I think it&#39;s been a bad look for the company for years, and invited additional regulatory scrutiny. Regardless of whether these anti-steering provisions are <em>legally</em> anticompetitive, they&#39;re undeniably anticompetitive in the plain sense of the word. I genuinely believe the Supreme Court has done Apple a favor letting this ruling stand.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Supreme Court Rejects Petitions in Epic v. Apple Antitrust Case, Largely a Win for Apple’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/scotus-epic-apple">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Apple Teases New Entertainment Experiences Launching With Vision Pro </title><link href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/apple-previews-new-entertainment-experiences-launching-with-apple-vision-pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9e" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/visionos-entertainment" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40514</id><published> 2024-01-16T15:54:01Z</published><updated> 2024-01-17T03:42:13Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Apple Newsroom, with some new content information for Vision Pro (finally):</p><blockquote><p> With Apple Vision Pro, users can experience Apple Immersive Video, a remarkable new entertainment format pioneered by Apple. Apple Immersive Video features 180-degree 3D 8K recordings captured with Spatial Audio to transport viewers to the center of a place, moment, or story. At launch, users can enjoy a <a href="https://www.apple.com/tv-pr/news/2024/01/apple-tv-unveils-groundbreaking-immersive-originals-from-todays-biggest-storytellers-set-to-debut-on-apple-vision-pro/">curated selection</a> of immersive films and series on the Apple TV app at no additional cost.</p></blockquote><p> That link has details about the debut titles:</p><ul><li><em>艾丽西亚·凯斯：排练室</em></li><li><em>Adventure</em> — adventure athletes in exotic locations</li><li><em>野生动物</em></li><li><em>Prehistoric Planet Immersive</em> — “Viewers will transport into the daily lives of dinosaurs, experiencing T-Rex teens crashing a quiet colony of pterosaurs on the beach until mama shows up to break up their party, and an intense battle between raptors and a pride of Triceratops在树林里。”</li></ul><p> There&#39;s only a handful of these new immersive experiences, but the main thrust of the Newsroom announcement is to emphasize that Vision Pro is a killer device for watching <em>any</em> movies or TV shows.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Apple Teases New Entertainment Experiences Launching With Vision Pro’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/16/visionos-entertainment">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Hands-On at CES With the Clicks Keyboard Case for iPhone 15 Pro </title><link href="https://9to5mac.com/2024/01/12/clicks-iphone-hands-on/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9c" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/15/clicks-hands-on" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40512</id><published> 2024-01-15T20:04:07Z</published><updated> 2024-01-15T20:04:07Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Ben Schoon, writing for 9to5Mac:</p><blockquote><p> For a case built for this express purpose, the keys are crucial to get right, and Clicks has nailed it, I think. The keys are rounded and have a bit of space in between each one, but the layout overall feels familiar and well done. The keyboard layout is also specifically designed to be really similar to the default iOS keyboard, which makes it feel all the more familiar.</p><p> Each key is also backlit and has an excellent tactile response. That&#39;s the aspect I was most concerned about, and while some of the pre-production models were a little rough, the final version that I was able to test during my hands-on (not pictured) felt <em>perfect</em> . It was clicky and tactile without being loud or too hard to press. [...]</p><p> In my brief time using it, I&#39;m very much of the opinion that Clicks is pretty much as good as this concept can be. It&#39;s well-designed, comfortable to use, and hits all of the right notes.</p></blockquote><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Hands-On at CES With the Clicks Keyboard Case for iPhone 15 Pro’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/15/clicks-hands-on">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title>嗯</title><link href="http://meh.com/go/df" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9b" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/14/meh" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40511</id><published> 2024-01-14T21:18:13Z</published><updated> 2024-01-26T16:38:54Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>My thanks to Meh for sponsoring last week at DF. Meh is probably the best — and certainly the funnest — daily deal site on the web. Here&#39;s their pitch, in their words:</p><blockquote><p> You don&#39;t want the daily deal at <a href="https://meh.com/?utm_source=daringfireball&amp;utm_medium=sponsor&amp;utm_campaign=dontwant">meh.com</a> today.</p><p> At least, you probably don&#39;t, statistically speaking. But you should go look. Because if you do want it, you really want it, at least for this price. And the cost of checking is, what, 15 seconds of your life?</p><p> So go to <a href="https://meh.com/?utm_source=daringfireball&amp;utm_medium=sponsor&amp;utm_campaign=dontwant">meh.com</a> . Decide you don&#39;t want what we&#39;re selling.明天就回去吧这就是整个游戏。</p></blockquote><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Meh’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/14/meh">★</a></div> ]]>;</content></entry><entry><title> Yours Truly on the Techmeme Ride Home Podcast </title><link href="https://www.ridehome.info/show/techmeme-ride-home/bonus-john-gruber-talks-apple-and-ai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v9a" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/14/techmeme-ride-home-vision-pro" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40510</id><published> 2024-01-14T21:05:24Z</published><updated> 2024-01-14T21:15:34Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Brian McCullough had me and Chris Messina on the weekend edition of the excellent Techmeme Ride Home podcast to talk about Vision Pro&#39;s launch (and for me and Chris to argue about hashtags). Fun show. You can even <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8jBAwMLvB-Q">watch on YouTube</a> if that&#39;s your thing.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘Yours Truly on the Techmeme Ride Home Podcast’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/14/techmeme-ride-home-vision-pro">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/vestager_cook" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v97" rel="shorturl"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024://1.40507</id><published> 2024-01-14T00:10:00Z</published><updated> 2024-01-14T05:00:26Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text"> It&#39;s just not clear at all exactly what Apple needs to allow to comply with the DMA, nor do any of us outside Cupertino have any idea what Apple plans to do. </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>European Commission chief Margrethe Vestager is on the West Coast meeting with US tech executives. Here&#39;s her entire statement on meeting Tim Cook at Apple Park, <a href="https://twitter.com/vestager/status/1745693612262953300">posted on Twitter/X</a> (I&#39;m surprised she posts on a US-based platform, rather than one of the popular EU social networks):</p><blockquote><p> 2 main points from my meeting w/ @tim_cook @apple ⬇️</p><p> 👉 compliance w/ #DMA, eg @Apple&#39;s obligation to allow the distribution of #apps outside the @AppStore</p><p> 👉 ongoing @EU_Competition cases eg @AppleMusic</p></blockquote><p> There are so many meetings and negotiations where I&#39;d pay a veritable fortune to have been a fly on the wall. Vestager meeting with Cook this week was <em>not</em> one. My guess is that absolutely nothing interesting was said. Nothing but platitudes.</p><p> The deadline for compliance with the DMA is March 7, and the big issue for Apple is the App Store: allowing native apps to be installed from outside the store (aka sideloading), and allowing alternative in-app payment methods. My understanding is that Apple has everything prepared for compliance, but, exactly what that&#39;s going to look like, seemingly no one outside the company knows.</p><p> We know nothing about how Apple plans to allow sideloading. I expect that even for users in the EU, sideloading will be off by default. I also expect that, unlike the Mac, sideloaded apps will still need to be signed by Apple. Will apps distributed through the App Store allow third-party in-app payment processing, or will that only be available to sideloaded apps? I further presume, that just like when Apple complied with Dutch regulations specific to dating apps, third-party apps that implement their own payment processing for in-app purchases will be required to provide Apple with detailed accounting and pay Apple a 27% commission.</p><p> Will sideloading <em>only</em> be available within the EU, or will Apple implement the same policies worldwide? For the most part Apple tries to keep things the same worldwide, but sideloading is such an exception that I expect them to region-lock it to the EU Especially given that stipulation that Apple needs to permit sideloaded apps to act as app stores themselves.<em>这</em>将如何运作？</p><p> I expect that Apple has designed sideloading in such a way that very few users will enable it. (This seems to be largely the case on Android, which has permitted off-by-default sideloading from its inception.) I also expect that Apple will still demand 27% of in-app purchase revenue from apps that choose to implement their own payment加工。</p><p> Basically, I don&#39;t think much will change for EU users, or for developers. But a lot of people — including Vestager and the European Commission — expect a <em>lot</em> to change. It&#39;s just not clear at all exactly what Apple needs to allow to comply with the DMA, nor do any of us outside Cupertino have any idea what Apple plans to do. Complying with the <em>letter</em> of the DMA does not mean capitulating to the <em>spirit</em> of the DMA. The idea that Apple is going to roll over and give up on steering their own platform the way they feel best benefits both their own bottom line, and <a href="https://www.apple.com/privacy/docs/Building_a_Trusted_Ecosystem_for_Millions_of_Apps_A_Threat_Analysis_of_Sideloading.pdf">their users&#39; experience/privacy/security</a> , is naive.</p><p> The European Commission expected that the GDPR would result in websites prioritizing the privacy of EU users — a better web in Europe than elsewhere. Instead, the result was increased user annoyance under a nonstop daily barrage of consent popovers — a <em>worse</em> web in Europe than elsewhere. I suspect the same will prove true of the DMA and mobile platforms. Fireworks are coming, but it seems like few people know it.</p> ]]>;</content><title> ★ Margrethe Vestager Met With Tim Cook Yesterday, But I Doubt Anything Happened</title></entry><entry><title> CNN: &#39;FAA Keeps Boeing&#39;s 737 Max 9 Grounded as It Reviews Inspections and Data&#39; </title><link href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/01/12/business/boeing-faa-manufacturing-oversight/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v99" rel="shorturl" type="text/html"/><link href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/13/faa-keeps-737-maxes-grounded" rel="related" type="text/html"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024:/linked//6.40509</id><published> 2024-01-14T00:09:50Z</published><updated> 2024-01-14T00:09:51Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/ </uri></author><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/linked/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p>Pete Muntean, reporting for CNN:</p><blockquote><p> The Federal Aviation Administration said on Friday that after reviewing Boeing&#39;s instructions for inspecting grounded 737 Max 9 planes, it has decided to seek more information before allowing the plan to proceed. In a statement, FAA also said it would keep the Boeing 737 Max 9 “grounded until extensive inspection and maintenance is conducted and data from inspections is reviewed.”</p><p> The announcement comes exactly one week after the dramatic in-flight incident on Alaska Airlines flight 1282, when a part called a door plug was blown off the side of the plane. [...] 171 of the planes remain grounded in the United States as airlines Alaska and United await updated emergency inspection guidance from the FAA.</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-increasing-oversight-boeing-production-and-manufacturing">The FAA, yesterday</a> :</p><blockquote><p> After taking decisive and immediate action to ground approximately 171 Boeing 737-9 MAX planes, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) today announced new and significant actions to immediately increase its oversight of Boeing production and manufacturing.一天前，美国联邦航空局正式通知波音公司，由于上周五波音 737-9 MAX 型飞机在飞行中丢失乘客舱门插头的事件，美国联邦航空局已对该公司展开调查。</p></blockquote><p> Something has gone deeply wrong at Boeing, a once-great company. This is exactly the sort of situation where government regulators are needed: for issues pertaining to safety.</p><div> <a  title="Permanent link to ‘CNN: ‘FAA Keeps Boeing’s 737 Max 9 Grounded as It Reviews Inspections and Data’’"  href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/01/13/faa-keeps-737-maxes-grounded">★</a></div> ]]>; </content></entry><entry><link href="https://daringfireball.net/2024/01/al_gore_mac_nerd_internet_pioneer" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="http://df4.us/v95" rel="shorturl"/><id> tag:daringfireball.net,2024://1.40505</id><published> 2024-01-13T03:43:08Z</published><updated> 2024-01-16T03:05:18Z</updated><author><name>约翰·格鲁伯</name><uri>http://daringfireball.net/</uri></author><summary type="text"> In 2003 there was one person in the world who could be described as a former vice president of the United States and avid Mac user. </summary><content type="html" xml:base="https://daringfireball.net/" xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2003/03/19Former-Vice-President-Al-Gore-Joins-Apples-Board-of-Directors/">Apple press release, on 19 March 2003</a> (about seven months after I started writing Daring Fireball <sup id="fnr1-2024-01-12"><a href="#fn1-2024-01-12">1</a></sup> ):</p><blockquote><p> Apple today announced that Albert Gore Jr., the former Vice President of the United States, has joined the Company&#39;s Board of Directors. Mr. Gore was elected at Apple&#39;s board meeting today.</p><p> “Al brings an incredible wealth of knowledge and wisdom to Apple from having helped run the largest organization in the world — the United States government — as a Congressman, Senator and our 45th Vice President. Al is also an avid Mac user and does his own video editing in Final Cut Pro,” said Steve Jobs, Apple&#39;s CEO. “Al is going to be a terrific Director and we&#39;re excited and honored that he has chosen Apple as his first private sector board to serve on.”</p></blockquote><p> I love that the second sentence from Jobs was about how Gore is a Mac enthusiast who uses Final Cut Pro. Compare and contrast with today&#39;s <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/01/wanda-austin-to-join-apples-board-of-directors/">utterly milquetoast statements from Tim Cook and chairman Arthur Levinson</a> about new board member Wanda Austin:</p><blockquote><p> “Wanda has spent decades advancing technology on behalf of humanity, and we&#39;re thrilled to welcome her to Apple&#39;s board of directors,” said Tim Cook, Apple&#39;s CEO. “She&#39;s an extraordinary leader, and her invaluable experience and expertise will support our mission of leaving the world better than we found it.”</p><p> “Wanda has long been a leader in unleashing the potential of cutting-edge technology,” said Arthur Levinson, the chair of Apple&#39;s board of directors. “She brings incredible insights and experience to our board, and she will play an important role in helping Apple continue enriching users&#39; lives around the world.”</p></blockquote><p> In 2003 there was one person in the world who could be described as a former vice president of the United States and avid Mac user. (That&#39;s still true today, and that person remains Al Gore.) Cook&#39;s and Levinson&#39;s descriptions of Austin could apply to just about any technology company executive in the world.</p><p> Gore&#39;s statement from 2003:</p><blockquote><p> “Steve and his team have done an incredible job in making Apple once again the very best in the world,” said former Vice President Al Gore. “I have been particularly impressed with the new Mac OS X operating system and the company&#39;s commitment to the open source movement. And I am especially looking forward to working with and learning from the great board members who have guided this legendary company&#39;s inspiring resurgence.”</p></blockquote><p> In 2003, Mac OS X was the most important product for the future of the company, and the open source movement was one of the major stories of the moment.</p><p> Austin&#39;s statement today:</p><blockquote><p> “Like Apple, I&#39;ve always believed in the power of innovation to improve lives, support human potential, and shape a better future,” said Dr. Austin. “I&#39;m honored to join Apple&#39;s board of directors, and I look forward to being part of a company that&#39;s always creating new ways to empower people all over the world.”</p></blockquote><p> She could have said the exact same thing about joining the board of <em>any</em> tech company in the world today. If she serves for 20 years, like Gore did (which is unlikely, given that she&#39;s already 70 and Gore is stepping down because of a policy “directors generally may not stand for reelection after reaching age 75” <sup id="fnr2-2024-01-12"><a href="#fn2-2024-01-12">2</a></sup> ), no one in the year 2044 is going to look back on her statement above and think, <em>Yeah, that captures what was then the current moment for Apple.</em> Austin may well be a perfect candidate to serve on Apple&#39;s board, but there&#39;s nothing in today&#39;s press release that indicates why.</p><p> Gore was widely mocked in the run-up to the 2000 election for supposedly claiming to have “invented the internet”. But he never claimed any such thing. <a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/internet-of-lies/">From Snopes</a> :</p><blockquote><p> The claim that Gore was actually trying to take credit for the “invention” of the Internet was plainly just derisive political posturing that arose out of a close presidential campaign. If, for example, Dwight Eisenhower had said in the mid-1960s that he, while president, “took the initiative in creating the Interstate Highway System,” he would not have been the subject of dozens and dozens of editorials lampooning him for claiming he “invented” the concept of highways or implying that he personally went out and dug ditches across the country to help build the roadway. Everyone would have understood that Eisenhower meant he was a driving force behind the legislation that created the highway system, and this was the very same concept Al Gore was expressing about himself with interview remarks about the Internet. [...]</p><p> A <a href="https://amsterdam.nettime.org/Lists-Archives/nettime-l-0009/msg00311.html">spirited defense of Gore&#39;s statement</a> penned by Internet pioneers Robert Kahn and Vinton Cerf (the latter often referred to as the “father of the Internet”) in 2000 noted that “Al Gore was the first political leader to recognize the importance of the Internet and to promote and support its development” and that “No other elected official, to our knowledge, has made a greater contribution [to the Internet] over a longer period of time.”</p></blockquote><p> Not a bad endorsement.</p><div class="footnotes"><hr /><ol><li id="fn1-2024-01-12"><p> No mention of Gore&#39;s appointment to the board in <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2003/03/" title="Daring Fireball Archive: March 2003">my archive for March 2003</a> , but that preceded the existence of the <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/">Linked List</a> (my short-form link entries). That month did see what I still consider my best ever one-two shot of back-to-back headlines: “ <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2003/03/aliasing">Aliasing</a> ” and “ <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2003/03/anti-aliasing">Anti-Aliasing</a> ”. (There was also an “ <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2003/03/anti-anti-aliasing">Anti-Anti-Aliasing</a> ”.) But <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2003/03/code_monkey">this one</a> , clearly, was the best piece of the month. <a href="#fnr1-2024-01-12"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 1。">↩︎</a></p></li><li id="fn2-2024-01-12"><p> It&#39;s wild to think that Gore, whose ill-fated lost-by-a-hair run for president took place a quarter century ago, has reached the mandatory retirement age for Apple&#39;s board, yet is several years younger than both Joe Biden and Donald Trump 。 <a href="#fnr2-2024-01-12"  class="footnoteBackLink"  title="跳回到文中的脚注 2。">↩︎︎</a></p></li></ol></div> ]]>;</content><title> ★ Al Gore, Mac Nerd and Internet Pioneer</title></entry></feed><!-- THE END -->